code interpreter, file system command
execution and websockets out of the box.
There is a bunch of examples. Come check
it out. What are you waiting for? Uh it
has given us a computer that's weeks of
effort. The developer experience is well
thought out. What are you waiting for?
Come here. Get started now.
Bite coding in AI Studio with Gemini 3
lets you build anything.
Build entirely new experiences.
Create apps that see. Make tools that
listen.
Build apps with a single prompt.
Get inspired.
>> Tell me what you want.
Refine
>> and refine some more.
>> Share with a friend
and remix.
Then share with the world.
Bring anything to life.
>> Tell me what you want to do.
>> Pixie Bricks is the fastest way to solve
internal business problems on top of
tools your team already uses. Describe
the extension you want and get user
interfacing components like forms,
buttons, and modals connected to
back-end logic like API requests and
database queries. One-click deployment
for small teams. Enterprisegrade
security for scale. Build your dream
extension today.
You know, render for quick deploys, but
did you know it's also the fastest path
to production for full stack apps? This
one has a web service. That's a front
end and a back end, manage Postgress and
a chron job that runs durable workflows.
And the best part is all of your
services in the same region can
communicate internally over a private
network that's both faster and more
secure than the public internet. So
whether it's an AI agent or your next
startup, build it better on render.
Everybody
down.
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
VI coding an AI studio with Gemini 3
lets you build anything.
Build entirely new experiences.
Create apps that see. Make tools that
listen.
Build apps with a single prompt.
Get inspired.
Tell me what you want.
>> Refine
and refine some more.
>> Share with a friend.
and remix.
>> Then share with the world.
Bring anything to life.
>> Tell me what you want to do.
Using cursor, Windsurf, Claude Code.
What about MCP servers? This AI coding
stack creates new risks such as data
theft and prompt injections. Backslash
security provides visibility,
governance, and real-time protection for
agents, idees, LLMs, and MCPs. We make
Vibe coding safe.
Allow me to introduce you to the
CloudFlare Sandbox SDK. It is an npm
install away. It gives you wonderful
code like this where you get the
sandbox, you do a get checkout, and then
you execute code like that. How
beautiful is that? And look at this.
That's not all. You get longunning
processes, real-time streaming, preview
URLs. How amazing is that? Code
interpreter, file system, command
execution, and websockets out of the
box. There is a bunch of examples. Come
check it out. What are you waiting for?
Uh, it has given us a computer that's
really weeks of effort. The developer
experience is well thought out. What are
you waiting for? Come here. Get started
now.
>> Pixie is the fastest way to solve
internal business problems on top of
tools your team already uses. Describe
the extension you want and get user
interfacing components like forms,
buttons, and modals connected to
back-end logic like API requests and
database queries. Oneclick deployment
for small teams. Enterprisegrade
security for scale. Build your dream
extension today.
You know, render for quick deploys, but
did you know it's also the fastest path
to production for full stack apps? This
one has a web service, that's a front
end and a back end, manage Postgress,
and a Chrome job that runs durable
workflows. And the best part is all of
your services in the same region can
communicate internally over a private
network that's both faster and more
secure than the public internet. So
whether it's an AI agent or your next
startup, build it better on render.
Heat. Heat.
VI coding an AI Studio with Gemini 3
lets you build anything.
Build entirely new experiences.
Create apps that see. Make tools that
listen.
Build apps with a single prompt.
Get inspired.
>> Tell me what you want.
refine
and refine some more
right now.
>> Share with a friend
and remix
then share with the world.
Bring anything to life.
>> Tell me what you want to do.
>> Using cursor, wind surf, clawed code.
What about MCP servers? This AI coding
stack creates new risks such as data
theft and prompt injections. Backslash
security provides visibility,
governance, and real-time protection for
agents, idees, LLMs, and MCPs. We make
Vibe coding safe.
Allow me to introduce you to the
Cloudflare Sandbox SDK. It is an npm
install away. It gives you wonderful
code like this where you get the
sandbox, you do a get checkout, and then
you execute code like that. How
beautiful is that? And look at this.
That's not all. You get longunning
processes, real-time streaming, preview
URLs. How amazing is that? Code
interpreter, file system, command
execution, and websockets out of the
box. There is a bunch of examples. Come
check it out. What are you waiting for?
Uh, it has given us a computer that's
weeks of effort. The developer
experience is well thought out. What are
you waiting for? Come here. Get started
now.
>> Pixie Bricks is the fastest way to solve
internal business problems on top of
tools your team already uses. Describe
the extension you want and get user
interfacing components like forms,
buttons, and modals connected to
back-end logic like API requests and
database queries. Oneclick deployment
for small teams. Enterprisegrade
security for scale. Build your dream
extension today.
You know, render for quick deploys, but
did you know it's also the fastest path
to production for fullstack apps? This
one has a web service, that's a front
end and a back end, managed Postgress,
and a Chrome job that runs durable
workflows. And the best part is all of
your services in the same region can
communicate internally over a private
network that's both faster and more
secure than the public internet. So
whether it's an AI agent or your next
startup, build it better on render.
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
using cursor windsurf claw code. What
about MCP servers? This AI coding stack
creates new risks such as data theft and
prompt injections. Backslash security
provides visibility, governance, and
real time protection for agents, idees,
LLMs, and MCPs. We make Vibe coding
safe.
>> Allow me to introduce you to the
CloudFlare Sandbox SDK. It is an npm
install away. It gives you wonderful
code like this where you get the
sandbox, you do a get checkout, and then
you execute code like that. How
beautiful is that? And look at this.
That's not all. You get longunning
processes, real-time streaming, preview
URLs. How amazing is that? Code
interpreter, file system, command
execution, and websockets out of the
box. There is a bunch of examples. Come
check it out. What are you waiting for?
Uh, it has given us a computer that's
really weeks of effort. The developer
experience is well thought out. What are
you waiting for? Come here. Get started
now.
VI coding in AI Studio with Gemini 3
lets you build anything.
Build entirely new experiences.
Create apps that see. Make tools that
listen.
Build apps with a single prompt.
Get inspired.
Tell me what you want.
>> Refine
and refine some more
now.
>> Share with a friend.
and remix,
>> then share with the world.
>> Bring anything to life.
>> Tell me what you want to do.
>> Pixie Bricks is the fastest way to solve
internal business problems on top of
tools your team already uses. Describe
the extension you want and get user
interfacing components like forms,
buttons, and modals connected to
back-end logic like API requests and
database queries. One-click deployment
for small teams. Enterprisegrade
security for scale. Build your dream
extension today.
You know, render for quick deploys, but
did you know it's also the fastest path
to production for full stack apps? This
one has a web service, that's a front
end and a back end, managed Postgress,
and a chron job that runs durable
workflows. And the best part is all of
your services in the same region, you
can communicate internally over a
private network that's both faster and
more secure than the public internet. So
whether it's an AI agent or your next
startup, build it better on render.
down. Everything
We Yeah.
Heat.
VI coding an AI Studio with Gemini 3
lets you build anything.
Build entirely new experiences.
Create apps that see. Make tools that
listen.
Build apps with a single prompt.
Get inspired.
>> Tell me what you want.
>> Refine.
And refine some more.
right now.
>> Share with a friend
and remix,
>> then share with the world.
Bring anything to life.
>> Tell me what you want to do.
>> Using cursor, wind surf, claw code. What
about MCP servers? This AI coding stack
creates new risks such as data theft and
prompt injections. Backslash security
provides visibility, governance, and
real-time protection for agents, idees,
LLMs, and MCPs. We make Vibe coding
safe.
Allow me to introduce you to the
Cloudflare Sandbox SDK. It is an npm
install away. It gives you wonderful
code like this where you get the
sandbox, you do a get checkout, and then
you execute code like that. How
beautiful is that? And look at this.
That's not all. You get longunning
processes, real-time streaming, preview
URLs. How amazing is that? Code
interpreter, file system, command
execution, and websockets out of the
box. There is a bunch of examples. Come
check it out. What are you waiting for?
Uh, it has given us a computer that's
really weeks of effort. The developer
experience is well thought out. What are
you waiting for? Come here. Get started
now.
>> Pixie Bricks is the fastest way to solve
internal business problems on top of
tools your team already uses. Describe
the extension you want and get user
interfacing components like forms,
buttons.
Hello everybody and welcome to AI coding
summit 2026.
We are so happy to have you all here
with us. Good morning, good afternoon,
good evening, good night. We all happy
to see you wherever you are. Let's
explore together what happened in the
new developer industry AI developer
industry with development of uh AI and
there are lots of developments recently.
So before we begin let's introduce
ourselves. My name is Nathaniel Kenma. I
work for a company called Twilio. But
one thing I love is that we are working
with AI tools and we're also integrating
AI into a lot of our products. So, it's
really interesting to watch devs get
their hands on some of these products
that have AI in it and implement them.
So, I'm looking forward to seeing what I
can learn so I can understand what I can
pass on. And I'm not here alone. I'm
here with the wonderful Maxi Maximikov.
I'm based in Oslo, Norway. I work at
Microsoft. And my job is very simple. I
just want to make sure that all our
customers are successful with AI native
developer tools like GitHub, GitHub
Copilot and all these amazing stack of
the products. I'm doing solution
engineering for that.
And one very important thing I want to
mention before we ever start our program
questions we want to have this
conference as interactive as possible
and we have tool called slido um and the
code for today's slido is super simple
because uh it represents conference days
2627 2627 just go to slido.com enter
this number and send your questions
along the way how about we try how that
works.
here now and huh today's question is a
bit maybe scary right how how you feel
what what you do do uh if you if AI will
take over your current job I mean there
are pros and cons right uh you have no
job anymore but you have uh much free
time what would you do in your free time
>> I've always thought about this right now
lucky Luckily, I love to talk. I mean,
that's why I'm here. And I love
listening to music. So, I would just
have a little hobby as a radio
presenter. Nothing big, just a small
little radio show, maybe even a podcast
where I just get to chat and just have
fun. Especially if we have UBI and I
don't need to worry about being super
successful. I'm just going to go and
talk about topics I love with friends I
love. How about you, Maxim? Uh I like
playing music and u I secretly hope that
I'm good uh DJ like on very basic level
but this is where yeah I will put all my
time.
>> Nice. Nice. All right. We'll check out
the results of what you put in the
slideo in a moment.
>> Yes. And if you're eager to start
discussion here now you can do this
straight away in our Discord community
channel. Take a moment just scan this
score code and stay connected with
speakers and uh all attendees during the
conference and what's more interesting
after the conference. So just uh just be
part of the community right?
>> Yes being part of the community.
Speaking of the community we want to say
a big thank you to our sponsors today.
Thank you to our platinum sponsor
CloudFare and our wonderful gold
sponsors Google DeepMind, Pixie Bricks,
Red Hat AI, Back Slash, Render, and
Focus Reactive. They support this
community, support all of us. So go and
check out their sponsor boos. They do a
lot of awesome things and the wider
community also includes our media
partners. Thank you to all of them for
helping make the today possible, getting
the word out for the event. It is really
appreciated that they are all part of
this. Now there are some people who are
really really important about making
today happen. You've already met one of
them but meet two more and that is the
AI coding summit program committee.
Let's give them a round of applause
virtually for putting together an
amazing lineup of talks today. I'm
really looking forward to it. If you
learned something today, you got to
thank the speaker obviously thank the
sponsors and all of them but make sure
you thank the programming committee
because they picked the amazing talks
that we are going to hear today.
>> Yeah. And uh I'm one third of the
program committee. So if folks if you're
uh unhappy with the program, I hope
that's not the case. Anyway, feel free
to blame me at least oneird of uh of
your uh efforts. But uh we want to be
social, right? And uh you see all these
social media icons on the screen now.
And hashtag, we love hashtags, right?
And uh we love to to snap a photo
showing how and when and uh on which
device are you watching this uh amazing
conference and take the photo post it on
your favorite social media with uh AI
coding summit hashtag we'll be watching
your posts and the best part everyone
who shares a post on that is
participating in raffle of our amazing
prizes. Um, and uh, do it right now, do
it later. And the prizes are amazing
t-shirt. For example, the one I wear
today, the one I believe Nat is wearing
today. Yay. Yeah, this beautiful yellow
lighting is one of my favorite t-shirts
actually. Uh, but not only, as uh, we
mentioned earlier, G nation multipass
for free. What is multipass? something
from fifth element much much better. Uh
this is actually remote access to many G
nation conferences like React Summit,
JSN Nation, React Advance London and
many many more. Um just find full list
and full conditions on gnation.com.
Definitely check that out. We'd love to
see you at some of those conferences.
Now there's so much going on today. got
the Discord, we've got the amazing
talks, there's a lot of information, but
if you want to be able to stay on track
and keep up to date, check out the
website aiccodingssummit.com.
You're probably on there already
watching us now, but if not, head over
there now and you should see this
navigation. So, underneath me, you have
I'm on the main video and underneath me,
you should see this timeline of the
different talks. Now, usually in an
inerson conference, if you want to
switch tracks, you got to get up and
walk. for you at home. It's just a click
of a button and you can switch between
our two tracks. Today we have the AI
assisted dev track and the AI
engineering track. So you can see what's
live, what's coming up next. You can
even look back at what you've missed.
And you can also join the discussion
rooms tomorrow directly from this
timeline as well. Now, if you're lost at
any point, just drop us a message at our
email events@gitnation.org
and we're there to help. We've got
people watching that email all the time
and making sure that we can help you
with anything you have problems with.
Let me just shout out the two discussion
rooms that we are going to have. We'll
have the real AI native development from
prompt to production discussion room and
Claude versus cursor versus co-pilot who
really helps. I love these two different
discussion rooms and I'm sure many of
you are going to have strong opinions.
So, make sure you join them and make
your voices heard. It's really nice
because we have the host but you can
actually get involved in the
conversation and oftent times there are
people who are really really wellversed
in these fields who will be a part of
that so you can learn and contribute.
We'll also be having a bunch of
different workshops happening after the
conference as well. So check the website
and register for some of these awesome
practical sessions you don't want to
miss. You want to definitely learn but
put it into practice. So check these out
as well.
And as always at all Git Nation
conferences, we want everyone to feel
safe and everyone having great time
during our event. We have code of
conduct. You can find it on
gnation.com/co.
And if at any time you feel that there
is been a violation, please email us
immediately cocitnation.org
and we'll make sure that we take care of
this case. Feedback. It's so important
for us. Basically, this is the main uh
source of uh information we use for
fine-tuning our events to making them
even better to to making them even
better fit for your needs. So, please
please please dedicate just five minutes
to complete the form after event.
And we together with Git Nation team who
is the organizer of the conference are
visioning you a great day full of
knowledge and what's super important
full of fun as well. Let's start. Can't
wait to get started. We are going to
kick off with our first speaker.
I'd like to welcome our first speaker of
the day, the legendary Kenty Dods. and
they're going to be telling us how they
build web applications in 2026. Now,
just in case you've been living under a
rock and you don't know who Kent is, he
is a world-renowned speaker, teacher,
and trainer. And he's very actively
involved in the open-source community as
a maintainer, and a contributor of so
many different popular npm packages. And
he's the creator of epiccreat.dev and
testing javascript.com. And when he says
he's found new ways to build websites,
we can probably learn a lot. Now
remember, if you have any questions
during the talk, you can use the slider
with the code 2627.
And without further ado, make sure
you've got your slider up and ready to
ask questions. Kent, the stage is yours.
Kick us off.
Hello everybody. My name is Kent Cods
and I am thrilled to be here talking
with you all about AI. My talk is titled
how I build web applications in 2026.
And actually it is just the beginning of
2026. So how do I know? Well, maybe I
should retitle this to how I will build
web applications in 2026. But uh for the
last over a decade uh for those of you
who know me, I've been teaching people
how to build quality web applications.
It's just what I enjoy uh doing. So what
does this have to do with AI? Well,
everything has to do with AI these days.
And um building web applications is no
different. So while we may have changed
the way that we build software, and I'm
going to show you uh some of the things
that I do now, uh the ultimate goal is
still the same. we still want to deliver
excellent user experiences for our users
on uh on the web. And so I'm going to
just talk about some of the things that
I have been doing that help me deliver
excellent user experiences faster. So
let's jump into it. First um I want to
tell a little bit of a story. So uh I
have a set of workshop series Epic
React, Epic Web, Epic AI, testing
JavaScript. And uh the more recent of
these, the recent versions are using a a
project that I call the Epic Shop or the
Epic Workshop app. And uh in the old
version of the workshop app, um and and
the old version of Epic React, you were
actually able to download videos for
watching them offline. In version two of
Epic React, we lost that ability. And so
here's one person who was lamenting that
they wanted to be able to download the
course videos for offline work.
Perfectly reasonable suggestion. Um, and
I just that wasn't really a feature. And
with the the nature of the workshop app,
it was actually a lot more uh on me to
do that and provide that experience.
With the original uh Epic React, it was
literally just like download these and
here you've got a bucket full of files.
Good luck organizing them yourselves.
But with the Epic um workshop app, the
videos are right in line with the rest
of everything. If you've never gone
through an Epic Workshop, you really
should. Uh it there's and there's free
ones, too, so you can get a feel for the
experience. It's fabulous. But uh yeah,
so this user was just or learner was was
lamenting the fact that they can't do
that. And I saw this issue and I'm like,
"Yes, I've been thinking about this.
It's just a massive amount of work." So
this was back in 2025. Our uh AI was
really good back then, too. But things
have really changed in just the last
couple months. And so I uh was able just
a couple weeks ago to build out this
feature. Uh so now it's available. Uh
this person's very excited about it. And
um and now everybody who's like the tens
of thousands of people who are going uh
through Epic Workshop apps can now um
download the videos for offline use
which is quite nice. So uh here's just a
quick demo of what that looks like. So
this is this is the workshop app. We're
on a particular exercise here uh for the
MCP workshop. And here I hit the
download button and it downloads. And
you can actually also go to your
preferences to download them all. So
we'll take a look at that. But yeah, so
now this is all downloading offline. The
experience um doesn't really change a
whole lot. then you can delete it to
save uh space and now you can watch it
um as it's being streamed from the
internet. So that's that's the basic
feature, but we also have the ability to
download all of the videos um all at
once so that you don't have to go
through and download each individual
one. It is a lot and uh there's also a
feature to control um what uh your
default quality is. So if you're fine
having a lower quality so that you can
save some space, you can do that uh
really easily. So the um the interesting
thing about this is that um this was a
really significant amount of work uh
that I accomplished 3 weeks ago, but I
didn't do it. Uh so yes, it's 2,000
lines, 2,300 lines of uh code, but I
didn't write that code. It was actually
an AI agent that did it. Um and of
course, like this is no big reveal. You
all are using agents in your software
development. Now my preferred is uh
cursor. I've been using cursor for a
long time and it's fabulous. Um but
whether you're using cursor or cloud or
codeex or whatever the uh principles
that I want to talk with you about and
how I develop software will definitely
apply to um to what you're doing. So
this was like a really huge moment for
me. I I'd been like playing around with
a lot of things but the models had just
gotten so so good that it really changed
my workflow. So let's talk a little bit
about this. um you are now an AI agent
manager. You are a manager of uh
computer things of of these agents. I
know lots of us individual contributors
for a long time. We just don't want to
bother with managing people or whatever.
We don't want to be in management. We
just like writing the software. And you
can continue to do that in the same way
that uh like you still see a horse and
buggy out on the streets of New York.
You don't see a lot of them, but they're
um a fun novelty. So, if you want to be
the fun novelty, then yeah, go ahead and
just continue writing the code yourself.
Um, but uh there's so much more
efficiency and frankly, it's so much
more fun. For me personally, I've had
the most amount of fun controlling all
these agents. We're looking at a a
screenshot of uh just like two weeks
worth of agents in uh and these are just
the cloud agents that I'm using on
cursor and we'll talk about that um that
uh just throwing agents all over the
place. It's awesome. and the tools are
getting really, really good. So, we're
AI agent managers. Um, but what does
that mean? How do you be an effective
manager? Well, let's first talk about
what agents are. Um, the the way that I
like to think about agents is that
they're junior teammates with infinite
stamina and zero context. And if you've
ever been a team lead before, had a
junior on the team, you know the the
sorts of things that you can do to make
them as efficient and successful as
possible. Uh, and those are the same
sorts of activities that you need to do
to make an agent really successful,
managing that context and all of that
stuff. And we're going to talk about
that, too. So, for those uh uninitiated,
here is my definition of an agent. Um,
and I asked um I posted something
similar to this on X and most people
seem to agree that this is a pretty good
mental model for what an agent is. Um,
in fact, I I posted a simpler version of
this and somebody gave me an even better
one. So, here we have our initial
context. initially we're not done with
the task and then while the task is
still not done we're going to pass
context into an LLM we'll get context
back and whether or not we're finished
and when we're done then we exit the
loop and that's that's the agentic loop
um now of course there's a lot going on
in that LLM function those are um
generating like and doing inference and
and uh doing tool calling and stuff like
that uh so this is an oversimplification
of course but the u the thing I want to
call out here is that context piece
uh that's the responsibility of your
harness. So that would be either your uh
cursor or your VS code or your cloud
code, whatever. Um and the prompts that
you write and that's really what we've
been focused on a lot is that um initial
context, that initial prompt. And if we
can get that right, then the agent is
going to be solid and and we're going to
get our one shot uh of like billion
dollar app idea, make no mistakes,
right? So I actually think um that this
is maybe the wrong focus. Um, I think
that our workflows need to change from
prompting to agent loop optimizing. So
that that context is really important
and we're going to talk about that. But
I don't think that prompting is really
this um the thing that's going to make
you the most effective AI agent manager.
It's managing the agent loop. So coming
back to this, you're managing this. How
does it know that it's all done? That is
your job as an AI agent manager. And if
you think about a manager for people,
that honestly is the primary job of a a
manager of a team of developers as well
is how do they know when they've
actually accomplished the task? Do they
understand the task well? So there
there's a lot of nuance to this, but
hopefully this gives you the right
mental model uh to think about and
frames some of the the tips and advice
I'm going to give through uh the rest of
this uh time together. So uh this is
cursor. I've got the the browser mode up
on the right. We'll talk about that in a
little bit. Um, and I've got the agent
in the middle and then my list of agents
here on the left. Um, I bootstrapped
this app using a project that I just
created called EpicFlare. This is like
the Epic Stack for those of you familiar
with the Epic Stack. Um, just built for
Remix 3 and Cloudflare. Um, and uh, it's
got a a couple nice goodies. This is
where I think I'm going to be pushing
uh, going forward is um, building out
this uh, stack. But the this is like the
first piece of advice that I can give
you, especially if you're planning on
starting a new project and you're just
really excited to get to get going on
this project. The the probably the
biggest waste of time that you could do
or biggest waste of tokens is to use the
agent to scaffold and generate the
project from scratch. It's just there
like there are so many things that
actually don't matter um in like
architectural decisions and it's going
to just take you a lot of time. Now,
granted, you can do this a lot faster
than we used to be able to, and you can
use lots of the skills that I'm uh
giving you to have the agent to help you
build that out, but there are some
really great tools out there. And
frankly, I'm not a PHP guy, but if I
were, Laravel would just kill this like
so so well because they have this
starting point. So, uh Ruby on Rails is
the same. Uh and those conventions um
make a really really big impact. So, I'm
building my own because I just really
like TypeScript. I really like
Cloudflare and I really like Remix 3.
It's not released yet, so like we're
still waiting on that, but really really
excited about that. And so um I'm
building out this so that new apps that
I start can have the architecture
already created for them. We're going to
talk about that a little bit as well. So
when you're starting a new project, my
first tip for you is uh like whether
it's an existing project that you're
onboarding into or uh you've
bootstrapped a project and you're about
ready to get going, um talk to the
agent. use ask mode. Um I don't know
what that is in in other agents. Like I
said, I'm focused on cursor, but there's
got to be a way to just ask the agent,
tell me about this ar the architecture
of this application. Help me understand
it. Ask it questions about it. Uh to
onboard yourself. Um we I I don't think
that people talk to the agent enough.
Just ask questions. Don't tell it to do
stuff. Just ask it. And that's what the
ask mode in cursor is all about. It's
very very helpful. Um and then uh you
want the agent to ask you questions. So
you're going to do something. You could
just like come up with the plan all on
your own, but what if instead you say,
"Hey, agent, I need to add this
feature." Or in in this case, um I'm
going we're going to build an app called
Home Energy that allows you to input u
the different u uh home appliances that
you have and how many watts they are
rated for. And then it'll give you an
estimate on how much energy you can
expect your home to be using. Um if
like, you know, an estimate of course.
Um this is a problem that I'm currently
experiencing. So that's why I I want to
know, okay, what is using so much energy
in my house? So, um, but yeah, this is
the the tip right here. Ask the agent to
ask you questions rather than trying to
like, here's the plan. I just wrote the
whole document. Say, please ask me
questions one at a time. This is also
important. One at a time. In fact, I got
Yeah, underlined it one at a time. Um,
because the agent's questions will
actually improve as it's answering
those. Lots of times, if you say,
"Please ask me questions," it'll just be
like, "Here's 30 questions." And, um,
some of them are irrelevant. And if the
agent just asked one at a time, it
wouldn't have even asked those. So I
say, "Ask me one at a time what are uh
what the plans are for the app, all of
that, everything you need to know so
that we can um create tasks for uh
building out an MVP or building out this
feature or uh fixing this bug or
whatever. Um, I don't always do this
with things that are like pretty well
defined, um, or whatever. But yeah, if
I've got a big project ahead of me,
absolutely talking back and forth to
agent, make sure that it understands,
make sure that I'm covering all of my
bases and the way that I'm thinking
about the problem. So then, um, we want
to uh, keep the agent properly scoped.
So I went through, answered a bunch of
questions, and uh, the agent started
asking like really specific
implementation detail things. And with
an MVP uh and especially with like
today's uh abilities of our agents, it's
really easy to change stuff. And so I
just said, "Yeah, whatever you think is
simple is fine. We can make adjustments.
Um don't get too far in the
implementation details. Um let's just
focus on higher level stuff and uh I'll
take your judgment." So scope your agent
um as you're asking these kinds of
questions as well and preparing the
plan. Um okay. So um it I switched it
over to agent mode and I say, "Hey, go
ahead and create the task." So that's
what this is. Now we're in agent mode.
The agent will actually do stuff now uh
beyond just asking uh questions going
back and forth. So that is a very
intentional like let's talk first and
now let's let's take action. It created
four tasks based off of the conversation
that we had. And um I told it hey I want
it to be like really clear acceptance
criteria. Uh talk about uh testing and
and all of that to make sure that when
we're making a plan to accomplish these
tasks uh we're including all of those
important things. So, we'll talk about
those here in a bit, too. Um, so, oh
yeah, that's the bottom. I'm like
hitting the down arrow and nothing's
happening. That's cuz I got to move
over. All right. So, now we're going to
plan. Uh, so I open up a brand new
agent. Uh, so get rid of all that extra
context that is irrelevant to this first
task. So like that's honestly that's
part of the the purpose of um of doing
that plan that uh overarching planning
in a separate agent in the first place
is to say okay like I want you to search
around the codebase understand this
codebase like gather all the context you
need then give me a basic plan uh or or
a task and then start a new agent your
your job is this task you don't have the
context from all the other stuff you
just have the this chunk of uh context
that is relevant to you um please make a
plan to implement that task. And here uh
this is in plan mode. Now um plan mode
in cursor and this is common in other
agents. Uh it tells the agent to ask
questions. So it's uh going to look at
the context that you give it try to and
from there it it went through and looked
through the codebase as well to gather
more information about it so it would
know the right questions to ask. And so
then it comes back to me and it says
here are a couple questions. This is
where your experience as a software
developer really pans out. And this is
why I think that um we're actually still
safe as software developers, who knows
how good the models get in the future um
and how good the tools get, but right
now if I were to hand uh an agent like
Cloud Code or Cursor over to a
non-technical person, they wouldn't be
very successful with it. So um until
that day comes, your experience as a
software developer is still highly
highly valuable. And so knowing the
right questions to ask, knowing how to
uh communicate with the agent, really
really important. So here we're going to
uh make a plan. It it's asking me some
questions. I go through an answer. You
can switch from plan mode back to ask
mode. If it's asking a question, you're
like, I actually don't know. What do you
think? Um and you can kind of go back
and forth. And uh ultimately when it's
when you're all happy with uh like all
the questions that it's asked and
everything, it's going to give you a
plan. You with your experience as a
software developer can review that plan
and uh and make sure that it's doing
what you expect it to do. uh and and you
can actually iterate with the agent on
that as well like oh you know what I
don't want it to like store watts I
actually want it to store amps or
whatever uh you can control that from a
product perspective uh as well as even
the implementations uh perspective which
is why your experience is so valuable
okay and then um here uh this is where
the agent loop uh closing that agent
loop becomes really helpful and it
becomes even more helpful later we'll
talk about but here I'm saying iterate
with the test uh and your implement
implementation until they're passing.
And it it failed the first time. And I
said, "No, no, no. Keep on like it."
What I'm saying here is like keep on
going until it's passing. That is the
agent loop. You set it off and then you
can go work on something else. And and
um and that is where these agents become
really really helpful and impactful.
When it's done, you can go ahead and
review. And so in cursor, you have the
uh review changes. You look through
everything. Um you'll notice here it's
the test is actually using some syntax
you might not be very familiar with.
This is relatively new syntax in
JavaScript, but it's a better way to do
a before each and an after each in
tests. And the only way that the agent
knew to do that is because I have it all
documented here inside uh the agents
docs and which is referenced in the
agents MD file. So having documentation
uh all spelled out here really nicely,
whether that be skills or agents ND with
uh references to other documentation
files really important on uh not only
closing that loop and helping the agent
like know the right direction to go and
how to keep tests simple and whatever.
Um but uh it also helps you maintain uh
control so you don't have to spend so as
much time reviewing it to make sure that
it's uh working the way that you want it
to work.
And then uh uh you can actually make the
agent uh do a review of that uh those
changes as well. And so I typically like
to have the agent and uh the review
agent and the actual agent do a couple
iterations. So like build it out um make
it like test it nicely and then have the
agent review it. Iterate on each one of
these steps and only when all that's
done then I'm going to go and review it
with my time. Um this is really really
powerful. uh a really nice workflow and
it allows you to like send them off to
do their thing and then you can go off
to do yours.
Okay, so now we've got um manual testing
is a really cool uh things here. So on
this uh task, we're actually building
out UI. It would be really like when I'm
developing, I'm going to be doing
automated tests of course, but I also
want to like make sure the user
experience looks nice and everything.
And so with manual testing, you can
actually have it open up the dev server
like it's running the dev server itself.
it figured out how to do that or that's
documented and then it opens up an
actual browser and the cursor is
controlling the browser. You can watch
it happen. Uh or you don't watch it
happen, you just go do something else.
Um but uh it um can actually use that
experience. And what's interesting is
when I was doing this um it was having
trouble with the automated test. And so
I said, "Okay, okay, stop, stop. Try and
figure out what's wrong by actually
running things manually and then uh you
can do the automated test." And it
worked. it it went through this and
like, "Oh, now I know what's going on."
And it's able it was able to figure out
uh the problem. Um, and then another
huge tip, something that I do all the
time is now I want to do MCP uh tools
for this uh I want this app to work in
chat GPT. And so here uh I'm telling the
agent to learn from examples because MCP
is still um a relatively new thing. The
best practices aren't really established
uh very well yet. But I happen to know
that Adam over here has some really
highquality MCP servers. And so here I'm
telling the agent to go and clone those
repos, figure out what is similar about
those things to determine what are some
really good practices, proven practices
in these repos, and add that to um our
task so that when we go through to
planet, we have like uh some guidance on
a good way to build out MCP servers,
which is awesome. Um, the other thing
that helped out here, uh, is EpicFly
already had MCP, uh, tools and the OOTH
flow already implemented, which is why
that architecture is so critical to have
that in place. The agent's a lot more
powerful if that's all done. And of
course, I used an agent to build that
out, too. But I'm uh saying like you
typically want to have that piece done
and then you can start adding features
to it. Just like with a human, too, it's
a lot easier to kind of chunk that work
up. And then the cursor.com/agents, this
is my addiction. I go to sleep um with
this. But uh yeah, so you can kick off
any number of things like run a security
audit, run a accessibility obt
this this is a really simple thing. Uh
just, you know, one sentence prompt and
the agent will run in the cloud and it
will open a PR when it's done. And um
and it's really really good. And I in
fact um when I did that MX download
video thing, that offline video, I
actually used a background agent for
that. I used a cloud agent for that. And
um it it worked amazingly well. And um
the really cool thing about this is that
cursor also has Bugbot. You have other
tools as well like Code Rabbit and stuff
that will review and um with Cursor when
the Bugbot shows up and here's a bunch
of things that are wrong, the agent will
actually automatically pick those up and
make adjustments and then they'll go
back and forth. uh it does seem to stop
eventually, but um if it's like really
it goes back and forth a lot um to avoid
it getting out of control, but um by the
time I finally look at it, the agent is
good with it. Bugbot is good with it and
the uh tests like validation, all that
stuff is passing. And so what I'm
reviewing is like some solid code. Uh I
can pull it down and test it out myself.
If it's like a really big UI change, I
want to experience that user experience.
Um but it's a great place to start. Um,
and even simple prompts can get you here
in uh in some cases where you just like
here's the bug like when I do this and
that and that then it fails. So write me
a test that reproduces that problem and
then implement it. And that's that agent
loop that you're working on. Bugbot is
fabulous. Uh, and yeah, this is
dangerous input. I sometimes will stay
up really late just prompting and then
I'll go to sleep and I'll first thing in
the morning grab it my phone and look
what what did it do? So be careful with
that.
But anyway, the my point here is that
closing the agent loop is even more
important in those situations where it's
running off your machine. You can like
look at what's going on um and see the
thread and everything, but typically
it's just like running on its own. And
so having really great documentation,
really good tests, and um a clear here's
what the outcome is supposed to look
like, that is super super important. And
um and the tools are are getting better
u for this as well. So back to this I'm
almost finished here. Um I actually want
to talk a little bit about that initial
context. So a lot of people will say uh
that the architecture is more important
than prompting. And and actually that's
probably what you're getting from uh
this talk is that I'm I'm saying
architecture is more important than
prompting. having a really good starting
uh place is um it makes it a lot easier
for you to just say add a test for this
and like it has that all set out so it
knows what to do or you know add add um
authentication with Google uh okay it's
got all of that structure uh there um I
actually don't think the architecture is
necessarily better than prompting I
actually think the architecture is
prompting the architecture is a part of
the prompt and if you can document
things well enough then and I use the
agent to keep that documentation up to
um and you can um have things set in a a
good architecture from the experience
that you have as a software developer.
Then the agent uses that as part of its
input context to um to go off and do
what it's doing. So the architecture is
part of the prompt and the prompt is
really really critical along with that
agent loop. So you are now a product
project manager, product manager and a
team lead. I don't know if you wanted to
be that but you are. You are an AI agent
manager. That like all of those roles is
an AI agent manager and your management
tool effectiveness is measured by your
experience. And that's what I want to
teach you. I want to teach you how to be
an experienced uh full stack software
developer that is uh able to direct and
orchestrate a bunch of AI agents. We've
got a lot of really exciting things
coming down uh the line with uh tooling
getting better and everything, but uh
your ability to convert the user
experience that's needed into um an
actual product is more important than
ever. And if you uh feel like that's
important for you, then uh join my
mailing list and I've got some exciting
things I'm working on for that. With
that, thank you very much. I appreciate
your time and look forward to seeing you
around the internet.
Thank you so much. That was amazing.
Always a great speaker and it's always
good to have Kent on the stage with us.
We will be talking to Kent in just a
second asking him all of the questions
that you have. So remember, go over to
the slideo and ask your questions. But
let's start with the warm-up one we did
earlier. What would you do if AI takes
your current job? I I love how people
first of all I I love 58% of you who are
using AI to make you better at your
current job, but I also want to explore
some of the other ones. And so we've got
becoming a farmer was came second,
becoming a pro beach.
I mean like that is my hobby on this
side for sure. Um but whoever sent open
a bakery please, I would like to visit
you and get some of the sweet treats
that you can make. Okay, enough joking.
Let's actually get in with Kent and ask
him some of the questions that are on
your mind. So, we're going to back to
the stage. Kent, remember to ask your
questions on the slider at 2627.
All right, let's get started. First of
all, Kent, it's so good to see you. I'd
love to hear you talk about like
building with AI in this new world, but
this world is always changing. So, do
you mind just telling us a little bit
like in the past week, what new things
in the world of AI that you think are
relevant that maybe you couldn't sneak
into your talk this last minute? Do you
think
>> Yeah, that's a uh I I did wear the same
clothes and I'm in the same studio, but
that was a recording. So, um but it's
not that old. It's not it's not that
outdated, but AI just move so fast that
it's impossible to like I could have
recorded that just now and or or like
given it to you just now and there'd
still be things that have changed since
I gave it. It's it's wild. But the big
thing that I wanted to call out
specifically is that cursor has uh
released their uh cloud agents uh
computer use uh which basically every
cloud agent that you spawn off um is not
just running in some sort of isolated
terminal somewhere but it actually has a
full desktop and so it can um install
you know it's it's a Linux desktop so it
can install whatever you need to it u
for web applications in particular it
has a a browser already installed. uh
you can actually create an environment
and then uh snapshot that environment so
it can restore it very quickly. Um so I
know this sounds like a sales pitch for
Cursor. I don't work for Cursor or
anything but um I uh just really love
their product and um that was one thing
that I actually couldn't share in my
talk um because it wasn't released yet.
But uh for the last month and a half,
I've been using that um a lot. And
that's a huge thing that causes the
agent loop where um now the uh your AI
agent can actually pull up the um your
website, click around and and actually
do things and notice, oh, actually it
doesn't work when I've got the whole app
pulled up and and I'm clicking around
and stuff. So, uh huge thing for closing
agent loop. Also, um I actually do a lot
from my phone. Um, and I'll just like
send a little prompt and then later I
can look at the uh screen recording that
it makes and like uh screenshots and
stuff. Um, and so that I am actually
able to to close a lot of issues right
from my phone. So that was one big thing
that happened in AI um at least in the
cursor world since the last time um I
recorded that video.
Whoops. That was being it. There's
always things changing and it's cool
that you get to stay on the cutting edge
of all of this. We've got a couple of
questions rolling in. Coming from the
famous anonymous
uh which is asking about that kind of
week you talked about and the different
stages and ways you might use agents. Do
you use different models for different
tasks like asking, planning and then
being an agent and going off and doing a
whole workflow?
>> Great question. Um, for a little while
there I was kind of jumping between Opus
and GPT5 uh 2 uh and then um Gemini uh 3
and then Composer. Uh Cursor released
their composer 1.5 a little bit ago. Um
and uh yeah, like I will occasionally
jump to uh Composer when I need things
to run really fast. Uh but uh GPT53 coex
has gotten really fast now too, so I
don't really feel the need to do that.
Um, I know a lot of people seem to say
that GPT is very soulless. I don't
really need my AI assistant or my uh,
you know, AI to have a soul. I I
honestly don't care that much. Uh, and
so I I pretty much use GPT 5.3 for just
about everything. Uh, and I'm really
happy with it.
>> Absolutely. No, I think it's also really
interesting. when you've got a really
well architected setup, switching
between models becomes a lot more easier
than having completely different tools
and spaces. Um, and and even with all of
this switching, how do you approach
learning and keeping up to date? Like
you said, things change like in the past
week, in the past hours, things are
changing. So, do you have a strategy to
help you stay at that bleeding edge?
Yeah, you know, I think I had some good
practice with the um like being a
JavaScript developer in the 201s uh
where everybody was complaining about,
oh, there's a new framework every week
and um this that was nothing compared to
what we're doing now with AI because
like we're there's a lot going on every
week. Um, but uh in in my experience
with that, I I learned to just tune out
uh not noise like it it's all like lots
of it is high signal. Um but uh just
being okay with not having to stay up to
date on every single little thing. Uh
and I think that there's a lot of value
in finding a workflow that you're happy
with and sticking to it rather than
changing it all the time. Uh you've got
to ship stuff. Uh that's I mean some
people just get a real kick out of
changing their workflow all the time.
That's not me. Uh, I want to ship
things. And so, um, I found a workflow
that I'm really happy with. Um, I, it's
not that I put my head in the sand. I do
know that there's a thing called open
code and I know about cloud code and
like I I know about codeex and and all
of that, but um, I just decided let's
let's just focus on cursor. uh and they
keep on releasing new things to make
some of um the things that I find hard
in developing software with agents uh to
be a lot easier. For example, like the
um the uh computer use that they have
now. So, um yeah, that's that's how I
remain sane.
>> Yeah, it's not easy in this day and age.
All right, one last question and then
we're going to go off. You talked about
MCP usage for agents to learn from, but
there's agent skills. There's a lot of
different kind of approaches to this.
Um, do you have any thoughts or
preferences or even guiding principles
to help choose which one to use?
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, actually, Epic AI Pro is
one of the things that I uh work on
right now and I've got an MCP course on
there right now. So, clearly I I care I
think that MCP is interesting enough for
me to put all that time to put a course
together. Um and yeah, I think um with
all of the different uh things that you
have available, there are some cursor
specific things. There are uh cloud
specific things and uh I actually try to
step back a little bit from that and I
pretty much use a handful of uh useful
MCP servers and then um my agents MD
file is an index of documentation. So
it's just like if you need to know about
this, go over there. If you need that,
then go over here. And that works really
well. I I have not really used skills a
whole lot. Uh I found just having an
agents MD that is a a you know
relatively small with an index to more
documentation um makes my agents really
effective. So that's what I do.
>> Awesome. That is all the time we have. I
see there are many people who have more
questions. They can find you online as
well and ask those questions and also
check out some of your amazing courses.
Definitely well known for those. Thank
you so much for joining us today. It's
been really great having you. Thank you,
Nathaniel. Take care, everybody.
Thank you so much. Let's move on with
the day. I want to pause and say a big
shout out and thank you to our gold
sponsor, Google DeepMind. Google
DeepMind if you've not heard of them.
They are a team of scientists,
engineers, ethicists, and more working
to build the next generation of AI
systems safely and responsibly. So, you
should definitely check them out. All
right, moving on to our next speaker, we
have Ado. They are going to be talking
about Agentic by default. It's a whole
new way of thinking about developer
workflows, and I'm really excited. Edo
has been spent 15 years building things
on the web and helping others do the
same. Currently, they work at Anthropic
and they manage community and create
content to help developers like me and
you get the most out of CL. So, there's
a lot of learnings that we can take away
from this talk. Remember, if you have
questions, head over to the Slido 2627
and ask your questions. But without
further ado, tell us what's new in the
world of code and how can we rethink our
developer workflows. Take it away.
Hey there, welcome to the AI coding
summit. My name is Otto Cookage and I am
a community manager at Enthropic. And
today we're going to talk about agent
decoding, what it is, and concrete
patterns that you can use today to get
dramatically more done with cloud code.
And I promise I'm going to try to keep
this as practical as possible. And
everything I show you today, you're
going to be able to go and try in your
terminal in about 5 minutes. So let's
get into it.
So the obvious first question is what
makes something agentic?
And to me, it really comes down to this
loop of plan, act, and verify. How most
people use AI for coding today is they
will ask their LLM a question. They'll
get some text output back, and they
might copy and paste it into their IDE
and see if it compiles. And if it
doesn't, they'll paste the error back
in, get some more output, and try again.
You're basically playing telephone with
a very smart AI. An agentic tool is
fundamentally different. When you give
it a task, it doesn't just spit out code
and hope for the best. It plans first.
It reads the codebase, tries to
understand the context, and figure out
what files matter and drafts an
approach. Then it acts, writes the code,
runs commands, uses tools, and makes
actual real changes to your project. And
then finally, and it verifies what it
did. It's going to run the test. It's
going to try to build the application.
It's going to read the error output or
the logs and if something's broken, it
is going to try and fix it. And if it
doesn't, it's going to loop back again.
It's going to replan, react, and
reverify over and over again until the
job is actually done.
And if we look at each of the phases,
the planning phase is going to use a
certain set of tools like read, g, and
think to actually try to understand the
problem. In the acting phase, it's going
to write new files, edit existing files,
run bash commands, and access additional
tools through MCP servers. Verifying
finally is going to use those same tools
to check its own work. And if we look at
the glowing dots on this slide, bouncing
between the three nodes, that's really
what it's going on with cloud code. It
continues this cycle until the task at
hand is complete.
And here is another way you can think
about cloud code. It is just an agent in
your terminal. Your prompt goes in on
the left side. Something like add email
notifications when a user gets
mentioned. And that's it. That is the
instruction. We're not telling it how to
do it. We're not telling it where to go.
We're just giving it what we want. We're
giving it the task. And in the middle,
we've got cloud code, an agent sitting
in the terminal with four core
capabilities. the ability to think and
reason, the ability to read our
codebase, the ability to write and edit,
and the ability to use various tools via
Bash. It's going to reason about our
code. It's going to read uh read files
in our codebase, write new code, and
execute the commands until we get to the
right hand side of working code. Our
test passing the the code being PR ready
and ready to merge.
And what happens in the middle box is
where all the magic lives. Claude is
learning about our existing notification
system that we have in place to
understand the patterns that we're
implementing. It is writing new code
that matches those conventions and not
new ones. And then it's running the test
suite to make sure that the new code
that it wrote and added is actually not
breaking. And if something does break,
it goes back and fixes it until we get
to our working code. So at the end of
the day, you give it the what and it's
going to figure out the how. Okay, so
that's just a very high level overview,
but now let's get into agentic coding
patterns and practical techniques for
getting the most from our agent coding
tools.
We'll kick it off with context. And
honestly, this is probably the most
important one, giving the agent the
right context. And the best way to do it
is via a cloud.md file. It is a markdown
file that lives in the root of your
project, and Claude reads it at the
start of every single session. Think of
it as onboarding documentation. And if
your project does not already have a
cloud MD file, you can run the /init
command to have cloud code automatically
read the codebase and write its own
cloud. MD file based on what it finds.
Some good things to add in your CloudMD
file are your frequently used commands,
your coding style and preferences,
naming conventions, things like that,
your architectural patterns that are
specific to your project, and your text
stack. and key directories. And we can
see on the right here, I have some
commands. I have the text stack that I'm
using and conventions that I want clot
code to follow when working with clot
code. The next pattern goes handinhand
with having really good context, and
that is plan mode.
Now, a problem that people will
typically run into when they are first
trying agentic coding is they'll give
Claude a very complex task and expect it
to just go out and do the work and get
it right on the first try. And don't get
me wrong, Claude will attempt to do it.
It's going to go look at the codebase.
It's going to do its best to make as
many changes as possible to accomplish
the task, but without a plan, the odds
of it going off the rails are
significant. And plan mode can fix this.
When you toggle it, instead of cloud
going and eagerly making changes to your
codebase based on the prompt you gave
it, it's going to give you a detailed
plan. And instead of immediately
rewriting half of your application,
Cloud Code is going to read your
existing code, understand the patterns,
maybe ask a clarifying question or two,
and then propose a plan of attack.
Here's what I'm going to change. Here
are the files I I'll touch, and here's
the approach that I'm thinking of
making. You get to review this plan. You
get to push back. Claude is going to
adjust the plan, and only once you
approve does it start making changes. I
highly recommend using plan mode for any
non-trivial tasks as it's going to make
your code output much much better. For
pattern three, I see this one as much
more of a mindset shift rather than an
actual pattern. And the reason I say
that is a lot of times developers will
give instructions to Claude on what they
wanted to do and they can get very
verbose and very specific. And what I
want to challenge you to do is to focus
on describing what you want done rather
than how. So we have a couple examples
here on the lefth hand side and the
right hand side on what to do and what
not to do. So I always encourage
developers not to give it very very
descriptive instructions on go to this
specific line and make this specific
change. Rather I try to give it a task,
give it an issue and let cloud code
figure out how to best implement it. So
rather than saying you know go to
package.json and add zot as a dependency
I might say something like add input
validation to all of our API endpoints
and ensure that we are getting
consistent error responses for each API
endpoint instead of telling it exactly
how to do it and how I want all of the
code written. And a pro tip here as well
is cloud code has a concept of slash
commands. So any prompt that you're
using multiple times a day you can
actually store it as a slash command.
save that prompt and then you just run
the command and it's going to run the
prompt. It can accept arguments as well
making the whole thinking and tasks
workflow much much simpler.
Starting with pattern 4, we are moving
into power user territory. And the
feature that I want to talk about here
is sub aents. So sub aents are
specialized AI assistants that run in
their own isolated context. Each one
gets its own 200k token context window
completely separate from your main
agent. And why does this matter? Well,
two reasons. The first is
specialization. If you look at the left
example here, we have a code reviewer
sub agent. Its focus is on code quality,
security, and maintainability. It only
has the ability to read code. It can
read, it can GP, but it cannot
accidentally modify or write code. And
it also uses a faster model for speed
because reviews don't necessarily need a
heavyweight model. On the right hand
side, we have a debugger sub aent. And
this one gets the edit and bash tools
because it needs to be able to actually
fix things. It's going to inherit with
whatever model we're using. And it has a
totally different job from the code
review agent. And the second big reason
is context management. Your main
session's context window is precious
real estate. If a code review reads 50
files and generates a massive analysis,
that is all going to be sitting and
polluting your context window, eating up
space and eating up Claude's memory.
With a sub agent, all that work happens
in isolation and only the summary comes
back to the main agent. You can create
agents with the / agents command or just
drop that or just drop a markdown file
in your cloud. folder. I am a big
proponent of putting as much work on the
sub agents as possible and having the
main agent just oversee the work and
assign additional work. The next pattern
I want to talk about is hooks. And hooks
are userdefined shell commands that
execute automatically at various life
cycle points. They give Claude
deterministic control over probabilistic
AI. And we have 14 different life cycle
events that you can tap into and execute
shell commands or scripts once these
events happen. So for example, pre-tool
use, you can block or allow specific
tool use. Permission request, you can
auto approve or deny permissions. Uh for
a session start life cycle, you can load
additional contexts from a different
place or set environment variables for
that session that that don't exist. Uh
and many many more. Notifications is one
that I use a ton just to send me a
either an audio or a visual notification
when cla needs my attention. Hooks are
way way underrated in my opinion and
something that everybody that's serious
about using cloud code should invest
heavily in.
Pattern six is MCP or model context pro
protocol. This is the universal
integration layer and honestly one of
the most exciting things happening in
the AI tooling space. Without MCP, cloud
code lives in your terminal and it can
read files and run shell commands. But
it can't directly query your database.
It can't post to Slack. It can't browse
to your Jira board or the browser. But
with MCP, you can configure various
servers in your settings. And suddenly
cloud has access to everything that you
would have access to your GitHub, your
Postgress, Slack, Jira, Stripe, Linear,
and so many more. MCP servers expose
various tools that let you execute
actions across systems. And here's what
that actually means in practice. You can
tell Claude to find all of the tickets
assigned to me in linear that are
blocking the release, check the
corresponding PRs in GitHub, and post a
summary to our Slack channel. and Claude
if you have the MCP servers set up will
be able to do all of that. It's going to
use the various tools provided by the
MCP servers to complete the tasks. And
the best part is this is just one single
protocol. No custom integrations. If
somebody built an MCP server for a
specific service, every MCP compatible
tool can use it immediately. For pattern
number seven, this is a newer capability
of Claude and Agentic tools called
skills. And skills are how you turn
Claude from a general purpose assistant
into a domain specialist who really
knows your stuff. Every team has
institutional knowledge. Your naming
conventions, your deployment checklist,
your API design patterns, brand
guidelines, and so much more. Normally,
this stuff is tribal. It might live in a
notion page or an outline page. But with
skills, you can package all of this
expertise and claude can load it on
demand. The design here is really
elegant and is made up of three key
features that make it so powerful. The
first is progressive discovery. Rather
than loading all of the skills into
context every single time you start up a
session, Claude will only load the skill
metadata. So in our example here, it's
only going to load the name, front-end
design, and the description.
The skills will also be autonomously
activated when needed. So, if you give
Claude a prompt that has something to do
with front-end design, it's going to
look at the skill directory and see that
there is a front-end design skill, at
which point it's going to load the rest
of the instructions for the skill. And
additionally, any scripts or any other
files that are relevant for this skill
and skills are universally portable. So,
the same skills that work in cloud code,
work in the API, work on cloud.ai, or
work in various custom agents. So you
just have to write the skill once and
you can use it everywhere. And skills
are an open standard that any agentic
tool can can leverage and use. So we
talked a lot about hooks and skills and
MCP servers and plugins are really where
all of these different capabilities come
together. The plugins primitive solves
the share my setup problem. A plug-in
bundles everything into one sharable and
installable package. Meaning we can
bundle commands, agents, hooks, skills,
and MCP servers and share them across
our entire team. So for our example
here, if we have a front-end design
plugin, it's going to it might contain a
design command, a front-end design
skill, a style check hook, and a Figma
MCP server. And with a single command of
/install plugin, front-end design, we
can get all of these capabilities on our
machine and share it across our entire
team. You can almost think of it as npm
for AI tooling because that's basically
what it is.
Pattern number nine, working in
parallel. This is one of the biggest
productivity unlocks in your entire
workflow. With git work trees, if you
haven't used them before, they create
isolated working directories that share
the same git history. And what this
means for us is you can run a completely
separate cloud code session in each one.
And each session gets its own fresh 200k
context window and each one can be doing
a different task simultaneously. So here
we are implementing oat oat 2 with
pixie. We're building an analytics
dashboard migrating our user table to
usuids and fixing rate limit edge cases
all simultaneously.
So we have four independent cloud code
sessions all running at the same time
all doing real meaningful work. And this
is actually what my workflow looks most
days. I come in, I look at my sprint
board and I spin up multiple work trees
based on recent tickets that that have
been opened or recent things that I need
to do. Then I go get coffee in the
morning. And when I come back, I have
multiple PRs ready for review. And I'm
not exaggerating. On a good day, I could
close out 10, 20, 30 PRs uh by early
afternoon. And since we are using good
work trees here, we don't have to worry
about the cloud co sessions interfering
with each other. Each work tree is fully
isolated. Each clot has its own context,
so we don't have to worry about merge
conflicts until we're actually ready to
merge.
If there's one thing you take away from
this talk is that you should be using
git work trees and parallelizing your
cloud code work. And for our last
pattern, I want to talk about how you
can make your agents non-interactive.
We have two really cool capabilities
that allow you to leverage all of the
capabilities of cloud code in a
non-interactive way. The first one is
running claude code in headless mode. So
in your terminal, if you do claude and
pass in the -p flag, it's going to run
claude without a terminal UI.
With this, you can pipe in a prompt get
structured output back. Meaning that
meaning you can leverage this in your
CI/CD pipeline or for example here we
have a GitHub action example that is
going to automatically do a code review
on every single PR. It's going to pipe
in the diff. It's going to get
structured JSON feedback on bugs,
security issues, and style violations
automatically. But it doesn't just have
to be code review. You can have it
automatically try and fix the errors.
You can have it document the changes,
create change logs, migration guides,
and so much more. And finally, we also
have the cloud agent SDK. And this is
the same agentic harness that powers
cloud code, but as a programmable
library available for both Typescript
and Python. So if you want to build your
own production agents with custom
tooling, custom workflows, custom
everything, you don't have to reinvent
the infrastructure, you can build on top
of what's already been battle tested by
millions of developers. And one thing to
be really clear about before we wrap up
this talk is that agentic coding isn't
all or nothing. It's not trust the AI
with everything or approve every single
keystroke. It is a spectrum and you
should move fluidly along with it based
on your comfortability level. On the
left, we have full control where you are
still heavily using the plan mode.
You're approving every step. You're
getting more and more comfortable with
agentic coding. And this is really good
for anything that is security sensitive,
working on a new codebase, and anything
where the cost of a mistake might be
pretty high. In the middle, where I
think most people are, is kind of this
guided autonomy. This is where most of
your daily work should live. You set the
guardrails. You have a cloud MD for your
conventions. You have set up some hooks
for enforcement, permission settings for
boundaries and so on. And you let cloud
code work within them. So you give it
enough freedom to be genuinely useful
but enough structure that you can
actually sleep at night. And finally on
the right we have full autonomy,
headless mode, adding claw to your CI/CD
pipeline, batching operations, fire,
fire and forget. Use this for well-
definfined repeatable tasks where you've
already validated the approach.
Personally, I think the sweet spot for
most teams is right in the middle with
guarded with guided autonomy where you
give it a good set of guardrails and and
let the magic happen. And if this is all
new to you and you really just want to
dip your toes in, here are four steps
you can take to experience agentic
coding today. One, install cloud code
and run /init in your terminal. It's
going to give the agent context about
your project. In about 5 minutes, you're
going to get a Claude MD file that is
going to give you the basis for what
Claude can do. To use plan mode, you can
hit shift tab to switch into plan mode
in in Claude and give it a task. Review
the plan that that it comes up with. And
if you feel good about it, let it
execute. Three, iterate on your CloudMD
file. Every time Claude does something
wrong or does something really good that
you want it to repeat, add it to the
CloudMD file. Your cloud MD file should
be a living, breathing document that
evolves as your project evolves. And
finally, let the agent do some work.
Give it a task. Let it work. Let it
sorrect when it fails. And resist the
urge to interrupt it after the first
misstep. The plan act verify loop means
that cloud will often catch and fix its
own mistake. So give it room to do that.
Four steps. That's it. Give it a try.
That is your on-ramp to agentic code. So
that brings us to the conclusion of this
talk. I've shared a couple of resources
here on what to do next. Install Cloud
Code, view the documentation, and if you
want more tips and tricks on how to
really get the most out of Cloud Code, I
created an admin of Claude in December
of last year that has 31 tips and tricks
to really optimize your workflow. Thank
you so much for joining me today. I hope
you learned something and I hope to see
you online.
Another
great talk. Thank you so much. It is a
pleasure to be joined here live with
Ada. How are you doing?
>> Not too bad. How about yourself?
>> I am doing good. It's always good when I
get to hear from people, especially
people who are embedded in building all
of these new technologies like literally
paving the way the frontier that we are
in in this world of of AI and AI
development as and it's so good to be
able to actually hang out and learn from
you from your talks and also to be able
to like work with you as well and it's
really really good to be here. There are
so many questions not only from someone
that I have in my head but also from the
audience. So I think we should jump
straight into them and let's start with
the first one. This one comes from
Brandon. Thank you for your question
Brandon which is this is kind of the
similar thread I can see in some of
these different questions which is how
do you decide to use a sub agent or a
skill? So would you use an accessibility
sub agent or an accessibility skill?
What are some of those criteria for
deciding which one to use?
Yeah, definitely. This is a a really
really good question and one I get a
ton. Um, and the way the way to think
about it is the actual skill itself is
the expertise, is the knowledge, is the
how to do it. Um, a sub agent is just
the execution layer. So, uh, you can
have sub agents and give them specific
skills. So if your use case is, you
know, for example, performing a PR
review or doing an an accessibility
audit, in that case, it might make sense
to make an accessibility skill that
outlines, you know, all of the things
that that you want the audit to do, all
of the things you want the agent to
check in terms of accessibility, and
then create a sub agent and point him,
you know, point them to that skill and
say, uh, you know, when I'm doing a
security review or a PR review,
use the accessibility sub agent that is
then going to use the accessibility
skill. Um and and the reason you would
want to do this is you know if that
accessibility skill is
uh applicable to to multiple use cases
and you know you may want the skill to
be pulled in when an agent is also
writing code and as opposed to just like
you know checking for accessibility
features. uh you may want to share that
expertise across multiple sub agents and
even your main agent, but you may want
to have a dedicated sub agent uh that
has access to that skill. So, you know,
you could definitely use them in tandem,
but think of it as the skill is the
expertise is the knowledge and the sub
agent or the main agent is the execution
layer.
>> I love that that breakdown of expertise,
knowledge, and then execution. That's
actually a really good mental model. So,
thank you so much. And there all these
mental models, right? These mental
models that you pick up and uh this kind
of leads onto the question from
anonymous which is how is the best way
to learn to use cold code starting from
zero. Like it's one thing to be able to
start prompting, but how do we go from
just the first couple of prompts to
being able to build those mental models
of agents, sub agent skills, how I
almost architect my ideas into prompts
that then go into cloud code and turn
into software.
Yeah, another really really good
question. And um you know at the end of
the talk I I kind of gave a couple of
tips on like you know if if you're
totally new to cloud code and not sure
where to where to how to get started
like just download the tool uh you know
get it set up on your machine open up a
codebase and just run slashinit to have
claude kind kind of go through your
codebase generate a cla file and um
cloud code is really one of those tools
that that I feel like it you learn it
best by experiencing it and and using it
yourself and seeing just how far you can
go. Um, and you know, cloud code in its
default mode without setting up any
skills, without setting up any any sub
agents, customizing it with MCPs can
still get you so far that um, you know,
I always kind of compare it to a lot
like Visual Studio Code or your IDE.
Many developers will, you know, spend
hours and days customizing different
plugins, different extensions to really
make it their own. But if you just
download VS Code, open it up, throw some
files in there, like you can get 80 90%
of the way there by just kind of, you
know, using the default settings. Um and
and the more you use it, the more you
know you'll see opportunities for oh you
know this would be great to parallellize
and and use sub agents for or you know I
am asking cloud to do this thing over
and over again let me have it add it to
to the cloud MD file or you know let me
extract it as a skill. So I wouldn't
like dive into the deep end and try to
customize everything from the get-go. I
would very slowly start using the tool,
start prompting it, seeing the responses
you get and just adapt and and you know
make incremental changes day over day.
That was a really good analogy because
whenever I think about my VS Code, I
always feel like I don't have a very
very unique special setup until I get a
new laptop and then I'm like, "Oh my
gosh, I've had so much and built over
time." And and you kind of talked about
the claw MV files kind of part of this
process and look there are lots of
studies research coming out coming up
with different opinions, but um maybe
you've seen some of the research that
came out that said maybe adding claw and
defiles can negatively impact model
performance. uh do you have thoughts or
takes on this? And also this is like a
brand new uh kind of world where the
answers are not just yes or no, they
often create a nuance. So hopefully you
can give us some of that nuance.
>> Yeah. No, absolutely. Um so I have not
seen this study. Uh I would love to if
you want to share with me I would love
to take a look. Uh but one thing I will
say about the claude MD file is that it
should be a living breathing document
that you ruthlessly update and and keep
um keep up to date as as much as
possible. Um I've seen uh and also like
keep the cloud MD file as short and as
concise as possible. If you try to put
too much information in it, if you, you
know, if it's a thousand, 2,000 lines of
instructions, the model can get
confused. And especially if you don't
update it, you know, you might have some
outdated commands, some outdated
instructions in there. And if it's like
a really long file and you're not
looking at it consistently, you know,
you you might have some bad instructions
in there that, you know, either slipped
in or you added that that were relevant
at the time, but aren't relevant
anymore. So, you know, you might be
asking it to do something one way, but
in the cloud MD file, it's like, no, do
it this other way. And then, you know,
you're kind of pulling your hair out
being like, why aren't you listening to
me? So, I would definitely say like, you
know, ruthlessly keep the cloudmd file
as short as possible, but also treat it
as a living, breathing document that
that you keep updated as often as
possible to get the best performance.
>> No, absolutely. And and you're right as
well like there's so many different
nuances and it's hard to kind of
accommodate even if you're doing
research. It's such a new space to
accommodate for all of the nuances. What
what codd files do people have and so on
and so forth. All right, we are
basically out of time so I'm just going
to pick the second
do you have for skills? Let's talk about
ones that you've used that are not real
that you've seen for a skill.
Yeah, I think one of the uh best use
cases I've seen for skills is front-end
design. Uh you know, if you've used like
just the default cloud models or any any
AI model to have it build UIs, you know,
you've had that Tailwind purple gradient
uh which you know it's kind of become
synonymous with
>> with the with AI generated code. Um, but
with the front-end design skill that we
have one that that we shipped that
anybody can use, but there's a lot of
amazing front-end designers that have
put out their own skills to really
elevate your your UIs and you know, a
lot of us engineers were uh, you know,
we're good at code, but when it comes to
visualizing things, maybe not so much.
So, front-end design is a big one. Uh, I
also saw that the planet scale recently
pul put out a ton of database skills. So
if you're uh you know building uh
databases and and working with schemas
their skills have been really really
amazing. Uh so so check those out.
>> That is so cool. I I definitely need
some design help whenever I'm building.
So that's much appreciated. Thank you so
much Adam for joining us. Thank you so
much both for all your questions. We'll
see you at the next talk.
>> Absolutely. And and thank you for having
me and uh good luck with the rest of the
conference.
Thank you so much. I am learning so much
so quickly. So many new things that I
can take away and genuinely go and add
into my workflow straight away. So I'm
writing notes for after the conference.
All right, let's move on to our next
speaker. We have Eddie. And they're
going to be talking to us about the
Ralph Wigum method. I have no idea what
that is. So I'm really excited about
this talk. Eddie is a passionate
software engineer and they've had over
eight years of experience with a focus
on front-end web development, but also
expanding into the backend, mobile
development, and DevOps. So, there's a
lot that they can take away from all of
this knowledge to teach us about this
new method. I'm really excited. Eddie, I
can't wait to hear about this. Take it
away.
Hello everyone. Today we're going to
take a look at the Ralph Wigum AI
method. And if you haven't heard about
it yet, it has been a big hype in the
online dev community. And I decided to
take a look into how it works. And I
liked it so much that I wanted to give
this talk about it because it seemed
much more complicated than it actually
was.
So let me first introduce myself. Hi, my
name is Eddie I'm a senior
software engineer at a company called
Front Value, which is a front-end and
nojs focus consulty based in the
Netherlands.
So why is it called Ralph Wigum and what
kind of problems does Ralph solve?
Let's get right into it. Well, Ralph
Wigum, of course, is a character from
the Simpsons whose characteristics
really match his way of working with AI.
So, just like the Simpsons character,
the Ralph Wigum AI method keeps trying
and it is very persistent in its
iteration loops despite any setbacks
that it might run into. And you might
have to believe in eventual consistency,
meaning that most issues can be resolved
by just running more real loops.
So, the problems with AI chats and
that's basically all about context
management. So context windows uh they
get worse the bigger that they get and
too big a context window can get
summarized or compacted and cont
compacting in clock code or cursor is
not lossless like you actually lose some
information in this summary and it can
leave out some very important parts and
this can cause problems uh in your
resulting code and it can cause
mistakes.
So in a nutshell, what does a Ralph look
look like? Well, you create a
specification and an implementation plan
as markdown files and then you trigger a
bash loop that runs an LLM like claw
code. And in this loop, for every
iteration, you tell the LLM, go study
the specs, check the implementation
plan, pick the highest priority task to
work on, and any specific extra info
that it might need for the task or
project. Go make some unit tests and
mark the task as completed if the task
passes. And then make a git commit. And
then the loop starts all over again with
a fresh context window. It's not a
persistent chat.
So this is the most basic example. It's
a while true loop where you just put the
same prompt into claw code over and over
again. Um and I use a bit of an expanded
version on this where you can actually
pass in some iter an iteration con and
uh it actually uh exports this string
that tells it that is complete when the
task is finished. So the loop will be
able to end when the work is finished.
And here's an example of a prompt. So uh
the first step is to study the specs.
Then you tell uh the LLM, hey, you
decide what to work on next. And this
should be the highest priority task. So
then it has to check for any feedback
loops such as types or tests. and it has
to actually go back and update the
progress in your implementation plan so
that it knows where to continue in the
next run. Then it has to make a get
commit of that feature and some other
information about only working on one
feature and the stuff about outputting
the complete text at the end.
So, another term that you might hear
when people talk about Ralph is back
pressure, which basically means telling
the LLM to use other systems or other
tools that help it verify that the code
that it generates actually works. And
this can be a test suite, it can be a
type system, or it can just be running a
build of your program. The loop
iteration will not complete until this
step succeeds.
And of course, the whole point of Ralph
is to have an AI coding agent run
autonomously. And to do that, you cannot
have it keep checking in with a
developer or a person, you know, that to
ask, hey, can I edit this file? Can I
use this command? So often people use it
with the uh skip permissions flag, which
can be quite dangerous. So uh people
have actually almost wiped their entire
file systems with this option. Uh
because clock code sees, hey, this Mac
is running out of storage space, but I
need more storage for this task. So, let
me just go find some stuff that I can
delete so I can continue my work, which
is pretty bad, of course. So uh I want
to highlight this line in the uh script
uh which is running docker sandbox run
cloud which is basically a sandbox
version of cloud code in which it still
runs with without the permission checks
but it cannot actually go and destroy
your whole laptop or other device that
you have which is uh the better way to
work in my opinion much safer. So let's
go and talk about this specification
that we have t been talking about. You
don't actually have to write it all by
hand and I recommend using an LLM to
help you write this thorough spec, but
it requires some iteration with the LLM
actually. So here's an example of claw
code. And here uh I tell it what I want
to create. And it's not a super clear
description yet, but it doesn't matter
because we tell claw code, hey, I want
you to have a discussion with me about
this and to interview me to get clarity
on the implementation.
So then claude will continue asking you
questions over and over again until it
thinks that it has clarity and then you
tell it to make the specification files
and of course you get this output. You
have to go over this line by line and
review the whole thing to make sure that
it actually aligns with your vision. And
if it doesn't match, then you have to
tell Claude or you just edit it yourself
until you get something that you 100%
agree with. And the other file is the
implementation plan, which is basically
a sectioned uh set of tasks that uh will
match the specification. And you also
have to check this one line by line to
make sure that it matches your vision.
so that claw doesn't go out and do a
bunch of stuff that you don't want it to
do. So, you have to really be thorough
here in this preparation step.
And for this example, I used it to
create a boiler plate for an internal
hackathon that we're going to run later
this year. And I found the quality to be
pretty high. Very high actually.
Especially considering considering that
it was mostly handsoff except for the
upfront tradeoff of the time investment
into the specking and creating uh the
plan basically, especially considering
that it was on the $20 a month plan and
I wasn't even using Opus. I was using
Sonnet 4.5 which came out with very good
results.
So, I know we said that it would be an
autonomous coding approach, but it
doesn't mean that we actually don't have
to work. Uh, we still have to, you know,
especially when we're getting started
with Ralph, it's best practice to just
take a look at how it's doing in the
beginning and see if it's going off the
rails or not. And then you can update
your prompt or your specification
uh to actually fine-tune it until it
does what you want it to do. and then
you can leave it off to the races.
Of course, there are downsides when
using Ralph. Um, of course, it requires
a lot more planning up front and you
have to be careful not to make the task
too big or else uh it will still go
ahead and compact in the end because the
context window will get too big and
that's not good. Um, it's not always the
fastest approach. for some tasks, it's
still faster to just do it by hand or
use some tap complete stuff to do it.
And uh another point is that you will
actually pretty easily use up all the
tokens in your subscription.
Of course, there are also a bunch of
upsides. Um you can now run this
autonomously while you're doing other
tasks or relaxing, whatever. Um, it's
great for exploring proof of concepts or
other tasks that are very clear in what
it needs to do. It's really good
specification. Then it's it's able to do
its best work basically.
Um, and you will still easily use up all
the tokens in your subscription, which
is great when you often see that you
actually aren't using the whole
subscription that you're paying for.
So, some takeaways. You should go try
the Ralph Wickham method. Chat to an LLM
about your specs. Be sure to sandbox
Ralph and use the bash loop. Don't
actually use the claw code plugin.
That's uh something to keep in mind.
It's not entirely accurate uh for the
method. So, uh that has been my talk
about the Ralph Wigger method. Thank you
all for watching and uh goodbye.
Thank you so much. That was another
amazing talk, learning new stuff. Today
I learned I'm I've got many today I
learned moments. Uh so I'm really
enjoying it and hopefully you are at
home. And a huge thank you to the people
who made all of this possible, our
sponsors. And I want to shout out our
gold sponsor Pixie Bricks. Pixie Bricks
is a platform for building and deploying
secure automation in apps that your team
already uses. definitely go and check
them out to make sure that your
automations are secure. Okay, we've got
our next speaker, Todd. And Todd is
going to talk about making AI coding
work for enterprisegrade browser
extensions. Todd is a co-founder and CEO
of guess who? Pixie Bricks. And he spent
the last 15 years building AI, working
in data science and software
engineering, and building tools for
large enterprises and hedge funds. So,
if you're wondering how you can take
some of the AI knowledge you've learned
and apply it in an enterprise setting,
Todd is perfectly positioned to give us
some advice on that. So, I can't wait to
learn. Todd, really, really excited,
especially us enterprise developers over
here. Please take it away.
Hi, I'm Todd Schiller, co-founder of
Pixie Bricks, and today I'm going to be
talking through some of the hard one
lessons that we've learned using AI to
code, an AI enabled extension that's
used globally by enterprises.
Our mission has always been to really
empower people to create the perfect
experience for the technology that
matters most to them. Therefore, our
first product was a browser extension
because browser extensions enable
permissionless innovation. You can
automate and modernize sites that you
don't yourself control, whether those
are third party websites, vendor
websites, government websites. You can
also automate and integrate across tabs.
And we fundamentally believe that
browser extensions are a key part of how
do you empower the people closest to the
work to really customize their tools to
the job.
Browser extensibility is in fact a
spectrum. Um there's multiple different
ways to customize the standard browser
experience. In the past year we've even
seen people many different forks of the
Chromium browser for things like
security um or embedding AI capabilities
directly into the browser. Then you have
the standard kind of custom ex custom
extension experience that most people
are familiar with. You go to the Chrome
web store, you get an extension, it does
something. Uh and then you have a
category of extensions that in fact
enable people to customize in different
ways. Uh and so one that some people
might be familiar with is user scripts
like Grease Monkey or Tamper Monkey that
allow you to run JavaScript in the
context of a web page. Uh, and then
Pixie Bricks is a different kind that
you can think of it like user scripts
but more low code or no code to enable a
broader audience to be able to
customize.
Each of these comes with different
trade-offs. Again, the the things on the
right side of the screen are generally
more lightweight, more agile, but then
those comes with trade-offs of less
control, less affordances
uh and
more uh kind of restrictions in terms of
what these can do um versus for example
creating a custom extension or building
your entire browser yourself.
uh as we've started applying kind of AI
coding tools like claude like cursor to
the problem of browser extensions we
found there was three main gaps or
mismatches in terms of how those tools
treat software development life cycle
the the first is that browser extensions
are actually distributed systems even
though at first glance they might look
like applications the second is because
of the web store structure and how
they're distributed they actually have
slower iteration loops than many of
these tools that are more focused on web
applications. Uh and third and finally,
in many cases, you want extensions to be
able to work in the context of host
sites. Those host sites has changes or
might be outwardly hostile to to your
extension. Uh and so these things are
surmountable. You just have to think
through how to best handle them and how
to best apply AI coding tools. Um, but
for for people who aren't familiar how
browser extensions work under the hood,
I like to describe them as a distributed
system in a box. Uh, you can think of a
browser, it has multiple different tabs.
Each tab has multiple different frames.
And so your browser extension is
injecting context onto each of those.
But then you also have surface areas
like the side panel and pages uh as well
as then things that are working behind
the scenes. So storage, the service
worker, offscreen document, a lot of
different pieces that are talking to
each other. Uh, and so you run into the
usual suspects of distributed systems
problems. Everything is async. Uh,
you're you're doing message passing with
serialized payloads. And so again, you
run into those common problems with
distributed systems. But in some ways,
it's it's worse than a normal
distributed system. Some of these
components have very complex life cycle.
Uh, you have things like tab
pre-rendering, backward, forward cache,
or or worker recycling. uh and so it
it's just a different animal in terms of
even normal distributed systems.
Uh and so on this we'll we'll talk
through kind of the four best practices
that that we believe. The first one is
really how do you choose the right base
foundation, right? So I don't believe
that most people should have to worry
about the things that I showed on the
last slide. And so you want to choose a
foundation where you can be the most
productive. Uh and so in our case we
started at the library layer. We use a
lot of different libraries in order to
smooth over quirks uh in the browser
extension APIs to be more have better
ergonomics. But if you are building
extension for a single use case and that
use case is pretty common, you might
consider using a framework instead like
WXT or Plasma in order to build it
quickly. And if you don't want to worry
about CI/CD or preview builds, you might
use a platform that helps you with those
builds automatically or even does things
like submit to the Chrome web store on
your behalf.
That's the side again if you're building
extensions. Uh and then if you're
building on top of extensions, right,
the the name of the game is really do
you want to to be in the user script
world, deal with the user script APIs,
or do you want to build on top of a low
code platform like Pixie Bricks? Uh that
again, that's going to give you even
higher abstractions in terms of
integrations, compliance, components.
Once you've chosen your foundation, the
name of the game is how do you maximize
the boring part of the application?
Browser extensions can be built with
standard frameworks like React, Angular,
View. And so what you want to do is
create a big area of those boring
applications and then encapsulate the
extension specific code. That would be
the extension code that uses the APIs,
the messaging frameworks, messaging bus,
etc. Uh, and so use this the standard
isolation tactics here. Use dependency
injection. Um, when using AI, it's
always better to be explicit than
implicit. That's going to help the AI
have better context locally in terms of
how a particular piece of code is
working. Uh, and then I always recommend
enforcing these boundaries using
llinters or other tools uh, to give that
instantaneous feedback. And that kind of
leads us to our next point, which is
really creating fast feedback loops in a
browser extension world. Uh, and so on
this slide, each each one of these icons
is sort of time units. And so on the
lefth hand side we have the quickest
feedback loops. These would be things
like use TypeScript. There are
definitions for the different browsers.
Um you probably want to even add more
type information on. We use type tags uh
or tag types for for strings um to help
differentiate different values. We also
use lint rules a ton and use AI to
create custom lint rules. So whenever a
bug comes in, we ask ourselves, was this
a preventable bug um or could we have
caught it earlier on? And we write a
lint rule for it. Moving through the
testing kind of hierarchy. Um, next up
would be your headless test. Again, take
advantage of dependency induction. Use
mocks, use fakes in the right places in
order to be able to do integration test
in a realistic way. Um, then there's the
how do you test the boring components of
your app, right? Use storybook, use the
standard vanilla playright MCP. Uh, and
then you can also use these tools for
endto-end tests for extensions. they're
just going to take longer especially if
you're doing multiple multiple different
browser types or multiple different
browser versions. We also test against
Canary for example. Uh and so there even
are some things that Playright can't
test and so we use other tools that are
more browser use capabilities like
Rainforest QA uh in order to test those.
Uh and then obviously the the other
thing you want to do is always shift
left, right? You always want to be in a
world where you're catching things
earlier versus relying on the slower
feedback loops. Uh, and then speaking of
feedback loops, again, extensions, often
the the value prop is modifying a host
page. It's not a good idea to run your
automated tests or do your QA against
those host pages all the time because
that's very slow and it's going to be
flaky and in some cases they'll kind of
catch your robotic behavior there. So,
what we do is we create test pages for
the different patterns we come across.
And so this screenshot is an example of
one that we use for host style
conflicts. Uh unfortunately with
extensions, even if you're using
shadowdom, some styles can leak through.
So we have a page with very extreme
styles on it. So we can see which styles
are are coming through to our extension.
Uh and then you have other things like
rich text editor, single page
applications. So the name of the game
again is whenever you have a bug, just
go ahead and create a test page for that
bug so that then it's in your repertoire
of regression tests and and definitely
use AI to to generate those test pages.
Uh and so to recap, what you want to do
is you want to set your AI coding tool
up for success. Choose the right
foundation, maximize the boring path,
create fast feedback loops, and again
create those test pages for those host
page quirks. that's going to give you
that stability in testing and and your
agentic loop. Uh and then the other
thing I'd be remiss to point out is that
enterprise grade is more than just code.
You can generate all the code in the
world, but if you don't have the right
enterprise IT documentation, the right
trust center, the right audits in place,
you're not going to get that much
traction enterprise, especially with
browser extensions. And so go do those
things and definitely leverage AI for
those non-code activities. Uh and so as
you're thinking about which point or
which foundation you want to build on, I
would definitely uh advise you to take a
look at Pixie Bricks. We are the only
enterprisegrade platform enabling
enduser AI coding. Uh so start for free
and definitely attend our workshop to
get hands-on experience building with
the Pixie Bricks platform.
Thank you so much. That was another
great tour. We've had an amazing lineup.
A massive thank you to all of the
program committee, the speakers, all the
people involved in making this possible.
Lots of great content. Now, before we
continue, I do want to shout out our
platinum sponsor, Cloudflare. Thank you
so much for making the world, right?
Everything CloudFare learned from
powering 20% of the internet is yours by
default whenever you use them. Cloudfare
is your AI cloud with compute, AI
inference, storage, and it let you ship
in applications instead of just managing
infrastructure. Definitely take them
out, check them out as you think about
building your AI infrastructure. All
right, let's move on to our next
speaker, Narish. Narish is going to be
talking about designing sandbox dev
environments for coding agents. Narish
is a software engineer on the agents
team at Cloudflare and they are talking
about they build opinionated
abstractions on the Cloudflare developer
platform to run agents on production and
give them access to sandbox
environments. Many people might be
thinking about how they can experiment
and deploy AI agents or different agents
in a safe way and this is going to be a
lot about that. Remember if you have
questions use the slido 2627
so that you can ask your questions. But
without further ado Narish
tell us about sandbox dev environments.
So, I am a big fan of demos. So, let's
start with the demo. Here is a very
silly pixel animated
um goose. Um and uh I want to make this
goose follow my cursor. So, let's ask an
agent to do that.
What's happening behind the scenes here
is there is an environment that has spun
up. The dev server has started. We have
a preview URL. The agent is going
through the codebase that I had. It's
thinking about how to go about implement
implementing this change. And once it
reasons with that change, ideally it
should be making that change and we
should be able to see it. There we go.
This talk is about all the different
things that have happened to make this
demo work.
The most important thing to identify
here is that there's no local host here,
right? So all of this, it's a real demo.
It's running somewhere and the agent and
this preview URL that we use to look at
this work had to find its way from the
internet from my browser to a very
specific port in a specific environment
and if I close this tab and come back
tomorrow ideally the agent should be
able to pick up where it left off.
That's what we will try to understand
how it works. So this preview URL is a
computer. Of course, it's a server, but
a computer is a nicer way to say it, and
I like that. Um, and every agent needs a
computer. I think we have come to a
point where models have become
good enough to a point where longunning
agents are now real. They are able to do
a lot of very powerful things. And the
computer that we give it also needs to
be designed in a very specific way uh
for it to be useful for the agent. I'm
Narish. In my past life, I worked on
coding agents that twice dropped
threebench and now I build the sandbox
environments that they run in.
Let's actually talk about what are all
the things that just happened in that
demo that we just saw and try to break
it down into different layers. The first
thing is the isolation boundary itself.
There's a microVM, its own kernel, own
network stack. There's no shared kernel
attack surface with anything else
running on the same machine.
And then there is a container that's uh
running inside it. So you know it's
running Ubuntu um or we are very
familiar with installed
um or rather there's a bunch of dev
tools that we commonly use
pre-installed. Then there are bash
sessions and a file system. This is
where the agent runs commands. It you
know reads and writes files, installs
packages, all the things that you and I
would do whenever we had to work on a
codebase like this. And then there is
the networking bit. the agent you know
probably ran npm start uh inside the
container uh it's running on an SML port
but getting the traffic from the agent
and our browser to that very particular
port is slightly non-obvious
and finally there is persistence so all
the files um that are installed all the
changes made by the agent they need to
survive all of these sessions
we will actually go through some of the
design decisions that go into doing two
things. One, to build a sandbox
environment like this, and two, how to
use a sandbox environment like this to
build whatever platforms or products
that you are interested in building.
Let's start with the runtime. What does
the agent actually get to work with?
Agents ideally need the same tools that
developers need. You could technically
just give it a very small repel and say
okay you know run the code that you need
but it's super restricted right um
ideally we want to give it a full you
know Linux instance a real computer so
that it can actually perform non-trivial
complex operations but the challenge is
how much of the heavy lifting to do a
lot of these orchestration can the
sandbox itself do because the less the
sandbox does, the more your agent has
to. The table stakes are very simple,
right? Um this is the baseline. Run some
commands, read and write files, clone
repos, install packages. Every sandbox,
well, every container has this and it's
necessary.
But what actually separates um good
runner from a realtime environment is
the next layer. Um the agent needs to be
able to start background processes. The
you know in this demo the dev server was
an example of a background process. Uh
it needs to keep working in the
background. Uh streaming uh so that you
know the agent can react to output as it
happens not after the command exists
exits. uh continuity when we work on a
terminal, you know, a a bash session,
basically make sure that all the
commands that we run are, you know,
sequentially happening or depending on
how you use bash really, but the agent
should have the same kind of cap
capability and it's not just a single
session. Ideally, it should be able to
manage multiple sessions within the same
sandbox. uh when you want to build
interactive um experiences wherein you
want to give your users access to um the
sandbox environment so that they can
also you know maybe look at what the
agent has been up to or uh even directly
run commands of their own. You ideally
want to maybe come, you know, connect an
exterm instance. Uh, and the code
interpreter that we spoke about in the
beginning wherein, uh, the agent could
probably also just output raw code and,
um, you know, just run that code in a
ripple and get the output but also with
like rich um, responses so that again
the agent doesn't have to go through the
process of parsing the output. So this
is just a very small subset of all the
things that sandboxes should be doing.
The next bit is isolation. How do we
contain this sandbox environment? Right?
The important thing to remember is that
you're running code that you didn't
write and executing instructions from a
user who you don't control and you don't
want to control. Um so that means that
the attack surface isn't just the code,
it's everything the agent can reach. And
the paradox is that we ideally we want
the agent to be able to do a lot and
reach a lot of surfaces. Uh but it still
needs to you know have some guard rails
around it. Um
so the common problems basically that
you're thinking about is well what
packages did then uh you know agent
install? Um was it prompted to install
it? was there, you know, are there any
possibilities of prompt injection that
could uh impact what the agent actually
does inside this environment? You don't
know what the user actually asked your
agent to build. And every message
actually shapes the decisions that your
agent is actually taking. You don't
review it, so you don't control it. And
uh finally, you also don't have full
control over what the agent reads before
it writes the code. So you know it's
reading files in a repo uh web pages a
previous turn in the conversation all of
it shapes its output and all of this
actually increases um the attack vectors
and this is the reason why isolation
isn't optional um and the way we do it
matters so at this point I think we're
all familiar with the idea of well
actually you know let's just run it in a
docker container sure uh but you know
what what what's wrapping that container
itself like what's the boundary right
the simplest way is to just you know
name spaces shared kernel with the host
it's fast lightweight but every sys call
from every container hits the same
kernel which is fine for your own code
but not for arbitrary agent generated
code and the other end of the spectrum
is full VMs wherein you get genuine
isolation
but uh it comes with 100 MB of overhead
uh 5 to 30 seconds cold boot times all
of which is actually really impract
practical at scale. MicroVMs are
actually the middle ground and I
actually don't like calling it a middle
ground because they are actually better
than both the different directions. Um
they come with very very light overhead.
They are extremely fast to start. Uh
they have their own kernel per sandbox.
I think the most common implementation
is firecracker which was built by AWS
for lambda and it is specifically
designed for this hardware level
isolation without the full VM overhead.
This highlighted column is ideally what
you want um to use for your sandboxes.
The third bit is networking.
How does the agent and the browser find
the right sandbox? Right? Let's look at
this URL. The subdomain in this URL
actually contains a couple of things. It
contains a port. It contains a unique
session token. But you know there is
there's nothing here that's actually
pointing to a spec specific machine,
right? And that's intentional because
you can't pre-provision DNS per sandbox
or you can't just assign a stable IP. So
every time when the request comes in the
you know machine needs to be resolved by
the platform you know extract the um you
know relevant information either
directly from here or through an
internal map do a fast lookup and open a
TCP connection to it. All of this needs
to happen behind the scenes. And um the
second bit is even after the request
reaches the right machine you also want
to make sure that it's you know uh
connecting to the right port and uh and
it's also established in such a way that
for instance again dev servers they
actually do hot reloading uh which means
there's a you know persistent websocket
connection and changes are actually you
know um going back and forth all the
time. this needs to just consistently
work without any additional uh setup,
right? So from the developer point of
view, we just want to make sure it says,
"Okay, expose port 5173." And you get a
URL back with everything wired up for
you. And the last weight is persistence.
And I think this is actually the most
important um because persistence is not
just about um you know what you need to
store and restore uh but also the way
you think about persistence impacts cold
starts right um the reason is uh or
rather you know let's actually start
with thinking about well what are the
two things that dominate cold starts
right One part of it is the
infrastructure itself that needs to come
up. How long does it take for the VM to
exist? How long uh before you can
actually connect to it. That's one part
of it. And the second is actually the
application readiness. Right? So when a
user comes in and they are starting a
fresh session or they're continuing from
an older session, you want your
application to reach the state wherein
your agent can actually immediately
continue working. This is actually the
gap that the developer is going to feel
because this is where things can
actually become really slow and this is
the part where you need to think about
okay how do I optimize this? There are a
few ways. Um the simplest easiest win is
pre-built images right so you can
actually build an image make sure that
it has all the you know code bases uh
dependencies everything that you need.
You can also maybe keep rebuilding it in
the background if things keep changing
and um and this is the image that
actually boots up within the VM. So
that's one thing. The second is if you
actually have slightly more dynamic
needs, maybe you um you know can't
always bake everything into an image
then you use persistent volumes. So um
you can actually mount these volumes
into these different uh ephemeral
containers and that way you know all the
data survives restarts as well and you
could actually take these volumes and
attach them to multiple sandboxes as
well. The third one which is actually
things starting to get very powerful is
snapshots. You could potentially take um
or rather you know if the platform
supports it, you should actually be able
to take um the entire disk or even a
part of that disk and snapshot it and
even you know uh snapshot the state of
the memory itself. And what this allows
you to do is you could actually pause a
VM and just like resume it at the exact
same point and the agent can actually
just continue working on it. Or you
could also, you know, snapshot an
instance and start multiple sandboxes.
This could enable things like uh forking
um the agent state and getting agents to
actually, you know, pursue different
options. And um finally, you could also
have warm pools. So this way uh you know
even before your uh if you're able to
predict what uh is the state of your
sandbox before the agent needs to start
working on it you can actually just
maintain a pool and get it going and all
of them have a you know fairly
significant impact on the amount of time
it takes before the agent can actually
start working. These numbers are just
illustrative, but you can imagine why at
every single step you actually
drastically reduce the amount of time it
takes for your application to be ready.
And these are things to think about. Um,
and and of course the way you optimize
also differs on uh depends on the kind
of use case that you're powering, right?
For instance, code interpreters are just
embedded in chat UIs. And um you know
the model is generating some code. You
immediately want a response. Maybe you
want a warm pool. Coding agents you you
know your users expect that these agents
will run for a longer time. So you start
thinking about it differently. Earl
training environments you're mainly
thinking about aggregate throughput and
so on and so forth. So different kind of
optimizations depending on the kind of
use case that you need. And uh these are
all the primitives that platforms need
to build so that you can leverage it
however you actually want. So when all
of this is actually done properly uh you
know ideally you should just be able to
say okay I want to just resume uh an
older instance of something that I was
working on and here we go. Uh the same
state that we were actually in we are
able to get back to. So let's look at
under the hood and try to understand
well how does this look from
um your point of view of you actually
using some sandbox. So it's actually
this whole demo that we actually just
looked at in its simplest form it's
actually just you know eight lines of
code. Let's break it down a bit. The
first one is isolation. So uh every
session it gets its own VM. You can
think about you know separate sandboxes
per user per org. There's all sorts of
things that you could actually do. Then
you and then there are all the different
methods that actually allows you to
start processes wait for a pro you know
a particular process to be ready uh read
and write files uh you know whenever you
actually want to. Then the networking
bit which we spoke about all the things
that we addressed uh earlier in the
networking section can actually just be
one line. you get back a URL and that's
all you need to think about. And
finally, you want to do some
persistence. In this demo, frankly, all
I'm doing is just storing my uh code in
a bucket, but you know, you could also
opt into some of the more advanced
strategies depending on the use cases
like we discussed.
So this is what at least from a
cloudflare context where I work um the
the way this whole architecture looks
like can be thought about as you know
request from the agent and the browser
is reaching the edge the worker and from
there there's a durable object which
basically the most important thing that
it offers in this context is it's
globally uniquely addressable which is
something that we wanted we want to
reach a very specific sandbox Right. So
the durable object makes sure that
you're able to do the routing and then
you are able to reach the particular
sandbox and within the sandbox you do
all the things that you want to do.
So why is all of this important right?
So um cursor almost a year ago uh shared
that almost 1 billion lines of code is
being accepted by their autocomplete
model every single day. Um just a few
months back. Boris who is actually the
creator of cloud code mentioned the
number of PRs that are that are 100%
cloud generated at this point and this
is just expected to continue right so
there's a lot of code that's actually
being generated for lots of different
reasons and all of them needs to run
somewhere so this problem just keeps
increasing in importance and so far we
have actually talked about all of this
from the point of view of well you know
we have
we need a full dev environment. But
there are some classes of workloads
where you actually maybe don't need you
just want to um take some dynamically
generated code and run them in an
isolated environment. What something I'm
very excited to explore going forward is
to do this without a microVM just uh
very lightweight uh isolates V8 based
isolates where you know this code can
run uh but still giving you the same
flexibility that we have been able to
get from um microVM based sandbox
environments. So
to summarize um you know a year ago
sandboxes were actually a very niche
concern but now every major coding agent
every wipe coding platform every code
interpreter runs in one and the
infrastructure that used to be optional
is now becoming the default. And these
are the problems that we think about
when building sandboxes and how you
think about when using sandboxes to
build everything that you do.
Um that's it that this is uh everything
from me. Thank you so much. And uh if
you want to go even more hands-on, Craig
from Cloudfare, he's also running a
workshop where you can actually get to
play with some of these things and uh
try this for yourself. Uh you can also
find me on Twitter and on GitHub. I'm
more than happy to speak about sandboxes
at any time. Um
that's it. Thank you.
Thank you so much, Narish. That was an
amazing talk. Wherever you are at home,
give a massive round of applause. If
you're already in the Discord, give a
virtual round of applause. That was an
amazing talk. Thank you so much. I'm
going to talk to Narish in just a
second. He's joining me. But remember to
get your questions in. put your
questions in to the styo or
styido.com2627.
Pop that code in because I know many of
you have had questions. We've had
amazing questions all day. So, keep them
coming. And Nares, how are you doing?
It's good to hear from you and be able
to chat to you in person.
>> Thank you so much for having me here.
It's actually quite nice and uh I've
been really enjoying all the talks today
as well. Uh there's so many things to
learn especially now that agents are
doing so many different things. Uh
hearing from everyone has been really
fun.
>> No, absolutely. It has genuinely been
three for three when it comes to amazing
talk. So, thank you as well for
extending the street. More than three
for three. Sorry. Five for five. Um all
right, let's continue. Um so, like let's
talk about like sandboxing agents,
right? You've obviously got to think
about these environments. Uh what is
kind of a key design challenge that
comes to you for like when you're um
designing sandboxing agents for like
non-coding tasks? So for example file
system ops or some other thing what's
your solution
>> I think the biggest pattern that I have
actually observed is that people are now
able to take uh standard coding agent
harnesses and when I say a harness it's
basically agents that are pre-built and
uh they can be tuned to do different
things for instance I know a lot of uh
you know uh developers out there who are
actually building agents like uh you
know financial uh trading agents, but
they're actually using a version of
cloud code or open code, but actually
just running in sandboxes, but they have
the right set of skills and the right
prompts to actually do uh fairly
non-standard tasks. So, I think uh at
least going into 2026
uh considering that the way to build and
run agents has actually standardized.
there is going to be a lot more
innovation in how exactly do you take an
existing hardness and actually tune it
to work uh for your very specific use
case. So you don't need to start from
scratch. you can actually uh just focus
on what exactly you want your agent to
do instead of trying to figure out well
how do I build an agent in the very
first place and uh and I think that
requires a very different set of uh
things to think about wherein uh yeah
you're not worrying about yeah which
model how do I run a loop how do I do
tool calls instead you are just focusing
on where do I run it what does it need
to do what does it need to access and I
think uh that's the biggest change
that's happening right now
>> awesome no that makes sense that makes
sense and Another thing oftentimes
especially when we think about sandboxes
like uh I think everyone thinks when
they first think for sandboxes running
locally like disconnected from the cloud
and it can still run but when we wanted
to use tools or interact with other
things um is it possible and this is the
kind of question are there options to
have that isolated safe sandbox running
locally but still utilize these tools
like open code cloud code without having
to spin off another micro virtual
machine somewhere in the cloud.
Definitely. So I mean I think the
simplest thing that a lot of uh
developers have been doing is to
actually run uh their agents inside just
a simple docker container and that kind
of works but it's not sufficient right
because docker does not actually provide
these same isolation boundaries that we
are actually uh familiar with in these
you know like cloud microvms and the way
uh like one of the solutions for
instance anthropic itself has actually
recently uh released
Claude Co-work right and what they do is
they have actually built a uh user space
implementation of the same level of
isolation boundary. So you know uh as
long as a process is running inside this
isolated environment it you know you can
you can prevent what kind of file system
access it has what kind of network
access it has and what are the different
even um capabilities that it has in
terms of the sys calls that actually go
in um and uh and the you know like if
people are interested in looking at a
very specific example uh they can
actually just go to the anthropic github
and I I think it's called uh sandbox
container or something and it's all out
there
>> now. That's awesome. That makes sense.
And it's really nice to see lots of
these cloud providers also giving the
tools and environments to help people
get started. Um and speaking about like
getting started like as we design the
thing that is really really powerful is
the momentum and velocity someone as a
engineer can get as they start to use
these tools. Um and there's this kind of
balance. I think we always think about
this when we think about safeguarding is
how do you free innovation and let
innovation fly but at the same time keep
it safe and almost rained in. Uh so what
advice do you have as we design these AI
soundbox sandboxes to make sure we keep
that balance alive of freedom to chart
new territory and explore but stay safe.
Um I think uh like a frankly again this
is one of the hardest challenges right
now right and I think even within
cloudflare this has this is a very
active research area for us and
something that we are actually
experimenting with which I think is
quite promising is instead of uh trying
to say okay you know what we actually
give unbound access to these agents
instead we actually um uh give it very
specific gates through which it can
actually pass through right and the
moment you actually control that gate
and say okay you know what these are the
specific kind of actions that are all
possible through this gate but only that
is possible then you actually limit the
blast radius for an example right let's
say someone's actually building an email
agent now ideally you want to say okay I
want to give this agent access to my
email but maybe you don't yet trust the
agent to actually be able to uh you know
like send emails you
>> all your emails
>> yeah exactly yeah and I It's already
happening with a few people, right?
>> Yes.
>> So now, now the trouble is the moment
you actually go to Google and try to
create a you know like an API key, uh
you don't get granular scopes and
instead you actually have to uh create a
key that has a lot of access and then
you have to use it but then the agent
can actually you know do anything else.
So instead you actually build a very
programmatic gate that basically says
okay you know what this programmatic
gate it only exposes this kind of a
function and uh and you control you know
just exactly what the agent can do
through that gate and that way I think
uh this is a very this is very easy to
build such patterns but you also you
know limit uh the blast radius of what
are all the bad things that could happen
when an agent goes haywire.
>> Absolutely. We don't want run someone
running over to diffuse a bomb from from
their back mini. Um, insider joke. If
you know, you know. Um, but this
actually I love the analogy of gates,
right? And like programmatic gates and
deciding this gate lets you do this,
this gate let you do that. But I mean
like if we think back to the days of um
when people would ask questions online,
oh my gosh, the fact that I can't
remember the name of the website we
always used to go to to get coding
questions answered. uh says a lot about
the about the way AI has changed the way
we build it all coming to me stack
overflow right so you went stack
overflow and it was a rookie error to
copy code you didn't copy bash
instructions you didn't know and throw
them into your lm like it was very
rickety error cuz pseudo rm delete
everything was going to happen
>> but we kind of are doing this with AI
right like a lot of people have given AI
unfeted access to root uh uh stuff in in
in bash. Um, and so how can we sandbox
an agent so it doesn't get get these
kind of superior powers which allow it
to then go and find these other things?
I know you talked about gates. Sometimes
you want to give them the tool like a
CLI console without giving it that kind
of explosive access.
>> Um, I think the shortest answer I can
actually think about is um, you know,
you control the environment itself,
right? I think uh just don't run it on
your Mac in your personal back. Run it
on an isolated environment. I think
that's honestly the biggest way to
control uh because otherwise you want
the agent still like being able to do a
lot. It has access to all the tools it
needs but just control the environment.
That's the shortest answer I can come up
with.
>> No, I I think like controlling the
environment is fair. So it's easy when
there's just no cables connected.
There's no nothing to worry about. No,
also like this has been really really
helpful and it's really good for us to
think about as these agents become more
powerful. We can do so much more with
them, but being able to balance all of
that out. All right, thank you Nesh. It
has been a pleasure chatting with you.
Enjoy the rest of your day and we will
continue with more amazing content.
>> Thank you so much. Have a great day.
Bye-bye.
All right, lots of amazing content. I
mean, there's so much that we can take,
which is why we are going to have a
short break. Go get some hydration.
Whether it's coffee, tea, water,
Gatorade, whatever it is, go and
hydrate. Come back in a bit and we will
continue with more amazing content. See
you soon.
VI coding an AI studio with Gemini 3
lets you build anything.
Build entirely new experiences.
Create apps that see. Make tools that
listen.
Build apps with a single prompt.
Get inspired.
>> Tell me what you want.
>> Refine
and refine some more.
>> Now
>> share with a friend.
and remix
then share with the world.
>> Bring anything to life.
>> Tell me what you want to do.
Using cursor windsurf cloud code. What
about MCP servers? This AI coding stack
creates new risks such as data theft and
prompt injections. Backslash security
provides visibility, governance, and
real-time protection for agents, idees,
LLMs, and MCPs. We make Vibe coding
safe.
Allow me to introduce you to the
Cloudflare Sandbox SDK. It is an npm
install away. It gives you wonderful
code like this where you get the
sandbox, you do a get checkout, and then
you execute code like that. How
beautiful is that? And look at this.
That's not all. You get longunning
processes, realtime streaming, preview
urls. How amazing is that? Code
interpreter, file system, command
execution, and websockets out of the
box. There is a bunch of examples. Come
check it out. What are you waiting for?
Uh, it has given us a computer that's
really do weeks of effort. The developer
experience is well thought out. What are
you waiting for? Come here. Get started
now.
>> Pixie Bricks is the fastest way to solve
internal business problems on top of
tools your team already uses. Describe
the extension you want and get user
interfacing components like forms,
buttons, and modals connected to
back-end logic like API requests and
database queries. Oneclick deployment
for small teams. Enterprisegrade
security for scale. Build your dream
extension today.
You know, render for quick deploys, but
did you know it's also the fastest path
to production for full stack apps? This
one has a web service, that's a front
end and a back end, managed Postgress,
and a Chrome job that runs durable
workflows. And the best part is all of
your services in the same region can
communicate internally over a private
network that's both faster and more
secure than the public internet. So
whether it's an AI agent or your next
startup, build it better on render.
Heat.
Heat. Heat. Heat.
VI coding in AI Studio with Gemini 3
lets you build anything.
Build entirely new experiences.
Create apps that see. Make tools that
listen.
Build apps with a single prompt.
All right, welcome back. We have more
amazing content coming up and that
starts with our next speaker, Daniel,
who's going to be talking to us about
specdriven development, the end of vibe
coding. Now, that is a very, very bold
title. I can't wait to hear about this
talk. Daniel is a consultant at Think
Texture AG and a Microsoft MVP for
developer technologies. He helps
companies design and implement complex
web applications with a strong focus on
modern web technologies with Angular as
well as generative AI and AI assisted
software development. They're going to
tell us today about the spec driven
development, whatever that is. And
remember, if you have questions, maybe
you want to know some of these answers,
head over to 2627 on the slideo and
leave your comments. Also, go and let us
know what you think about this in the
Discord. But without further away,
Daniel, I can't wait to hear about this.
The stage is yours.
Welcome to my short talk about spec
development. Um, yeah, the end of W
coding or maybe better WIP coding done
right. Um, yeah, first let me introduce
myself shortly. So, my name is Daniel
Zogel. I'm from Germany. I'm working as
a principal consultant um for Think
Techure. And yeah, my main focus
normally is of course software
engineering, but I'm also really
interested into this kind of topic um
how to make yeah developers more
productive and of course also about
generative AI. I'm also yeah Microsoft
MVP for developer and web technologies.
Yeah, because yeah my main tech ST is
where web application um programming and
also yeah GitHub co-pilot for example.
So this is why I'm promoted as an MVP
from Microsoft last year. And yeah,
let's dive in into this topic. And I
like to start with yeah, first with the
problematic part um where yeah, AI
agents nowadays um still struggling. And
yeah, first maybe you um when a new LLM
is released, you will find some
benchmarks and yeah, LLM providers
normally um try to convince you that
yeah, their LLM is really good when it
comes to software development tasks. And
of course this is not a false thing.
It's it's correct. But it depends on
which yeah benchmarks you're taking a
look at. And for example there is this
famous um SWE benchmark but there's also
a pro version available or pro score.
And this compares LLM to each other um
when it comes to more complex more real
world tasks. And when you take a look
into this benchmark scores, you can see
that um even yeah new LLMs like for
example um Sonet 4.5 still struggling in
solving those real world tasks. Also
yeah it depends of course on which
numbers you are taking a look at but um
for example the latest ST overflow
survey from last year shows you that
yeah 66% of the developers need to spend
more time fixing code when they use AI
assisted coding tools. So maybe on first
glance it looks everything is right and
but when you take a second look into the
code generated by your favorite AI agent
you can see there are multiple mistakes
and yeah you need more time fixing them
and what's also dangerous and important
to take a look at are security issues
and security faults in yeah AI generated
code and you can also see numbers like
this 2.7
times more um security issues um in AI
generated code and of course all those
problems need to be solved and hopefully
Hopefully I can show you a solution to
those problems using specdriven
development. So there are five core
limitations I identified and yeah all
those yeah limitations should also be
solved by spec driven development. First
there's context management. So we only
have small context windows. Of course,
it depends on which LLMs you are using,
but yeah, normally we have at around
200,000 tokens of context window sizes.
And of course, this context window is
too small to fit yeah all company
knowledge and of course also not your
full coding base into this context
window. Then we have multifile
coordination. So when you're working in
complex projects, you not only have one
or two or three classes that are yeah
tied together, normally you have more
complex flows in your application. So
your AI agent needs to update all those
files and oversee all those yeah
dependency structures in your codebase.
Then we have silent failures. More to
that on the next slide. Um this is the
yeah most dangerous um issue we have
these days when it comes to AI generated
code. We have architecture decisions. So
this is also often a problem when you're
working on an existing project where the
architecture is already not good
implemented. And yeah, when it comes to
AI assisted coding, AI agents are also
often struggling into yeah, following
architecture decisions. And when you
yeah use them in an existing project
without a good architecture, of course,
the results will be really really bad.
And at the end, um enterprise context is
also a big problem because yeah,
sometimes you have knowledge inside a
company that is maybe not documented um
somewhere or not in your codebase. So
how should the AI agent know that there
are some yeah rules in your company that
that the AI agent should follow when it
implements code for you? So how to solve
those issues? Yeah, this is when
specdriven development comes into place.
But before that, it's really important
for me, it's um really really important
to take talk about this and the
dangerous patterns because when you use
AI agents and I'm using them yeah every
day often you can see that they remove
safety checks from your code. For
example, you have a try catch block and
the agent thinks, okay, I don't need
this try a catch block because yeah, we
have another safety checks in our
codebase. So maybe it's not relevant. So
let's remove this or some locks are
removed. So you will never see that an
error happened. We have also this
problem of yeah making you happy I would
say. So AI agents try to yeah make you
happy by generating code that fits into
your um yeah estimate that you have into
them. So you give them a task and the
agents host it. But often agents yeah
hallucinate and they add falsely or
wrong data to yeah the code. So the code
task looks like it's completed but only
with the help of yeah fake data. This
also happens often when you um for
example write unit tests also more to
that later. And yeah there's this um
quote um I think this is also a really
good quote. Um yeah this kind of silent
failures is far worse than a crash
because yeah flaw outputs will often
lurk undetected until they surface much
later. So maybe you know that in
software development um as early as you
yeah catch on bug um it's cheaper it's
faster to solve this task and when you
have a white coated yeah code base and
you try to solve this issue later of
course this will take too much time. So
finally we can talk about specdriven
development and first it helps us to put
the complex context up front. So when we
later use an AI agent agent to solve our
tasks we don't need to wait until the
agent finds all the relevant context
needed to solve this task because we
have done this work up front. more to
that of course uh later. We have yeah
structured reasoning so the agent always
knows um what it should do step by step.
We have this together with the
validation checkpoints. This is also
important. So it's not just like okay
the AI agent generates code but there
are also some mechanisms that helps the
AI agent to validate its results um
independently.
Then we have this autonomous
implementation. Of course, this is yeah
currently not working 100% but this is
yeah maybe for future LLMs um and tools
coming in the next coming of months or
weeks um that the agent can completely
solve all those task without um our need
to take a look into yeah the code uh
because we will combine specdriven
development together with testdriven
development for example. So we build
really strong guard rails for our AI
agents and I think this is really
important. Um we should yeah
act with our AI agents like they are our
yeah pair programmers. So this is why
Microsoft calls it co-pilot and not like
stupid search engines. Of course, they
are really good when it comes into
searching through our codebase, but
yeah, maybe when you already uh used
such AI agents, you know, often they
lack um of context when it comes to
yeah, complex code bases. So, we will
combine specri development, the what and
why together with behavior-driven
development, the system behavior and
testdriven development um for code
correctness. So with this yeah three
categories of yeah development flows um
we should solve all those issues I
showed you before.
Um there are two yeah major frameworks
or libraries you can use out there. Of
course there are multiple ones available
but my favorite ones are open spec and
spec kit. Open spec is a bit more
lightweight. It's yeah made with
typescript and the workflow is really
simple. There's only a proposal phase
where you define your specification.
Then we have our apply phase. So the AI
agent is solving the specification or
implementing the specification for you
and at the end you can only yeah archive
the results. That's it. It's a really
simple solution. On the other hand, you
have specit from GitHub. Um it's based
on Python and a lot of shell scripts and
it's more comprehensive. So we have u
yeah more yeah tasks we can um yeah do
with um with specit. So there are
different so-called slash commands or
yeah custom slash commands you can run
and there are four phases we have
specify plan task and implement and I
will later show you um how all those
faces are working together and this
compared to each other um there are
different yeah projects who can or
should use those tools um openspec
because it's more lightweight and more
simple is better for yeah brownfield
projects so you have an already existing
codebase you want to work on and on this
existing yeah codebase you can use open
spec but when you have a green field
project so yeah you have not touched any
line of code yet in your new project
then the specit is yeah the tool for you
so but you can combine it of course uh
this is something I also like to do by
myself so when I have a green field
project first I use speckit to specify
everything more detailed and when the
foundation is yeah done by speckit then
I can switch to opensp spec to yeah
generate code um or smaller code pieces.
So we can also see that yeah specd
driven development is um already um a
thing in the industry. So um for example
there's an um own IDE developed by AWS
called KRO. So um yeah they launched
this IDE and yeah over 250,000
developers um are using Kroll after 3
months. So yeah, we can see a lot of
developers um are playing around with
this technology or this technique to
develop software with the help of AI.
There are also some yeah internal
studies from example from Delta airlines
you can see that yeah 94% of the
developers using spectrum development
are really um satisfied when it comes to
yeah this kind of workflow and we can
also see on GitHub for example that all
those libraries are gaining a lot of
attention also here specit as an example
after one week we can yeah we saw that
over 16,000 stars in GitHub um already
reached so we can see a lot of
developers are adopting this pattern
really quick and really fast. So let's
dive uh into um the four phases.
Specify, plan, task, and implement. And
before you even start writing one single
line of specification, not code, but
specification, um what is really
important is to define the so-called
constitution. In this constitution, you
define rules that the agent later should
follow no matter which task it's working
on. So it does not matter if it's the
specification phase or the task phase or
the implementation phase. It does not
matter. So for example in this yeah
short demo um I want to build an
authentication API with express and node
as an example. So it's really really
important that security um is always
first. So for example we should always
validate our inputs as an example. We
should always log out errors. This is
really important later. Also, I showed
you this in the slides before. I also
like to combine spec driven with
behavior driven and test driven. So,
when you use AI agents and tell them you
have an existing function as an example
and tell them please write me unit
tests, they will normally write
evergreen tests. So, those tests are
written to fit your existing code. So,
those unit tests will never tell you
that there is a bug inside your existing
code. So this is why test-driven
development works really good when it
comes to AI generated code. So in this
constitution I tell the agents okay when
you write or implement later a task you
should write the test first and
implement after that. So you write a
solid test the agent generates code the
test will be executed and then you can
see okay is the test passing yes or no.
And it's funny to see so I because I'm
using spec driven a lot in my projects.
You can see often that um the
implementation fails on the first try.
So there yeah it's a really good
pattern. Use testdriven development in
your constitution. And of course it's it
really condensed down. There are more
rules you can add to this file. It
depends on your preferences. Then of
course you can always use AI to ask yeah
your favorite LLM to maybe improve your
constitution. And after that it's
finally time to start with the first
phase. uh the specification part and
this is yeah the only file you really
write by hand um because it's the
fundament of yeah of spec development
because yeah this is the name this is
where the name comes from the
specification and the specification is
about the what and the why and not about
the how. Um so it's yeah you define
everything
um what you like to achieve and how to
achieve um but not with which kind of
technology you like to achieve your
goals. So you don't write something
about I want to build an yeah back end
using next.js
and the front end should also use
next.js for example. Now you write what
you like to achieve and why you like to
achieve and then you can see here some
outputs are built flaky. You can see um
copilot in this case created five user
stories but named them P1, P1, P2, P2
and P3. Uh so it's just yeah broken
output sometimes. Yeah because this is
how LLMs are working. But in this case,
Copilot created me five um yeah user
scenarios based on my specification on
creating yeah an authentication back
end. And we can also see this um yeah
specification is also broken down into
functional requirements, entities,
success criterias and that's is really
important edge cases. You should also
always think about edge cases. For
example, when it comes to yeah
authentication, how should yeah later
the back end um handle a token that is
not valid anymore or the refresh failed
something like that. It's really
important to think about edge cases.
Then there's this planning phase and in
the planning phase um you can get
technical and this is when yeah software
engineers can yeah use their skills. Um
hopefully you know how to create a good
architecture, which libraries you like
to use and so on and so on. And then you
tell your favorite LLM again of your
choice um which technologies you like to
use. So in this case for example I want
to use JWT. I want to use SQite rate
limiting express node 22 LTS TypeScript
or whatever vest it does not matter. Uh
everything technical is now defined in
this phase. And this is also yeah really
important um to think about your text
stack here in this this phase. And then
you can see here also some screenshots
about the output. You can see um first
there was a research. So copilot or the
LLM behind copilot effect checked
everything if those libraries I like to
use are compatible to each other as an
example. Then um a design and contracts
were designed. You can see here is a
open API yl as an example to define how
the API should look at the end. And
there's the implementation plan how we
are technical um stuff together with the
specification should be implemented
together later. And then only two phases
left. We have the task phase and this is
really simple. Normally you just run the
um task command uh in copilot or your
yeah favorite AI agent coding tool of
your choice and then um the LLM will
split those technical tasks and your
specification down into yeah small tasks
and each task can be yeah implemented
and tested independently from each
other. So you can yeah if you like to in
this case create 89 commits after um
after the implementation. So each task
will be one commit as an example and
yeah each task can be tested
independently and we can see here small
task authentication back end with JWT
using express um it's a green field
project in this case you can see um at
the end it will create 89 tasks. So it's
yeah really really detailed and the last
phase is where the magic happens. um you
hand over this list of tasks and the
constitution and the plan and the
specification and everything else uh
generated um by the LLMs before to one
or if you like to multiple AI agents and
they will now work on those tasks and
you can also see here in this screenshot
because I used testdriven development
you can also see that um yeah each file
or each functionality in this yeah small
demo um was well tested so we have at
around yeah 26
unit tests and as I described before in
the constitution test driven first. So
yeah the LLMs generated the tests before
they actually started the technical
implementation at the end. So I can sure
that the features are working but of
course you should later take a closer
look by yourself into the codebase.
So where does SDDD actually pay off
because not everything is perfect of
course. So where it excels um in green
field projects it's working really good.
So when you start from zero to yeah to
one you can use um specit from GitHub to
create a really comprehensive and
detailed description and what you like
to achieve for complex features. It's
also working really good because you
have this markdown files describing
everything needed for the agent. So you
define those guardrails the agent should
hopefully not hallucinate at the end and
you can also use it really good for
multi- aent coordination. So maybe you
know this is also a thing that you not
only have one agent locally running but
you can also hand over some tasks to
background agents for example. So this
also works really good. But SD also
struggles in some yeah projects and
conditions. For example, when it comes
to small bug fixes, maybe spec driven is
a bit overkill. For example, using
specit um yeah using specit for one
specification takes at around 30
minutes, maybe longer um when you
specify something really detailed. And
when it comes to bug fixing, of course,
maybe fixing the bug will take you 5
minutes. Why should you define multiple
markdown files? Also for rapid
prototyping and maybe solo developers
when you like to achieve something
really really quick then of course spec
driven would yeah make you slower of
course maybe the results are better but
when it comes to prototyping code
quality security is maybe not really
important for you you just want to try
something out then of course specri
development is also a bit too much for
your task. So what are the key takeaways
to summarize everything up. So AI agents
are of course powerful but they are
limited when you take a look into the
current numbers like yeah they are
creating false or falsy code security
issues developers need to fix more bugs
uh when they write code by themselves
maybe they would be faster um so yeah so
they are powerful but limited and
specdriven development shifts from yeah
code as a single source of true to
intent as truth so our specifications
define what is the real truth and not
the code itself. So specifications
become also more executable through AI
with the help of yeah your favorite AI
agents or sub agents and but it's really
important to choose the right tool. I
only showed you two, openspec and
speckit. There's also yeah this um yeah
IDE from AWS um hero I mentioned there
are different libraries out there. So
yeah, feel free to try them out so they
fit into your yeah specific workflow.
And we can also see yeah like for
example MCP servers or custom
instructions um specdriven development
will be a standard in the enterprise
sector because it's really important for
your complex projects that you have a
really strong specification everything
is documented. You know why you achieved
something and why you implemented
something the way you implemented it. So
this will also be really important in
the future. So there's only this quote I
like to end this talk um expectctional
at pattern completion not at mind
reading um from the GitHub principle and
then um I think this says it all about
specific development. Thanks for your
attention and yeah feel free to follow
me on my socials. You find also the
slides when you follow the link um on
this last slide you will find yeah some
demo repositories you will also find the
slides and also my socials. So feel free
to follow me and yeah again thanks for
your attention.
Thank you so much Daniel. Another
amazing talk. It has been amazing being
a part of today with so much amazing
content, so much amazing speakers and so
many amazing questions from yours truly.
So I'm going to welcome Daniel to the
stage and we are going to go through
some of your questions. Daniel,
hopefully you have enjoyed yourself. How
is it going?
>> It was going great. Of course, I don't
like to hear myself, but yeah, it's a
great event. So, I enjoyed the talks uh
that went before my talks. So, yeah,
great event.
>> It's It is awesome. It's been such a
great event that I've had to I'm
enjoying it twice over uh by teleporting
to different locations, those people
asking in the Discord. I see your
questions. I see your questions. Anyway,
let's get to the questions in the slido.
Uh the first one comes from Alejandro.
What is the difference between specd
driven development and cloud code plan
mode? The use of the ask question tool
essentially kind of like that whole
planning phase like what's the
difference?
>> Yeah. So it's not like one or another.
Um so the thing is that with spectrum
development the yeah single point of
truth is now your specification instead
of your code. This is everything that
spectrum is all about. And of course you
can combine it with the blending mode of
claude or any other tool you know any
other tool is supporting this blending
mode. So I use personally the blending
mode more to yeah use a reasoning model
for example to think about more some
technical things um using yeah the power
of an reasoning model and everything
else or depending on the blend um is at
the end also documented in my
specification file. So it's not like one
or another. Um but the specification in
spectrum development is the single
source of truth. So this is the main
difference between yeah those those two
things. I love this. There's like nuance
between all of these different places
where instructions lift. And then we've
got specs, we've got code plan mode and
and the next question from Alejandra as
well constitution cla MD agent. So we
kind of have these two questions
together almost which is like what
should go into the constitution and what
should go in the claw MD. But then just
in general, how do you approach? Because
I'm sure in a month from now, two months
from now, there's going to be another
place to put instructions. Do we is
there a mental model we can use to
decide what things go where?
>> Yeah, it's really complicated because,
you know, maybe a few days ago, there
were a lot of content from some AI
influencers that please don't use cloud
MD anymore. Now, use skills and yeah,
it's not really simple to overview
everything. So the constitution at the
end is about the what and the why in our
project. Um so this does not need to be
technical or anything. This can also be
yeah more about yeah the the business
cases and the agent files or the skills
or whatever the next cool thing will be
in the next few days or weeks. Um is
about the how. So the constitution tells
the the agent okay what should the agent
do or what should the agent do and why
like you should do follow test driven
development and in the agent MD file or
cloud MD file is then documented okay
when you define or write a test please
use chest or use we test for example so
this is the main differences uh between
yeah those two files so the constitution
is not too technical this is more part
of yeah your skills or maybe your agents
MD file or whatever you're currently
using.
>> I love it. Constitution and then maybe
you have amendments in there as well
somewhere.
>> It's currently really a mess.
>> Yeah, I know for sure. All right. So,
like this is always really easy when
you're starting a brand new project.
It's a small side thing or you're just
playing around and learning. But we want
to actually put this into use with like
big like projects. How could someone set
up and integrate spec driven development
in this an existing huge codebase?
>> Yeah, first things first. So you can use
specd driven in a new project or an
existing project. So there is um not the
challenge of of the tool. So the tooling
is working in all kinds of environments.
Uh the main challenge is of course when
you're working in an existing project
then of course you have to make sure
that maybe your agent MD file or skills
are already set up. Um so when you use
um yeah your favorite specdriven
development toolkit is already following
your yeah your yeah existing
constitution. So hopefully you already
have a constitution you um yeah already
follow some best practices in your
projects. Then you of course you have to
document those files in yeah this
constitution file uh thing. Um but you
don't have to yeah redoment existing
features or existing code um into yeah
spec files. So you yeah just go on with
your existing code base and then you
decide okay now we like to use
specdriven development. So you can just
start but of course your existing code
is then not documented in a
specification but this is no problem. Um
of course you can try to yeah document
it in a specification file. uh but you
don't have to. So yeah, just go on and
try it out.
>> I think this is good. And and you know,
I remember earlier you were talking
about your constitution, your
constitution not being technical, it
being very high level. Um and so there's
kind of this decision about like
resolution, like how much resolution do
we want in that constitution in the spec
files? Um, and this kind of leads to
Rob's question. Is there an ideal
feature granularity in spec driven
development where the specs are detailed
enough to drive accurate imple
implementation but not so broad that
intent becomes diluted but then at the
same time you give it kind of like that
freedom and guidance at the same time?
Are there any rules to follow?
>> Yeah, the the funny thing is uh this
this has nothing to do with spectrum of
development. So I had this discussion
all the time since I'm working in
software development with my product
owners. So because yeah they have yeah
many ideas and then they create some
user stories and we always had this
discussion okay how can you create a
user story that is small enough to be a
yeah independent feature and it's the
same thing with spectrum development so
I think about myself okay when there's
maybe no product owner and there's no
good written user story okay what would
be the smallest chunk I can cut out of
this maybe too big defined user story
that can work independently so I think
This is important. Yeah, maybe the the
full feature itself is not completed of
course, but this small piece can be
stand on its own feed. Um, so this is
how I like to write my um yeah, my
specs. So it should be one feature, but
of course what is one feature? It always
depends like like always. Uh so yeah,
this would be my advice. Think about
this feature or this specification can
stand on its own feets. Uh this might be
help you. Yeah, but hopefully your
product owners also know how to write
good user stories. So then hopefully you
can just translate a really good written
user story into one specification.
I love that. I love that. And uh another
kind of question when we think about
like this world where it's constantly
changing, uh Kent right at the top, he
said uh that it reminds him of when
there was new frameworks coming up in
the world of JavaScript all the time,
right?
There are new frameworks coming up with
like agents and stuff. So is are there
any frameworks you would suggest for
strengthening and scaling the agentic
effect in a team setting like GSD or
opensp spec or anything else?
>> Mhm. So in my talk yeah I mentioned
those two two libraries. Um of course
there are some more libraries but for me
personally um I like to use a lot um
open spec. So for me personally it's
battle tested. I already have used it in
various projects because it's
lightweight and for me also important um
it's independent of course of yeah which
what what is your favorite agent or
coding tool because when I work with
developers one likes to use cloud code
the other developer likes to use GitHub
copilot so I think this is also
important because yeah we don't know
maybe next week um maybe Google will
launch a more or more performant or
better I don't know uh CLI tool so we
like to use this tool and I don't want
to replace also my specdriven
development tooling I'm using. So for
me, yeah, specit um from GitHub and open
spec are the two battle tested
frameworks or libraries I like to use.
So yeah. Yeah, no worry. That makes
sense so much as well like the idea that
so many different like same way with VS
Code. Everyone has their unique ways,
their setups and stuff and being able to
give these frameworks to let people have
the kind of unique setups but at the
same time giving freedom as well. Now I
want to come to the most upvoted one
here and I agree it's not a question
it's a statement Daniel that was a
fantastic talk incredibly useful so much
that I can think about especially
working in large projects cuz it's one
thing to work on like using AI by myself
on a little project I'm building um but
using it in collaboration with others a
lot of this is really good especially a
constitution that can live across
different people's kind of coding tools
and and workspaces so thank Thank you so
much for an amazing talk and where can
people find you if they want to find out
more?
>> Yeah, thanks for having me. Uh if you
like to follow me u yeah use use
LinkedIn for example. Uh LinkedIn is uh
yeah the platform I like to use the most
to communicate with you guys. So yeah
just Google my name or yeah use LinkedIn
to search my name. U my name is really
unique so you should directly find me.
Uh yeah feel free to yeah send me an
invite. Uh I like to accept them of
course and yeah thanks for having me
here. Oh, you asked for it. So, when you
get that bucketload of connections, it's
on you, Daniel. It has been a pleasure
having you with us today. And folks,
thank you so much for your amazing
questions. I can't wait to see what
talks we have left. I'm going to leave
you in the wonderful hands of Maxim in
just a bit, but we'll see you right
after this.
Thank you so much. more amazing content
lined up. So many thank yous today, but
a special one goes to our gold sponsors,
Red Hat AI. Red Hat AI is a platform
that accelerates AI innovation and
reduces the operational cost of
developing and delivering AI solutions
across hybrid cloud environments. So you
should definitely go and check them out
as you think about building your AI
infrastructure, applications, and all
sorts.
All right, let's move on to our next SP
speaker, Lewis. Lewis is going to talk
to us about why software engineering is
becoming plan and review, not less than
just code. Lewis is a co-founder of Vibe
Campban and is a self-taught full stack
engineer who spent 5 years at the
intersection of AI and developer
productivity and they've been working
from 2021 on neural code search to LLM
based code translation to vive cam
bandan today. So, lots of experience in
this space. They are going to talk to us
and I'm really excited. Remember, if you
have questions, use the slido code 2627
to let us know what you think or what
you want to know and I'm sure that Louis
will be able to answer them. So, without
further ado, Louis, the stage is yours.
Hi there, I'm Louie and I'm one of the
co-founders of Vibe Campban. And we make
tools that help software engineers work
with coding agents. And that means that
we spend a lot of time thinking about
how to effectively work with coding
agents, be productive, get more done.
Um, and there's a lot that can be
accomplished. And so if you can figure
out ways to optimize your workflow, you
can get a lot of advantage in a world
where some engineers who figure out how
to use AI are going to be getting two,
three, four times as much shipped as
those that don't. Today I'm going to
focus on two aspects of this. one is
planning and one is review and how you
can optimize your workflow around these
two human elements of the process that
are becoming more and more prevalent.
So
one of the things that I think about a
lot is that as coding agents
capabilities have become stronger they
are running for longer. They're taking
more time to complete their work. If we
look at the types of jobs that you might
do on a day-to-day as a software
engineer, you can bucket them into
planning, writing code, and reviewing
code. Whether that's reviewing what you
do or reviewing what your teammates do.
And if we tried to put a percentage of
what amount of time we're spending doing
those different jobs, I think before AI
significantly started to improve
people's productivity, it might have
looked a bit like this. a significant
amount of writing code, a decent amount
of reviewing both your own and other
people's code and a little bit of
planning as well. And as things start to
get accelerated through AI, so first
with GitHub copilot,
then through chat GPT,
later with cursor, and of course most
recently again with Claude code, you
start to see that actually the writing
code part has flipped from being the
thing that I spend most of my day doing
to the thing that I'm spending almost no
time doing.
And so I guess the question is, what do
we do with all that extra time that we
just got back?
Well, one of the things you could do is
get on Tik Tok or play Candy Crush or,
you know what I my my vice I don't mind
admitting to is doomcrolling Twitter.
And there are even ideas now that will
help you uh procrastinate the hardest if
if that's what you want to do. However,
I think there are actually plenty of
things that you can do. And one of the
things to think about is that actually
even though writing code is not really
something that's even part of my
workflow anymore, there are other areas
of the workflow that seem to be taking
up more time than before. So, if before
I was spending 10 minutes writing code
and thanks to AI assistance, I'm now
spending 1 minute writing code, I didn't
just get 9 minutes back. In fact, I
think it probably added at least 2
minutes to the amount of time I had to
spend planning and at least 2 minutes to
the amount of time I have to spend
reviewing code. And so it's a mixture of
being both an accelerant and also
displacing work to other areas of the
workflow, creating work in those areas.
And so if that's true, then basically if
you want to ship more, you need to find
ways to plan and review more quickly. If
you're sitting there thinking, I really
want to, you know, ship something and
I'm just looking for the lever to pull
that's going to help me get that out
there even faster. Essentially, if you
can figure out how to plan more faster,
review more faster, you can figure out
how to ship more, that is the biggest
lever you now have.
So I'm going to dive now into some of
the tips that I have for getting more
done or making your life, you know, more
fun in a world where most of the job of
software engineering is becoming
planning and review. And the first of
those tips is if you had to choose and
it is a choice, you should be choosing
to spend more time planning than more
time reviewing. And I actually think
that if you spend more time planning, it
will save time that you otherwise would
have to spend reviewing.
So one of the things that I mean by
planning uh is you need a system of
record. So with coding agents, everybody
kind of has to be a bit of a manager.
You need to find ways to structure your
daily work that so that you can easily
see okay well what tasks do I have in
progress what tasks are in review and
what tasks are there to do and this is
because you're going to be getting so
much more done than you were before that
it can actually become difficult to
really keep track of everything that
needs to be done when it's all happening
in your brain. So it doesn't have to be
vibean the product we make. It can be
notion it can be you know Google docs or
whatever but you need to be organized
about your own personal productivity in
a way that I think only teams really had
to care about this before AI coding
agents arrived on the scene.
My next tip is about actually the the
act of planning with an AI coding agent.
So you need to uh basically ask AI
before it makes a change to take your
description, you know, and your
description might be quite small, maybe
contain references to what the problem
is, but not the full detail of how to
fix the task. And what we're going to do
is we're going to work with a coding
agent to turn that into a much more
comprehensive plan. So you can see here
in the red box I've just got a simple
prompt that says please plan how to
execute this task and you can use the
claud code uh or the codeex plan modes
to achieve this as well. You don't have
to just prompt it to create a plan and
what you'll get back from your coding
agent is the outline of of the changes
that it's going to make. So you can see
here it's uh it's referencing different
files and it's being specific about some
of the changes it might make. This is
really your opportunity to ask for
changes and it's important that you ask
for changes in the planning stage rather
than at the changes stage because as
soon as the coding agent tries to make
changes,
it's very difficult to then undo those
changes. AI coding agents are lazy and
so if they make changes and you later
decide you don't like those changes,
what you'll end up with is some
compromise between the first attempt and
the feedback that you gave it rather
than the clean change that you otherwise
would have wanted. So this plan is
really your opportunity to kind of set
the approach. Um and from there you're
you're much more likely to to have a
successful outcome.
So visualizing how planning might affect
review. Uh I've got two timelines here.
So the top timeline is one where the
person in the driving seat didn't spend
a lot of time planning. And so you can
see that they did a small plan. Uh AI
went and made a change. It then uh came
back to the human and said human please
review this. The human had some
feedback.
And then you can see this goes back and
forth with AI making further changes,
the human reviewing, AI making further
changes, etc. The other option, option
B, is you invest more time in planning.
You give it much more detail and
sometimes that means that AI is going to
run for longer because you're actually
going to be making it work harder than
it otherwise was going to to achieve the
change that you want. But the tradeoff
and the upside of this is that now you
probably only have to do one round of
review. So you check it, maybe there's
some small things that are off, but
directionally the work is correct and
that means that you only need to
implement one round of feedback. So the
thing that really takes time is when you
as a human have to get involved and
review is one of the parts of the
process that is really human labor
intensive. So if you can find ways to
review the changes less frequently,
you'll find that that has a huge impact
on your ability to do more because it's
so time consuming. So to recap, plan
more and you will review less.
Now we're going to talk about review and
there's two parts to the review puzzle.
One is reviewing the change itself as a
user maybe checking you know a browser
to see if the features have been
implemented correctly and the other is
actually reviewing code. Uh so first
we're going to talk about the uh the the
first one of those options. So, how do
you review things for their functional
um correctness? And basically, one of
the biggest things that and the biggest
mistakes that I see people make is they
have a really complicated dev setup. So,
you know, at the kind of extreme end of
the spectrum, maybe you need to have a
dev server running, but that's connected
to a dev database, but that dev database
doesn't really do much unless you seed
it with some dev data, which nobody's
written down anywhere. So, you need to
do it manually yourself. And before you
even are able to test the change, you
realize, wow, I've got to go and click
around and do 10 minutes of work just to
test this change. Um, so what I really
advocate for is making it as simple as
possible to run dev servers both so that
you can test things, but in the near
future AI is going to be able to test
work itself, but it's not going to be
able to do that if it's spending 10
minutes setting up your dev server and
even getting it running in the first
place. So here you can see on the left
I've got my chat and on the right I've
got my dev server and I'm able to start
that so easily because in one click I
can run a dev server from within vibe
can. We also have a dev server setup
where we actually copy all of the data
um from a seed directory into the
database each time. So you have this
kind of fully uh verifiable environment
that is set up that's pretty dependable
each time and there's zero setup needed
other than me just hitting the start
button to be able to test things.
My next tip is around code review. And
the most important thing with code
review at the moment is actually to make
sure that you're getting AI to work for
you to review the changes. And this
isn't something that I actually would
have recommended uh maybe even as soon
as 3 months ago, but very recently AI
code review tools have gotten really
good. There's a lot of different
startups out there that are tackling
this as their sole mission. that I
actually think that the out ofthe-box
claude code and codeex um coding agents
and the review feature of those coding
agents are pretty much as good. And so
what I do is in uh my editor which is
varan I ask for a review which will run
under the hood either the codeex or the
claude code uh coding agents in review
mode and you'll get back a list of
changes that the agent has identified
you should make and often they've got a
priority like P1, P2, P3 and you can
decide okay well yes this is important
please go and fix it or alternative ly
that looks a bit like maybe something
that's style and actually I prefer a
different style. Um and you can skip
them but it saves me a lot of time. I do
this on all of my uh pieces of work now
before I go and review the code myself.
Which brings me on to my next point
which is you want to review the code but
you only want to do it once. And I'd
recommend doing that right at the end of
the process. So work with AI, get a
plan, execute the plan, uh test the
change functionally, maybe give feedback
to it based on that, and only once
everything is working, start to look at
the code because it's incredibly time
consuming process to read AI generated
code. So again, you want to minimize the
amount of times and the amount of time
that you're spending doing that. So this
is how I review code quickly is again
within the editor that I use, I have my
logs on the left, but on the right I'm
able to pull up the code change that the
editor that the coding agent made. And
as you can see, uh there's a a small
diff here. it's made a kind of a bit of
a stylistic mistake which is to import
um but midway through the file which I
know is not totally illegal but is
something I just don't really like. Um
and so I'm able to comment on these
changes midfile and that'll send the
feedback to the coding agent which will
then go and make the change and
hopefully there won't be any further
changes after I've given that feedback.
And this is a kind of thing that I think
we've touched on throughout the
conversation we've been having, but I
wanted to call it out in its own uh as a
as its own piece of advice because I I
think this is so important and I'm
always amazed at how few people are
really taking advantage of this. But you
should be working on multiple tasks in
parallel. We are at a point with coding
agents where they can run for five, 10,
sometimes 15 minutes unaided. And if you
get two or three of those working at the
same time, you can probably find that
you'll always be busy doing something
while the others are running. So to
illustrate this, I've got an image of
the board that I was working with
earlier today, and you can see that
there's three different tasks going on.
Uh, one of them is running and while
that's running, I've got time to edit
and to unblock the other two. So, for
example, this one here that's open might
need me to open uh the dev server, start
the dev server, open a browser, and
check out the changes. And that keeps me
busy while another one is running and
the coding agent is working on it. And
so as soon as that one's done, well,
I'll then be free to work on whatever
the next action is for that one, whether
it's code review or checking out the
changes in a browser.
And I just want to end on a kind of
final note about, you know, what it is
that we're really doing. I mean, this is
a really experimental time to be coding.
you know, the the workflow that I've
just described is something that only
really crystallized very recently. I
mean in the last 6 months if that and
I'd say it's really changing and it's
your job to figure out based on the
projects that you're working with how
they're set up. Is it front end? Is it
backend? Is it data? You know, it's
really your job to to figure out how to
automate the things that AI is asking
you to do. If you just keep a mental log
every time AI finishes doing something,
what's it asking you to do? Is it asking
you to read a plan? Is it asking you to
review something? Is it asking you to
run a command? If so, find ways to
automate those things as much as
possible. And if you can't automate
them, make it as easy as possible for
you as a human to do those tasks. reduce
the amount of setup needed for you to
work on those tasks. And that is the
biggest lever you have to get more done.
Thanks so much for listening and I hope
this was somewhat useful. As you can
imagine, I spend a lot of time thinking
about how we're all going to work with
coding agents. Um, and if you'd like to
follow along with my experimentation,
uh, you can follow me on Twitter,
tokenobler. Uh, alternatively, you can
check out some of our work at
vivecanband.com. And we've got a Vibe
guide on there as well, which teaches
you a lot of the tips, and there's many
other small ones, too, about how you can
get more when working with coding
agents. Thanks again,
Thank you so much Louis for your session
very insightful and uh we have quite a
few questions from our participants.
Let's start straight away. So your
session was uh about like planning and
reviewing right and u uh actually I see
two top questions are exactly on the
topic. Could you dive maybe even a bit
deeper on how do you plan well and first
of all maybe what what could we mean by
well and maybe some some tools some some
extra advices on top of what you already
presented.
>> Yeah. So I would spend much more time
planning than you think you should. So,
you know, for example, I mean, something
I was working on about half an hour
before this uh was a piece of work that
was uh it's complete now, but it was uh
it ended up being about 2,000 lines of
code. But in order to get to the point
where I could start generating code, I
did a bunch of research on the codebase.
I looked up, you know, what's uh where
in the back end do we need to make
changes in the front end? and generated
a kind of uh a spec and and some of the
earlier talks have actually talked about
uh particular formats you can use for
specs. I just have a kind of free form
um you know kind of list out the
problems list out the uh potential
places in the code that we need to touch
uh and then go straight into coding once
you've kind of gathered all the all the
data um and it changes depending on the
type of task that you're working on. I
think for more simple tasks, you know,
you may be optimizing for speed and you
can just get away with maybe uh a very
short plan and then do more review. Um
so you just have to adjust.
>> Okay. So uh the the the bottom line is
spend more time on planning. Uh I
believe uh your your message is super
clear and uh actually one question is
gaining popularity with very high speed
and this is kind of maybe maybe funny
maybe maybe not that funny question but
be honest are we just moving the
bottleneck from writing code to arguing
with AI about the plan? What's your take
on that?
>> Um well I think there's some truth
behind that. I mean, the way I think
about it, the the the reason why I get
up every morning and build a tool that
is helping developers plan and review
code is because I think that is what the
bottleneck now is. The bottleneck used
to be you as a human sit there coding
and if you're a if you're thinking about
this from the perspective of somebody
who's trying to get as much done as
possible, maybe they're trying to build
a product, meet a release, you know, the
best way to meet that deadline um or or
bring that deadline forward would be to
code faster. And then like what's the
kind of AI equivalent of that? Well, I
would say you need to figure out how to
review code faster. It's probably the
the number one thing. So, um, in a in a
way, I guess it's kind of true. Um, but
the bottleneck is kind of always
shifting. I mean, you know, models have
gone from being able to edit one file to
being able to edit one file and run a
type checker to being able to edit one
file, run a type checker and almost open
a browser and test the changes as well.
And so the bottleneck in six months time
will be different and it was different 6
months ago. So it's uh it's we're in a
period of rapid change about where the
that bottleneck is.
>> I fully agree. I fully agree and uh um
wherever bottleneck is it's on us right
on on humans most likely not on uh not
on AI and that's a funny thing or maybe
not that funny thing here so we are the
bottleneck let's be let's be honest and
and and open about that cool um next
question with lots of uh thumbs and by
the way folks thank you very much for
sending your questions and for voting
for your questions uh for your questions
and other questions um any pointers on
how to handle
um many context switches of having over
five agents running on different tasks.
Any any practical advice on that?
>> Yeah. Uh so sometimes I I get into this
thing where um I've got maybe more than
three things running and you switch from
one to another and you kind of feel a
bit insane because you you you know you
can't even remember what this task was.
You're looking at the logs and you have
to scroll back to the top and remember
like what was the prompt and I don't
know what this is. It's it's like
multitasking brain. Maybe there's a a
name we need to invent for this this
kind of weird fatigue. Uh in order to
combat that, I think um I mean just
practical things like label
conversations with a very clear label of
like what what this is related to. Try
and get things to run for longer as
well. So, if you're switching between
five different tasks and it's like one
task every every minute, your brain's
going to be fried and it's just no way
to live. So, you know, maybe try and get
to a point where you're you're setting
slightly more ambitious goals um and
things are running for slightly longer
and then you know you're switching
between tasks every few minutes rather
than every every minute. Um, and then I
think it I think you don't necessarily
have to have five things running at
once, but you just need like a like a
reasonable queue of things to work on.
So, as soon as you finish reviewing one
thing, you just need to be able to go to
the the next thing and and stay
occupied. It's not necessarily about
having things constantly running. Um, so
yeah, there's just some some thoughts on
that.
>> Yeah, thank you. Thank you. It's a very
practical advice and I I personally feel
that the tooling itself is not is not
there yet because uh currently every
vendor of AI native dev tools um is
actively promoting this uh multi- aent
uh experience right but uh what I've
seen so far maybe like list of the
sessions um again to some extent that
helps but um exactly like like like you
mentioned right u developer experience
could be much better I mean all all
these um uh developer experience, user
experience points. I believe this is
this my my hope that engineers of uh AI
native dev tools are working hard on
that to again keep better overview kind
of much better dashboard of what's going
on rather than just list of running
sessions. Let's see where that goes. And
let's uh take the last one. Actually
very good to finalize our uh quick
discussion on like final part of of the
story, right? We we discussed planning
uh what's inside and now review. Uh do
you have a custom tool or prompt for
reviewing? Maybe let let's generalize
like what um what's your general advice
on reviewing maybe like general and
tooling and prompting.
>> Yeah. Uh well I think
there's something very illogical about
the way that we've been reviewing code
in the in the past. I think like you
know if you create a GitHub pull request
the first thing you see is this
alphabetical sorted list of um of files.
It's like how useful is that to to kind
of review things in an alphabetical
order. Uh not very useful. So what I do
is I uh I I prompt the agent to actually
kind of create what I call a review
story where if it's a uh you know a big
change which maybe touches some config
backend front end it's prompted to
present files in that order. So I start
with the kind of the low-level changes
database work up to the routters and
then finish with the front end and
things like that. I I just find that
conceptually much easier um to to
grapple with especially when you know
90% of your day is basically code
review. It's just less mental overhead.
>> Thank you so much. Super practical
advice. I will definitely look at that
myself and um yeah so we are in in
planning and reviewing era. Who knows
what comes tomorrow but uh that's today
and let's make sure that we are as
efficient as possible in at least those
two tasks. Thank you so much, Louis, for
sharing your insights and uh have a
great evening. Bye.
>> Thanks. Bye.
>> Our next speaker, Yishi, and he'll tell
us about uh code reviews. What are the
missing points there and what's more
important, how to fix it. Yishi has made
it a focus on his career to solve
complex programming problems both as
consultants and entrepreneur and we want
to hear from you. Please send your
questions to Yishai right here right now
or during his session or immediately
after just use slido and code 2627
Yishi the stage is yours.
Hi everyone, my name is Ishai. I'm the
CTO at LB and today I'm going to talk
about AI code reviews. Um, maybe you
have them, maybe you don't. I'm going to
talk about why they're probably not
doing uh everything they can for you and
how to fix this.
So, I'm going to cover um some intro
about AI code reviews and why we think
this is the first uh step that AI really
takes into the SDLC. Um I'll show some
antiatterns um that cause AI code
reviews to miss the point. And then I'll
focus on how to make them better um what
really matters um in your AI code review
system and how to get from mediocre
results to great results that really
transform how you work. So, uh, AI code
reviews, that's a, um, one a growing
success story for AI, um, within, um,
the coding workspace. Um, and in
contrast to how AI typically helps
developers, um, in the IDE or in the CLI
by helping them code, uh, code reviews
actually begin uh, AI's journey into the
process itself because they now u leave
the scope of a single developer and are
really a place where AI becomes uh, or
augments the process. Um if we look at
the different ways in which AI helps
developers and helps engineering teams
deliver uh value through changes in the
codebase we have three major modes and
in this slide I'm going to describe the
modes but also the their maturity um
model and how they advance uh over time.
So the first row is the coding
assistance. These are the famous cursors
claude code um clin cilots and so on.
typically living inside my IDE or on my
laptop in a CLI. Maybe I have a swarm of
of agents. Uh but they're in the scope
of helping me write code. So I'm the
developer. I own what I'm doing. These
agents help me write uh more code, help
me help me write it faster, maybe help
me write it end to end. When it's ready,
I will submit the code as a pull request
or as a merge request and it will get um
through the rest of the SDLC. This mode
um obviously exploded began
experimentation uh in 2024 and last year
basically uh was the year when this mode
matured. Uh so large organizations
already deploy uh agents and helpers in
this mode. um and in maturity I'm
talking about RFPs about um by baking
this into budgets about ha having
measurements around um how is it helping
me uh about having training programs
becoming part of uh even resumes and how
we evaluate candidates all of these
things are happen have happened and now
this is basically has become another
mature tool in the hands of developers
it's not over in terms of uh evolution
but it has gone through a quick maturity
cycle to become um something everyone
needs. The second mode, assistant
agents, are typically ones that are a
little more autonomous. They're no
longer within my um you know, private
yard as or my laptop as a developer and
they typically react to new code. So
these could be obviously AI code review
agents, but also agents that help me
update my documents, describe my pull
request. Um they're responding to some
changes or to steps in the SDLC. uh
they're not taking work end to end and
these are now um you know going through
late experimentation and beginning to be
mature with AI code reviews being the uh
I would say the the avanguard of
maturity um many organizations including
large ones are now looking and deploying
and um doing bakeoffs with AI code
review and similar flows that help um
the developer um process um with um
augmenting some steps
in particularly reacting to new code.
Finally, the third row is the more
autonomous agents like the Devons, the
copiloted coding agents and others that
are designed to take a task end to end.
These typically run in some loop in the
cloud or in my pipeline. They look at a
Jot ticket or a similar description of
what needs to be done, maybe take
something off the backlog, maybe find a
bug, they create a fix or they create a
new feature, they will put up the that
pull request or the change request and
they're much more autonomous in their
nature. These are still through like
going through experimentation. These are
still early. Um, organizations are
trying these out, understanding the
challenges they bring uh such as
ownership of the code and so on. They're
obviously happening happening. They're
adding value, but they're not uh in the
mature phase yet. In this talk, I'm
going to focus on AI code reviews, which
is in the second row and is now
beginning to move from experimentation
to maturity. A lot of what I will talk
about is what is required if you like to
become a mature solution.
So we uh in lunar b we talked with a lot
of engineering organizations um and
we've we ran a survey to understand
where people are seeing AI getting
involved in the SDLC. I'm not going to
walk through all of the areas here but
you can see um the area that is u um
under the coding category uh has a lot
of AI and mixed um modes where AI is
doing more work and AI plus humans uh is
taking over. So that could be writing
the code, that could be creating a pull
request and so on. If you look at the
review and release the the box I
highlighted, these are the one of like a
couple of the smaller areas.
Specifically,
if I'm looking at who reviewed the PR,
um this is where you see a lot of mix
mode and you you see some nice AI
activity. So AI code reviews are
starting to help uh organizations with
reviewing the code suggestions. But if
we look at who made the decision to
merge, who actually approved the pull
request and and merged the code, that is
still very very much human. Um that is
the smallest bar of all the table um
with regards to AI um involvement. So we
see uh organizations are leaning into AI
code reviews but not so much at least at
this point leaning into AI to make a
decision about accepting the code.
Remember that we're going to come back
to that later.
So um one of the key challenges coming
from using AI to help me write my code
is that it creates new types of
bottlenecks. We now have much faster
ways to code and developers who have
learned to use the AI tools um and and
really leaning into um having agents
like claude uh cloud code on their
laptop um running a few of them of them
in parallel spec driven development.
There's a bunch of of new practices that
all result in a lot of new code. So
there's much more new code. AI is happy
to create a lot of code. Um very
verbose. Um but who's going to review
all that code? Um if the review process
and you just seen that the decision
process is still manual, we now have a
new bottleneck about how do we handle
all of this um you know 10x uh amount of
code. Uh if our delivery pipeline the
the reviews, acceptance, decisions are
all still human. Um, in addition, having
so much more code and the additional
like increased velocity in code creation
means that quality issues are now
becoming more expensive. I have 10x more
code, there's going to be 10x more
quality issues even if I keep the same
quality standards. Um, which means I
will need to respond to quality issues
um um in a much higher rate. Um, so
having more codes actually means we have
to increase our quality rates and have
even fewer bug um density than or
smaller bug density than we had before.
So just to get everyone along on AI code
reviews uh if you don't already have
those uh in your organization, these are
code reviews happening in the pull
requests very similar to what um you
would expect from a human reviewer.
Whereas there is a a bunch of comments
in uh the pull request and in some cases
there is a suggestion highlighting a
specific line of code or area in the
code where there's a problem and a
suggestion on how to fix it. in some of
the um get provider UIs, you can
directly commit such suggestions. Um so
whatever you expect from a human to
provide you uh when reviewing your code,
you should expect from AI u code review
bots to you know look at your code, look
at the changes you've made, understand
their meaning, look at look for problems
and give you a result. The real reasons
why this helps drive productivity is
first and foremost a short feedback
loop. If I typically have to wait for
hours or maybe a day, maybe two, maybe
two weeks to get someone to review my
code when when this is a bot, when this
is AI, you get get feedback in minutes.
So, I'm still in the zone. I'm still
very much thinking about the code that I
just changed. Getting early feedback
means I don't have to context switch. I
don't have to remember what I did here.
I can quickly fix um or address the
feedback and improve my code when it
this actually reaches a human reviewer.
Maybe after uh I fix the the stuff that
AI found for me, the human reviewer gets
a much better pull request. It's already
fixed of all the um easier issues to
find. Um I now have much better quality
code to look at and I can focus my human
brain power uh on the difficult things
and waste less time on uh dealing with u
either simple simple things or just
things that I found before I had to. And
the third uh uh bullet here uh is is
important. it's an opportunity to add
another automation step. So if you know
we just talked about this new kind of
bottleneck and the fact that
organizations still need a human
decision to uh decide to accept code
when I have a good AI code review I can
start thinking about maybe I can
automatically merge the code if it
passes the code review right at least in
some cases maybe some PRs in some parts
of the codebase under some rules uh if
they pass um everything is clean AI has
inspected the code it's determined
there's no um block or bugs maybe I can
do a merge maybe I can skip a human
completely. And that is where you gain
huge productivity because humans will
probably always be the bottleneck.
So why does AI code review make so much
sense? Why is that a great use case for
AI? So first of all, it's an existing
human process with a lot of friction. I
have to wait for others to provide me uh
with feedback. They have to context
switch out of what they're doing.
There's a lot of back and forth between
humans. So there's a lot of friction in
an existing process that is a prime
target for AI to optimize. It's a well-
definfined task. The input and outputs
are well defined. Here is my diff to the
codebase and the output is a list of
comments um and suggestions to fix the
code. So, it's very well defined.
Another thing that AI loves um AI code
review typically can work with um
limited context. I don't need to know
everything about everything to provide
um a solid code review. I need to look
at the codebase, but I don't need to put
it all of it in my memory at once. um
much like a human um you know knows some
of the codebase knows how to search for
more information if they need to um
understand something they haven't
learned before um there's a well-
definfined context that I can look at
and it doesn't have to be huge um and
this rides the wave of using AI to to
assist with code we've all seen that AI
has is really good the LLM are really
good with reading understanding and
writing new code um that's already been
proven by the first wave of AI coding
assistants so it's natural to extend
that to do code review in addition to
code generation.
Now, I'm going to talk about why AI is
missing the point in many cases when
doing code reviews. And I'm going to
highlight some anti anti patterns we've
seen with organizations that are
starting to experiment or to roll out AI
code reviews and talk about why these
are basically blockers from getting the
most value from AI code review. And
finally, I'm going to talk about how to
improve it. So, the first pattern is,
you know, ad hoc adoption. just, you
know, just spend the 29 or 20 bucks a
month. Um, buy a tool, uh, provide your
team with access, maybe roll it out in
some repos. You now have random pockets
of use. Maybe it's not reviewing all
code. Maybe it's not reviewing all code
all the time. Maybe it's reviewing just
a first uh, version of a pull request,
but doesn't um, review it again after
changes are made. Maybe it's getting
ignored. We know about a lot of tools
that are running NPRs, spitting output,
but they're not really getting used. No
one is actually looking at them. No one
is relying on them as part of the
process. Um so just putting a tool out
there is not enough. Um typically you
are blind as an organization like who's
using how much is like what is it
finding for me? Is it really finding
bugs? What kind of bugs? Where are the
bugs happening? What's the density? All
of this information typically in a at
least in a naive AI code review rollout
uh is not there and you are flying
blind. Um and if there's any learning
here, it's going to be lucky. So AI code
review um does it learn does it improve
from the feedback that it's getting from
users? Does it understand the way we uh
want to see code and code changes
happening in our codebase the
differences between teams and all of
that. Um so if if you're just you know
slapping on a tool these are the uh the
walls and the limits you're going to
hit.
Second pattern is over reliance. So oh
there's an there's a code review. Um AI
has reviewed my code. I don't have to
review my code. I can write some sloppy
code and hope that AI will catch it. Um
so that's a pattern where by having a
tool uh with some quality label around
it. Um some teams, some developers will
uh will um you know overly just say okay
there's someone else that's going to
find the problems. Um and then there's
also a case where you have um you know
some people use the same basically the
same model like cursor and then bugbot
the same model to write the code and
then to review it. That in itself um
could be a problem. You want to at least
look at um a variety of models between
writing code reviewing it. So you have
more chances of finding things and more
angles here.
And then the third um pattern we're
seeing is sticking to the same old rigid
process. Right? We have one step which
is AI co which is code review. We can
augment that augment the human at just
that point maybe save some time for
getting the first review and and and
early feedback. That's a lot of value
but we're not changing the process.
There's still going to be a review and a
human decision. Um and it's the same one
process fits all um for all pull
requests at all times. This is what what
we see happening at like 95% of the um
of the industry. Everyone has to go
through a human approval and the process
is extremely rigid. Um I hinted at this
earlier. Um ignoring the opportunity to
make some changes to the process to
instill some flexibility and automation
is u like a glass ceiling on what you
can get from AI code reviews. If you can
somehow leverage them to make automatic
decisions about merging that becomes a
game changer. So keep that in mind as we
talk about how to make things really
really work better.
So what really matters? Um I'm going to
start talking about like first of all
how to think about evaluating a code
review rollout or solution. So this is
about the tools you're choosing also
about how you're using them. Um and
there's going to be a progression here.
I'm going to start with a simple uh
table stakes and move up the ladder uh
with each rung adding more requirements
and more value that really makes AI code
review solutions shine. So the first
part it has to be um you know not noisy.
It has to to not spam me, not provide me
with wrong comments or with a lot of
noise. If it provides me with noise, it
will get ignored. Um, the second run, it
has to find problems and errors. If it's
silent or if it's missing a lot of the
things that I needed to find, again, I'm
not getting a lot of value. So, I'm
looking at some completeness. Um, I need
to be able to rely on this to find
issues.
Third rung is um having multiple types
of findings. Uh, not everything is a
bug. Some things are security issues.
Something are around maintainability or
readability of the source code. Some
things should be a performance issues.
Um so having um like multi- facet um
code reviews which can highlight
different types of findings and
hopefully categorize them so it's clear
what it is finding. Um that is going to
be the next uh the next level up. You
want uh not just a single track or a
single-minded code of view that looks
just for logical bugs. Um because the
real problem is not is never just one
thing. Um the next rung up is it has to
know why. It has to be aware at least
with some awareness of why am I trying
to make this change? Why am I building?
For example, can it look at the ticket
the geo ticket or the issue that you're
working on and compare the
implementation with what the product um
requirements really are. Maybe it's a
great implementation of the wrong thing.
So having ability to talk about scope
about did you actually implement what
was needed? That's the next level up.
And it's a it goes beyond just looking
at the code. It's also understanding why
we're doing this. Going up the ladder to
the the higher up um parts of uh AI code
review solutions. Um so not all teams
work the same way. Not all code bases
are the same. Um an AI code review tool
has to know how the team works. Has to
be able to learn and conform to what the
best practices are for that
organization, for that team. So using
guideline files um scales other uh
inputs that basically fine-tune it and
customize it to become a team player and
not just a generic thing that looks at
code. Uh it has to understand this is
how we review and accept code in this
codebase and this team. Um it has to
have some learning capability and get
smarter, get better. So improving based
on the feedback it's getting from users
leveraging existing knowledge looking at
previous um pull requests and comments.
There's a lot of inputs that you can use
here. But the question is, do I have a
place in my SDLC for something that is
static and doesn't improve? Um the next
um um level is can I actually talk about
is it making me more productive? So we
talked all about all the value it's
giving me, but do I have a way to
measure this? Do I have a measurable way
baked into the solution that lets me
understand this is actually helping me
move faster? This is, you know, finding
more things, improving quality, uh,
reducing cycle time, um, helping us move
faster, and can I prove it? Can I show
it? Because there's gut feeling, and
then there's data. Uh, and finally, can
I use it to transform how we work? Can I
use it to change the process to automate
some things away, skip humans where um,
where possible? It's a great building
block for that. But am I a able do I
have the the surrounding support um and
tooling that lets me leverage the
findings and the fact that I have AI
code review to really transform the way
we work the way we accept code that will
be the top of the of the ladder. So by
looking at all of these, this like also
hints at what makes a great AI code
review solution and and rollout. It has
to touch all of these. Um, and I'm going
to give a few uh examples or or show a
little how we address this with with LER
B tooling. But again, you can apply this
evaluation ladder to any solution that
you you you want to deploy out there and
see where you have, you know, good
matches for each of the stages. And the
maybe one question you should keep in
mind and and and um look at whenever
you're uh rolling out the solution, do
you have a way to prove the value you're
getting? Cuz you're going to get asked
if you're um a team lead or someone in
charge of rolling this out. Um this will
be the first question. Can I prove the
value that I'm getting from that tool?
So looking at some examples, this is uh
an example of um like a ticker that
shows the actual findings, the actual
PRs that Linerb has scanned for for you
know this is dog food. This is our own
code. Um you can see the numbers in the
types we have bugs, performance,
maintainability, different findings,
different types and it gives me a at a
glance an understanding of the action.
What's what's what's actually happening
with AI code review across my teams? Um
we talked about being able to measure
and understand. So here are some
examples of how to talk about
measurements. I'm going to focus on just
um you know two or three of these. I can
look at coverage. So how much of my new
PRs are actually getting code reviews by
AI? This depends on the way I rolled it
out and whether it's enabled everywhere.
You can see coverage is not always 100%.
And this is, you know, maybe I started
rolling out by having just um, you know,
half of my codebase, maybe part of my of
my repos, and then I want to push this
up to have AI review all of my code and
see this come go to 100%. If I'm looking
at issues resolved, so a good AI review
solution tracks the changes that that
are made after the comments to
understand whether the comments and the
issues raised were actually fixed by the
developers. Did they commit uh, push
another commit that fixed those
problems? So you can see the number of
potential issues identified and then the
numbers of number of issues resolved. I
can understand whether the comments and
the issues uh that are found actually um
you know get addressed and then there's
the direct commits from the AI
suggestions. So if I'm the AI code
review actually gave me a a snippet to
fix the the problem and someone
committed it directly from that snippet,
we have we can track that as Um this is
like a great um signal telling me this
comment was directly accepted. AI has
actually contributed code lines here
through the review. That is a great
signal of success.
Um another interesting example is
looking at um scope issues. So remember
when I mentioned AI has to be able to
understand what you're trying to build.
So here is a drill down looking at
specific PRs across different repos
where AI code review found a deviation
between the implementation and the
ticket. So this really helps me
understand how I can um uh you know
double click and understand not just the
overall numbers but go into specific
examples double click all the way to a
pull request to understand exactly where
where and how AI has helped me. And over
time you can see it's finding about 22
or 23 um scope issues every week for the
team. So there's always uh value coming
in. Um yeah, this is another uh example
of what the scope um finding looks like
and it says talks about specifically
handling users uh in our database
contributors and so on. The
implementation is different from the
requirements and this is something that
the developer will have to fix before
this can actually provide what was
required.
Um I'm going to finalize by talking
about AI code reviews as a signal uh or
as a sensor for understanding code
quality. If AI is reviewing incoming
code, it is now able to tell me what is
the density of problems of different
types like bugs, security and so on uh
present in PRs that are created by
different flows. So I can compare code
that is written manually to code that is
generated by you know clog or copilot or
I can compare two different tools that
are being used by the team. Um we all
know that AI sometimes can provide um
code that looks okay but has issues.
Having that AI code review as the first
step now becomes a quality sensor. I can
look and say am I getting good quality
from my AI tools or maybe I have junior
developers that are creating code that
is not up to par and AI code review is
telling me that. So this another very
interesting angle of using AI code
review not just to fix the PR but also
to help me u measure incoming code
quality across the board and
multi-dimensional.
Um I'm going to skip a couple of these.
I talked about proving uh the value and
proving the impact. Here's an example
where we look at various uh engineering
productivity um metrics such as review
time. how long does it take me to merge
a piece of code or the pull request size
and others and I can start comparing
compare the u behavior or the metrics
for when a gen code review um was
applied to other places where it wasn't
applied or rolled out yet now I can
understand is it helping me to make my
cycle time shorter is it helping me with
with eventual code quality um is it
helping me um move faster as a team
basically so remember the question is
always can I prove can I show that this
new solution that I rolled out, this new
practice actually helps me deliver more
and having those comparisons is a great
step in that direction.
So to summarize, code review is a great
opportunity for AI. We, you know, it's
it's almost like a a task that is
perfect for AI, but there's a a bunch of
challenges between you and getting AI
code review to really really help you uh
move faster. And if you want to maximize
the value you're getting from AI code
reviews, you need to focus on
observability. Do I have the metrics and
the numbers and the graphs to tell me
what is it actually doing for me? Not
just a single developer in a pull
request, but as a solution. I need to
understand um and see how it helps me
drive the downstream impact. Am I
actually delivering more and to really
move the needle? Can I leverage that to
start automating some of my acceptance
and delivery cycle? Maybe there are
simple requests uh in some areas of the
code and some changes that AI code
review can be enough. I can automate
that. I can make the decision to merge
uh that piece of code without requiring
another human set of eyes. There are
ways to do this and remain compliant. We
have a lot of customers doing that. That
is the um maybe it's a bit you know
hiding but that's the real game
changanger that you can get from AI code
reviews. So thank you everyone. Um
there's a QR code here inviting you to
try out our uh essential solution with a
free trial, learn more about um AI code
reviews and that's it. Thank you.
Thank you so much for sharing your
knowledge and experience about AI
powered reviews and actually um it's a
great uh there was great segway to your
session from the previous one because
previous one ended exactly on that topic
reviews right and now we we are diving
much deeper into the topic that is
resonating with uh developer community
very very uh it's seriously uh I just
look at the number of questions and they
there are more and more appearing so I
just like approve approve approve uh
yeah let's not waste time and let's uh
start with the first one um based on
your experience what's the main
architectural mistake teams make when
plug AI into their uh PR uh workflow
>> so I I don't know if it's it's an
architectural mistake, but the common
mistake we're seeing is um like a set
and forget uh approach. You put
something and you hope that this solves
all your problems.
>> Um in reality um like any other uh
change in process or tool, you have to
>> um not just think about where and why
you're adding it, but also how do I
change the process around it. So it's
not just another another thing adding
noise to the PR, but can I
um use it to change the process uh in a
more fundamental way. So stopping at
just putting it there, I would say
that's the the biggest mistake.
Fair enough. Yes. Uh 100% this is kind
of you know to some extent this is uh
proper change management should be
involved right. It's not just uh like uh
one one oneoff operation. you you change
something and you follow uh how that
evolves.
>> Now let's take um this one uh actually
very very practical one. So we are using
Gemini for code reviews at my company.
Someone is saying Brandon is uh saying
to us but nine of 10 code reviews
comments are false positives. H any
suggestions on how to approach this?
Yeah. So, um,
you know, both in my talk and I think
what we're saying it's very easy to get
something to review your code, a simple
GitHub action or a similar um, prompt.
Just, you know, send a div to an AI
agent um, with a simple prompt and see
what happens. In reality, building a
review agent that actually works well is
an art and requires investment of time
and effort and a feedback loop and
improving over time. Uh, fundamentally
it's about
uh providing the right context to the to
the agent. Um, which is not just a diff,
you have to let let it look beyond the
specific uh lines of code that were
changed in the PR. um leveraging things
like guideline files and other ways to
tweak the output um and do some smart
things with understanding the code and
and so it's it's an art of not just
prompt building but also context
building um most of the smart AI review
tools have moved to an agentic flow
where they it's not just a one-off
prompt it's actually an agent loop that
goes and looks for more code that can
help me understand the code etc and so
There's there's depth here to build it,
right?
>> Yeah. Actually I'm big fan of prompt
engineering as uh as engineering myself
and I feel that I clearly see that it's
becoming more context engineering
exactly like you mentioned and uh for
sure you already mentioned that there
are some tools right and the question is
exactly about that maybe just just share
uh more tool you know you you trust you
you tried what can help developers on
maybe on top of the ones you already
mentioned. Yeah. So, um, OB's plug is
our own tool, Liner Bees AI code
reviews, but we're seeing Code Rabbit
get a lot of traction when we were
hearing good things about, uh, Baz,
which is another Israeli company, Baz.
Um, I'm hearing good things about Kodo.
So, there's there's some nice players
out there. Um I'm also hearing many of
our customers have also you know looked
at using copilot or using the cursor
bugbot. There are there's a bunch of
decent uh products out there and I think
after you get the baseline of something
that gives you good comments now become
the the deeper questions which I
referred to in my talk which is oh can I
measure what it does for me? Can I look
at the impact it gives me on my
productivity? it to to me it's not just
about the quality of the comments
>> that has to be good but there's so much
more beyond
>> did I as a developer get good review on
my PR
>> 100% and you you you mentioned uh
quality and the next question is exactly
about that and uh it's it's very
interesting one I mean we can spend full
hour in discussing that but maybe uh
like what are your like key thoughts
about what how let's say code quality
How is that changing in AI world? Is it
the same code quality we had in preAI
era or it's something different? What's
your opinion?
>> So I think uh at the macro level to me
quality means do I get up at 3:00 a.m.
to fix something? Do I am I getting
pulled out of bed or um my plans
disrupted because a customer is has an
issue and this is code that we own and
we have to make sure that it runs well.
um how that in like how that translates
to the technical stuff is a bit less
interesting. I think uh with more AI we
will see less uh visibility of the
actual code. So, it's not working well,
but maybe I'm not worried about
understanding exactly the line of code
which introduced the bug, but more about
how quickly can I get it fixed and how
um confident uh I am that I have good
tests and good coverage that will catch
it or similar behaviors later.
But that fundamental thing doesn't
change. 3:00 a.m. is still 3:00 a.m.
>> Yeah, essentials are still there. So
sessions of iness of software
development are still there folks. We
still need to to learn the basics right
and then build on top of that. Same for
quality.
>> One small thing that may change and may
be interesting with AI it may be quick
enough
>> to
get a report of the problem fix it
faster than waking me up. So I think we
may be more resilient to small errors if
they can be quick fixed very very
quickly. Okay. So it was down for 2
seconds or 3 minutes and no lasting
effect then my life my quality of life
is better.
>> Good addition. Good addition. And uh
yeah last question let's let's take it
like in short way. Uh collecting metrics
like uh what are your take on what's
your take on that?
So um I think two levels when you have a
code review solution in place um first
of all you need to measure it directly
like uh give the developers a way to
give you feedback on the review like a
thumbs up and thumbs down icon or
similar way to say this is a false
positive or I like the the review. Uh
there's a second layer of if you
provided them with the actual fix in the
review and they accepted that they
committed that code that's a great
signal that your suggestion was good and
um we are also able to check the code
after the PR was modified and see if the
this the uh issue was resolved even if
it's not through a direct commit on the
I don't know on the PR UI. So these are
all direct measurements of am I doing a
good work. The the second layer is can
you uh correlate this and like with core
productivity metrics like uh your cycle
time your how many bugs you have in
production or the you know error rates
because if your code review is helping
you improve the quality of the code that
you ship that should be measurable
>> 100%. uh what you can measure you can
improve like
>> just bottom line.
>> Uh thank you so much Ishai and folks we
have so many unanswered questions and my
best recommendation just uh find on
LinkedIn follow him connect with him
send a message uh and uh by the way I'm
also very open for uh for you to send me
connection requests on LinkedIn. I post
mainly about exactly the topic AI native
development. So I'll be super happy to
stay connected with everyone who is
watching this uh this uh amazing
conference. So find me easily Maxim
Salicov Norway, Maxim Salic Microsoft
just uh let's let's stay there and thank
you so much and yeah let's keep in
touch. Thank you everyone.
>> I want to express huge thanks to our
gold sponsor company called Render.
renders the fastest path to production
for AI application. 4.5 million
developers, 7 million services, and over
250,000
monthly signups. It's all about render.
And now, time for having quick short
coffee break, tea break, whatever break
you prefer. And let's see each other in
just a few minutes.
VI coding in AI Studio with Gemini 3
lets you build anything.
Build entirely new experiences.
Create apps that see. Make tools that
listen.
Build apps with a single prompt.
Get inspired.
Tell me what you want.
>> Refine
and refine some more
right now.
>> Share with a friend
and remix.
Then share with the world.
Bring anything to life.
>> Tell me what you want to do.
>> Using cursor, wind surf, clawed code.
What about MCP servers? This AI coding
stack creates new risks such as data
theft and prompt injections. Backslash
security provides visibility,
governance, and real time protection for
agents, idees, LLMs, and MCPs. We make
Vibe coding safe.
Allow me to introduce you to the
Cloudflare Sandbox SDK. It is an npm
install away. It gives you wonderful
code like this where you get the
sandbox, you do a get checkout, and then
you execute code like that. How
beautiful is that? And look at this.
That's not all. You get longunning
processes, real-time streaming, preview
URLs. How amazing is that? Code
interpreter, file system, command
execution, and websockets out of the
box. There is a bunch of examples. Come
check it out. What are you waiting for?
Uh, it has given us a computer that will
do weeks of effort. The developer
experience is well thought out. What are
you waiting for? Come here. Get started
now.
>> Pixie Bricks is the fastest way to solve
internal business problems on top of
tools your team already uses. Describe
the extension you want and get user
interfacing components like forms,
buttons, and modals connected to
back-end logic like API requests and
database queries. One-click deployment
for small teams. Enterprisegrade
security for scale. Build your dream
extension today.
You know, render for quick deploys, but
did you know it's also the fastest path
to production for full stack apps? This
one has a web service, that's a front
end and a back end, managed Postgress,
and a chron job that runs durable
workflows. And the best part is all of
your services in the same region, you
can communicate internally over a
private network that's both faster and
more secure than the public internet. So
whether it's an AI agent or your next
startup, build it better on render.
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
VI coding an AI studio with Gemini 3
lets you build anything.
Build entirely new experiences.
Create apps that see. Make tools that
listen.
Build apps with a single prompt.
Welcome, welcome back to AI Coding
Summit 2026.
Just a quick reminder, we are looking
for your posts with a hashtag AI coding
summit. take a great chance to win
special coding summit t-shirt like that
one and g nation multipass
and our next speaker is actually speaker
da rodi and Alex and they will tell us
about what's going on beyond w coding
differentiated workflows with
anti-gravity it's a new tool right Alex
is special builder working in developer
relations at Google's firebase where he
helps teams uh ship production grade AI
features with Genkit, Vert.x AI, and
Firebase Studio. Rosie is a deafil for
Firebase Studio at Google as well. And
let's
come up with some questions, right? I'm
pretty sure that you'll have uh some
some questions to ask. It's super simple
to do. Just use slido slido.com and our
code for today is 2627.
Rodi, Alex, please tell us about
anti-gravity.
>> Hello, my name is Alex and I am a
developer relations engineer usually
based from Waterl, Canada. and I'm
Rodie. I'm also a developer relations
engineer and I'm based out of San
Francisco.
Let's start with the basics. What is
anti-gravity and why should you care?
There are many different ways to build
with AI, but the harness, the tools, and
the model can make a really big
difference. With anti-gravity, the best
of Google tools are coming together to
create a unified harness and a powerful
coding agent.
Instead of the coding agent just living
inside of your IDE, your agent lives
across multiple surfaces that the
developer might spend time on. We
include an agent manager. This is your
simple hub, a agent first view with a
higher level view than your code and
your projects. It focuses on
orchestrating multiple agents running
across your codebase. It has a single
unified agent manager and you can work
across all your projects across your
entire machine. We also have an AI
editor with all the bells and whistles
that you're familiar with. It's a VS
Codebased interface. It has a lightning
fast autocomplete as well as a tab
complete model. It has an agent sidebar
where you can be able to have multimodal
input and do so much more. And at any
point you can hit command E or the
equivalent on Windows to get back to the
agent manager.
And going back to the editor, there's
also the agent controlled Chrome browser
which lets you give the agent access to
the richness of the web. And not only
the context over specific things like
the images and things being rendered,
but you can also do complex things like
have it complete tasks for you and be
able to fill out forms as well as to be
able to run your automation tests. And
this is also a sandbox, so you can test
it and have the agent click, screenshot,
and verify that everything works
correctly.
Let's start. But before we get started,
we need to install anti-gravity, which
is very straightforward. You either
download and follow the prompts for your
system or if you're like me, you just
send that brew install anti-gravity
command and grab a copy. Then go through
the installation on boarding wizard,
sign in, and you are done.
However, there is one step I like to
spend some time on. The important thing
for us to decide is a level of autonomy
we'll give to the agent. You will want
to balance convenience versus control.
Also, remember that better than safe
than sorry. So, make sure you follow a
few best practices. One, start
defensively. Increase automation over
time. and two, take your time to get
comfortable with each model, each sub
agent, and each task.
Three, keep sandbox enabled and only
disable it if absolutely necessary. And
four, allow list actions and website
mindfully. As long as you control those
properties is probably safe. But if
you're lurking on the depths uh sides of
the web, be mindful. These agents might
be tricked. Like every other software
engineering skill, AI steering takes
some time before it feels intuitive.
Enjoy the learning journey and do not
rush it.
Anti-gravity offers two ways to build
with the agent. See the difference for
yourself. presenting
on the left side fast mode on the right
side the default planning mode. Fast
mode is for building quickly and is
especially useful with Jiny Flash model.
Sometimes you just need to trigger a
task to be completed uh like uh building
a quick mockup, a workflow, updating a
dock and you don't want to spend time uh
going into too much detail. As you can
see, there is a lot more steering
capability that you can find uh in the
planning mode. Uh this is great when
starting to work on a more complex task.
It can execute
uh lot of different searches, gather
information for you, and allows you to
fine-tune how the generation should
flow. Both flash and pro models are
decent choices for this mode and you'll
get a taste of which of these two work
better as you get to build more
projects. Using the planning mode, we
can take the idea that we have and kick
off a new project in the playground. The
playground is a great place to validate
ideas before committing to a full
project. After we send the prompt, we
will have a full overview of the app
that gets generated with all the
features that need to be built. And one
by one, the agent will start to work on
the task and make progress. At the end,
it'll generate a walkthrough with steps
on how to run it and verify that it's
working. At each stage, the agent
generates artifacts for us that ensure
that there is visibility into what is
being created. And for things like the
overview, it can offer the human in the
loop an ability to comment and provide
feedback at every step in the way to
steer the output. We also offer image
generation. This is for building UI
designs as well as assets in the
application. It also has a very good
image understanding like being able to
understand screenshots and browser
recordings as well as many other types
of error messages and things that you
can provide to the agent. This is the
beautiful part about anti-gravity where
it's bringing all of Google's products
together with a great synergy. And Nano
Banana Pro has been available since day
one in anti-gravity. So you can rest
assured that new model capabilities will
come to anti-gravity so that you can
take advantage of them. Gemini 3 has
greatly improved on the design output
and code generation. And in
anti-gravity, you can take advantage of
it with all the ways that you might
interface with a designer or asset
generator. You can directly attach
images into the chat and with detailed
instructions on how to implement it. You
can also use MCP servers like Stitch or
Figma to directly grab design assets and
implement them as code. Anti-gravity
recently introduced support for skills.
They are a way to add deep and narrow
context on specific tasks that require
knowledge that may not be in the
training data or easily found with
search grounding. When you ask the agent
to do something, it can search the
skills that it has for possible matches
and then load them into context and
provide a much better output. Skills can
also include scripts, resources,
examples, or even instructions on how to
call a specific MCP server. Talking
about scripts, what happens if a script
that the agent runs ends up blocking and
waiting for the input?
Not much really. Anti-gravity will wait
for a few seconds and then it will take
action. Be it sending a key combination,
typing text, interactive comments,
anything. Even better, due to its
asynchronous nature, the terminal agent
can run concurrently, starting multiple
servers and scripts simultaneously,
making complex projects development much
easier to automate.
And my favorite is the browser agent.
It's like that universal multi-purpose
tool that I want to keep around with me
just in case. Might not be the fastest,
but hey, it's the most universal thing
ever. Also, it's an amazing timesaver uh
trick, especially when dealing with
legacy code. Each time when a UI frame
gets implemented,
uh you can let anti-gravity go ahead and
run and poke around finding and fixing
those UI bugs before I even notice them.
What's even better, it will record its
interaction and the most important steps
presented in in that final report.
remember uh the uh agent manager.
Essentially, I get something I can
quickly check and present to my entire
team. And this can also be a great start
for a next sprint or feature.
We have all this automation, but I
sometimes want a manual gearbox that
gives me full control of how I'm
driving, not just steering. In these
moments of inspiration, I take control
and flow using the keyboard. Uh, this
collection of delightful top features
makes me smile on those evenings when I
want to craft some code just like in the
old good days. H I think we're almost
there. When you're ready to move beyond
an agentled chat in your editor, you
then can start to work with the agent
manager that has included inside of
anti-gravity. This gives you the
visibility into all the agents on your
machine and your projects. and we're
hoping that it will help change the way
that you work. Anything that requires
input from you as the human will surface
here and you can make decisions and
actions on how to proceed. There is so
much more that we haven't talked about
and we hope that this just gets you
curious to try out different type of
agentled experiences. There's a lot of
updates and features rolling out
constantly and we're monitoring your
feedback and we're always looking for
ways to improve. Make sure to follow us
on social for ways that we're posting
every day and techniques that you can
actually apply to your workflow. And
make sure to head over to
anti-gravity.google to get started.
Thanks.
Thank you, Alex. Thank you, Rodie, for
this very short, very contentpacked
session. Let's have some time to to
discuss uh a few things and we have uh
several questions pending and let's
start from this one. I mean um I believe
everyone
noticed that this market of u AI code
assistant wipe coding tools is uh is
getting really hot these days, right?
many vendors uh many like big tech,
small tech, startups all try to to bring
uh amazing products, concepts,
completely new ideas to the market. And
the question is um is very
straightforward. What would you say is a
key benefit of anti-gravity over
something like cold code or codex? I
mean what uh I think yeah let's compare
this with these two tools because uh we
have um let's say uh some some other
tools on other side of the spectrum but
what's your take on cloud code and codex
like um how can let's say what could
motivate folks to try anti-gravity
>> uh thank you uh maximum uh let's indeed
unpack a little bit all the uh
concentrated knowledge uh as as you
mentioned right we have a really really
uh busy landscape with lots of
innovation actually the pace is so fast.
I can barely keep up uh with what we're
releasing. Uh with that being said,
there are a few there are a few features
that I personally love. Uh there are a
few features which I think have a lot of
promise in the future. So what I
personally love is the browser agent. Uh
I think the team did a brilliant job uh
on integrated integrating a fullyfledged
Chrome uh browser uh from pretty much
from the beginning and letting people uh
have a way to fall back all their
workflows into the browser. We see that
some some of the uh uh competitive tools
also adopt uh this kind of uh workflow
as well which I'm really happy because I
I think you should have multiple ways to
run the same workload because you don't
really know beforehand which ways will
have very subtile and weird ways of
failing. So you want to have a
redundancy. I think it's so important in
these kind of agent driven development
to have redundancy. So that's one of the
things. Uh another one uh I really love
our approach on the agent manager. uh on
how to drive multiple agents. And I know
this is very much a work in progress
still. We're still figuring out how to
best uh parallelize work and how to best
get the results. But I love the concept
of having an inbox. So whenever an agent
goes does it work and comes back with a
question or an issue, you get
notification in the inbox of
anti-gravity. So you know, oh there's
something for me to take care of. I
really love this pattern. I think
there's many ways to to take care of
earlyization of of development tasks. uh
but uh you know it's up to the developer
to de to try out all these different
approaches and see what works for them.
Uh for instance, I'm not a I'm not the
the biggest fan of the terminal. I use
it when I need to to connect to my
servers, but otherwise I I like my uh
user interface, something that is
between an IDE and uh a task manager
slash workload manager. So here at
Gravity I think feels the spot really
well. With that being said, you know, we
we give access to all of the the best
models that we can. So uh this is they
they can kind of try different things
and see which model works best in the in
the anti-gravity. And one important
thing uh we everybody can start for free
like they can try out anti-gravity for
free. They don't need to to commit to
anything. They can also get uh they can
sign up also to the uh AI package.
Again, give it a spin. uh see if that
works for them before making commitment.
So I I believe this is a good
opportunity for everybody to kind of to
get their hands wet uh with uh the agent
multi- aent workflows.
>> 100%.
>> Yeah, please.
>> Yeah, I was going to say I think another
big part about anti-gravity especially
is trying to bring the best of Google in
one place. Uh we even announced recently
that um you can do anti-gravity from AI
studio as well. And we're trying to
bring all the tools uh possible for you
to build it, you know, in one place.
Like we have nano banana built right in
to generate images. We have the Chrome
dev tools that we're connecting with and
we're working across teams trying to
like, you know, be able to build the
best agent with all of these things in
one place because, you know, Gemini can
be used in other tools, but like, you
know, we're trying to author the
experience end to end and I feel like
we're gathering, you know, multiple ways
on how to improve that. We're iterating
on feedback and we've like the team's
already sent so many updates and they're
just a lot of cool stuff.
Awesome power of ecosystem. I loved it.
I loved it for for sure Google has
amazing
services tools that uh interconnected
brings uh superpower 100%. Uh and next
question is quite uh quite technical. Um
talking about context does anti-gravity
support agent MD or clothe MD or like
let's let's just generalize that which
ways to content are supported by in
anti-gravity.
The short answer is uh that we do
support uh context files. Uh the long
answer is I highly encourage everybody
to try try out the skills format. So
skills format builds on top of the idea
of having a context file but it goes one
step further. It allows you to to comp
uh to have uh compo composition
essentially skill sets which can either
live in your project alongside your
source code or they can leave your in
your in your user profile and you can
share them among multiple projects. Uh
what's really cool is that there is a
broad industry acceptance of the skill
format. So you can start in anti-gravity
and you can then port it to another
workflow that maybe your colleague is
using or you can adopt someone else's
source code which is was built anywhere
else and if they also adopted the the
skills uh uh framework it will just
seamlessly work in antigravity. There
are still a few uh things around that
where how you present the skill file. So
different environments have different
naming conventions but uh they are
tooling that allows you to very
seamlessly uh uh port from one to
another. So my my personal take is uh
yeah you you can have a a project level
uh markdown file like Germany MD uh or
agents or such or such uh to have kind
of the the the high level overview of
how the project should be handled. But
more importantly, I I think it's it's
really cool to just dive in and see uh
what more specific workflows make sense
for your project, for your workflow or
for your team and uh have this uh
modular approach which is really well
supported uh by integravity and kind of
and I think it's future proof uh future
proof especially as we go into an an era
where we'll have multiple agents with
multiple spe uh skills per agent uh you
know looking at the So I think I would
highly encourage you to to look into
this specific area of skills.
>> We also have um agent/ruules
where you can have multiple rules files
that you can enable or disable. So since
we have the concept of an agent manager,
you can imagine that one task you want
to have certain set of rules and another
task with a different set of rules. Uh
we also have the concept of workflows
which are kind of like rules that can be
triggered with commands. And then like
Alex said, the uh skills are just an
incredible new resource that really
unlock um ways that you may have been
compressing a lot of information into a
rules file. Now I my rules file in my
projects are basically like try to
always prefer a skill if you have it.
You know, try to do these things and
it's usually like one or two sentences.
>> Great advice, folks. And I'm personally
big big fan of agent skills myself. So
uh and for for for everyone who is
watching us uh go to your browser open
skills.sh
and you'll be surprised I promise by the
number of skills created by community by
vendors uh by everyone. Um last time I
checked it was 73,000.
I will not be surprised if it's a couple
of thousand more since like like like
yesterday. So yeah. And uh you can
install this just by by one uh one one
npx command. I believe this portal is
actually supported by by Versel but I I
might be wrong. Just skills.sh super
simple to remember and uh I believe it's
again um like cross uh cross agent
thingy right it's supported in
anti-gravity
cloud everywhere. So this is open open
standard um if I remember correctly it
was anthropic who created this
specification and shared this. So yeah,
skills, skills, skills. Um, and let's
take this one. I think we we have time
for only for one question. Uh, every
tool and IDE requires setup and
configuration. Uh, agent require tool
configuration and MCP configuration. Is
anything available to try to automate
this part to make to make agents get a
bit more selective and dynamic with
certain task? Maybe it's even like
feature request, right folks for you to
to think about. What's your take on that
in anti-gravity?
>> Uh I I I believe there's two ways to to
approach this. Uh first one is again
using something like skills which can uh
have a workflow on how to set things up.
Uh another work approach would be uh to
essentially have run the anti-gravity
thing uh in environment that's already
set up to use exact tools you want. Uh
for instance uh these anti-gravity has
really good understanding how to use a
terminal. So uh it can go check what
your terminal can do, run the tools,
wait for the results, interactively
respond to prompts. Uh so I I will
highly encourage uh to look into the
direction of uh here are the tools that
already work on my machine uh through
the terminal. I'll just let anti-gravity
know that that my the workflows and
these are the tools and these are the
things that I prefer to use myself and
let you figure out how to do that. So
while you can use MCP servers for thing
that you want to expose directly to the
agent, there is another way which is
using the terminal that it already has
access to in order for you to do kind of
the same type of admin tasks. Uh and uh
can and there is one there is actually
one more advantage to use terminal
tools. Uh terminal tools are very are
very easy to pipe. So if you have a
complex workflow which needs to get data
from one tool and and pipe it or send it
to another tool, uh the agent can figure
out uh probably the schema and how to do
that efficiently. So it doesn't have to
look at all of the data flowing through
it and you you save some tokens, you
save some time and uh it ends up being
just as efficient. So uh so these are
the two tricks that I personally use uh
for uh setup and configuration that is
scalable.
>> Thank you so much. And my uh
recommendation for myself, use AI to
help you to configure AI. This is what I
do daily. Thank you so much, Alex and
Rodi. Was a great session and uh very
lovely Q&A session. Uh yeah, let's stay
connected and uh cheers.
>> Thank you so much.
Huge huge thanks to our gold sponsor
focus reactive. Focus reactive is a
specialist agency in AI powered web
platforms as a partners of uh versal
Shopify payload CMS and sanity. Focus
reactive delivers production grade AI
integrations from semantic search to
open-source LLM toolkits for headless
content management systems and
e-commerce.
And our next speaker is Christian.
Christian is a seasoned software
developer and technical leader with more
than 10 years of experience. He's also a
published author. Christian will tell us
about security pitfalls in AI generated
code. It's it's a huge deal, right? If
we talk about um all things AI native
development and I'm pretty sure that
you'll have lots of questions to
Christian and use your chance to to ask
them. Just send it via Slido using code
2627.
Christian, we can't wait to hear from
you about security in AI native
development.
which is very very important nowadays
since we use a lot of AI code and also a
lot of AI tools to generate code. I want
to raise the topic about security
pitfalls in AI generated code topic
which more and more developers will
explore. We know that the models are
getting better and better but do our
code is secure in the end and what is
happening if the developer don't review
this code later on. So today's agenda
will be a little introduction about me,
who I am, what I'm doing and also the
promise of AI code, how AI code is good
for us, how we can use it, why we can
use it and some dangerous assumption
about this code and AI help. Uh later on
we will continue with what changes when
the developer itself not just use the
tool but also review the code later on.
uh and here I will share with you five
pitfalls which I believe are really
important in world of security and we
should be aware later on I want to share
with you some information for where you
can learn about security also how you
can be up to date and of course if you
have uh questions you can ask later on
so let's start
about me shortly I'm a front-end
developer with 11 years of experience
using AI daily um different tools of AI
like a cursor like code and also VS code
um extensions for AI um like a copilot
ko also so all of the varieties my role
in my company it's a principle so for
that reason I have opportunity to use
many tools but also to see what are
fitting bad or or good for us like
company standards also I'm doing books
and I'm author of some books And I'm a
docker captain. This is title given by
docker to the community participants
which are really good on what they doing
and also I'm a speaker. So talking about
docker guides all of these guides was
authored by me. So if you're interested
for example how to doize reacts
application in best way you can go to
official documentation and check. That
being said, I want to share with you
something very important and that is
release of my new book and this is
docker for yaks developers. This book is
a missing piece which I try to fill in
our world of technology just because
many resources in internet um it's
written in a way that backend developers
should explore and understand docker and
when we talk about front- end
perspective is missing. So I try to
bring the information and fill this gap
to the community. You can check the
docker for reactjs developers. If you
love to go to docker or react, this book
is for you. The rest of the books are
just related to interviews in um react
world and also I have a book for
typescript. Definitely go to my website
and if you're interested, write to me or
just share opinion.
Now back to the presentation itself.
Today I want really to mention something
very important and that is the promise
of AI. What is promise of AI? So most of
developers the days um using AI to write
code but do the code itself is enough
good and do the speed which AI it's
really good at it um it's promising to
deliver a good quality of code and also
um I saw many people including me also
that we are using AI but we stop
thinking of the whole process. we stop
thinking how we should develop the
application in right way and also I saw
myself and many of developers I'm
teaching that this comfort zone of AI
generated code and speed itself it's not
meaning quality and for that reason
I want
to say few uncomfortable real reality
reasons and what is really happening
when we use AI without thinking what
will cause later on in our application
what we assume so when the code runs
without errors the verification process
it's shifted in a way to AI what I mean
here so imagine we generate some feature
this feature is really big and after AI
change let's say thousands of files
what we do usually is blindly the AI
that the code itself is very good just
because the model is very good but often
that is not reality and I saw it in
first hand how our applications was
compromised was hacked just because what
is happening is that the developer
doesn't do what is need to be done in
the end and that is to review the code
itself and the review process is very
hard just because AI can change a lot of
files and usually people just watching
them and don't try to spot the mistakes
or to use AI to fix them. So what is
happening at my team right nowadays uh
is that people senior developers are
saying that this is fault of AI. the
code is but let's blame AI and AI
it's too so when you blame AI you're
just not saying nothing you are the
person using AI so the ownership of the
code is yours and it's your
responsibility to verify the code itself
okay some dangerous assumption for AI
code first of all it's looks clean so
nothing suspicious but do this is really
true it the application compiles
So technically this should work. The
application is fine. Um my test passed
so everything is covered and also the
sprint is ending. We will fix this later
on. So all these assumptions I did it by
myself and also people do them a lot.
But the hard reality to understand is
that
AI really produce code fast. It's appear
really nice. It's structured good. It's
able to understand your context of the
application but is blindly inherit bad
practices like um code which is not
verified enough code which expose
security um vulnerabilities to the
public code which is using um let's say
some of the environment variables are
coded in the application or AI just
because it's very fast of generating
code is not meaning that we should trust
it and we saw many many attacks raising
nowadays including the official ReactJS
um library it was compromised the server
side of it it was compromised just
because nowadays we try to produce a lot
of code but in this fast process we
don't have valid validity check do this
is the right approach do this is secure
code and
again the reality is no share
responsibility with AI If someone try to
hack you and succeed, they will blame
developers not the AI tool behind it.
So keep in mind that each code which is
going to production, it's your code you
are assigned to it in GitHub uh story
and also commits your name will be put
on not the AI tool which generate this
code. So what is changed when the
developer itself review the code before
submitting it?
Code is trusted rather than questioned.
We saw that AI can generate code really
fast but this code can be compromised
and when you review the code you're sure
that the code is good to go to the
production and everything will be fine.
So also edge cases are ignored. What is
meaning that sometimes we use different
applications communicating between
between each other. Um which is meaning
the relation between applications can be
compromised can be exposing a secrets or
we can communicate with application in
wrong way or many many varieties. When
we talk about security we should follow
the rules that as much possible security
layers you have in your application to
verify that your code is secure. This is
meaning in the end your application will
be really secure and you will be not
compromised. So more security it's equal
to enough good application and good name
in tech community.
Um so also here it's very very important
to understand um ownership. Again, I
said that many times that your code is
your responsibility, but this is very um
very important nowadays just because I
saw many examples of okay AI can do
that, AI can do a lot of things but in
the end you are the person behind AI. So
use it like a developer but also not
good enough to ship anything which is
not verified. As I said, let's watch
some pitfalls which AI often do and how
to avoid them of course. So first of
all,
what is happening when AI create
applications is that it's use a lot of
good HTML. It's use a lot of good let's
say CSS and is very good of creating the
application itself. But when we're
talking about security attacks like um
injection attacks for example, you can
put SQ injection in your input just
because AI never sanitize the input
itself or let's say attacks which are
really common nowadays is you forgot to
remove some sanitization checks or you
compromise the sanitization and later on
what is leading is compromised
application. So here the rule it's
always to validate when we're talking
about forms when we're talking about
inputs or um any kind of submission or
interaction in the user to database and
back end to be validated and sanitized
in proper way and to be honest here the
example is very bad AI will not do the
validation and sanitization by himself
they will um tools will generate the
code but they know they are not so smart
enough to think in direction that how
this should be validated or sanitized in
the best possible way and here also I
want to share that usually AI grab
information for internet and we teach
our models from internet in internet you
can find a lot of good examples but most
of the examples are really dangerous and
you don't know who's is the person
behind them again don't trust AI
validate the code before going to
production
second attack It's um very popular. So
this is unsecure authentication logic.
Imagine you have a form in your website
and this form it's used people to be
able to walk into your application.
So imagine you are prompting and typing
to AI please generate me login form. I
want to be able to walk in and don't
specify how the authentication process
will happen. what authentication tools
you will use. Usually what AI will do is
to generate dummy login credentials like
test users or test one two three or
something which is not ready for any
environment like staging or production.
This is for test purposes. So to be able
AI to generate proper authorization and
notification process, you should exactly
tell the AI what to follow and also what
tools you will be using like out zero
for example or JWT token or something
else. So that being said about
authentication logic each time you
should validate do anything left like um
let's say user which is test user use it
in your application or test files which
you can securely go to your application
but you forgot to remove it just because
AI is very good of that to generate cost
fast. So second pitfall
it's basically broken authorization.
Okay. So imagine that AI will generate
the form. This working form is very
good. It's looking nice, shiny,
beautiful. But in the end you just
telling KI okay this is my user. I want
this user to be able to access only
dashboard
and I don't want to be able to access
the um let's say system settings or any
kind of settings which will affect
different users. So AI will generate the
form will put some validation will
probably the validation itself will be
stupid just because AI don't know a lot
of information what you have in your
database. Imagine that this test user is
able to access the dashboard but also
the settings and when the settings are
changed everything is change and your
application basically it's compromised
just because you never specify to AI
what is your authorization process what
permissions you should have for
different roles and do this specific
user it's editor role or admin role or
what role itself
And
yeah, I love this one. So, secrets in
the code. Yes, really still we have
really good progress of AI tools and
also models which generate code. But
still I saw so many examples in code
reviews that AI blindly put secrets in
code rather than to put them in um some
files which are never committed to g
like NV files or any secret mechanism or
let's say GitHub secrets and etc blindly
put something which will never be
exposed but it it is right now exposed
just because we use AI and Um let me
give you example. So I have a client and
I was working with AI to change let's
say how the back end communicate with
front end and we change the API URL and
also the credentials to be able to use
this back end and I provide information
to AI like context itself what is the
back end how we can connect and etc. And
what I saw is rather than update the NV
file it's create directly the variable
it was const
so directly it was put at the secret in
the code itself which is making my
application really exposed to the world
and please never commit files never
trust AI blindly and also the secrets
should stay in specific places for that
reason many let's
um hosting providers they specify
specific place for these secrets. Your
code is basically code but never should
include any kind of secrets or
environment variables.
And the last one it's also very very
good and that is dependency and supply
chain blindness. So um I saw one
application um it was ReactJS
application. So this ReactJS application
it was old like one year and a half and
no one touched it. And of course we
decide to use AI to update our
application to new version of ReactJS
and also to update everything related to
the changes in this version.
What is happening is that React it was
really old. It was like I think 16.8
eight and it was not updated. So AI
itself tried to update to new versions.
But what is happening is that AI update
to specific version which one week
before react world and also NexJS and
many people share around the world that
this specific version it is compromised
and we should update to the latest
patch. Unfortunately, AI don't do that
but directly install the um compromised
version of ReactJS and this is just a
small example
also when ISO like example is that when
AI update the mpm packages also added
some packages which I don't want and
later on don't do like check for example
mpm outit but what is happening is just
tell me okay it's done everything is
working fine the build is good
everything is fine but in simple check I
found like 10 or 20 I don't remember
exactly but it was a what security
vulnerabilities just because again I
blindly trust AI
so
many people ask me what they can use lag
information to be secure and also stay
up to date
um this is my preferences of course I
highly advise you to check them export
the internet we have a lot of
information about security but what I
trust is really CVA organization which
is website including all of the security
vulnerabilities in this website and also
give them specific identifier or ID
which later on can be used to um
reference the vulnerability and to see
also how um serious is this
vulnerability for example this was the
place where react community and react
itself mentioned that they have
vulnerability in server components. They
provide ID and this vulnerability it was
in the maximum possible um range and it
was high. So for that reason everyone in
the world using React understand that
they have something in React which is
compromised and for that reason we
should update the patches. Another
resource very very beautiful very good
to use is cloudflare of course they are
a really good um let's say provider and
also they have radar which is giving us
information in the real world in right
now time um in lifetime basically what
is happening how many security uh issues
we have and how the securities uh risks
are raising nowadays and unfortunately
um if you do a little research you will
find that before AI error when we write
the code of course we was compromised
the hacking itself will be evolving but
nowadays this number are raising a world
just because nowadays we can use AI not
just to write the code but also to try
to compromise your application and to
use both to try to slow down or hack
your application um to do DOS attacks or
any kind of vulnerabilities
Another resource will be basically the
official websites like Meta, Apo,
Google, Reddit, NexJS or bloggers,
YouTubers when something happen really
big like the last security issues in NGS
and ReactJS probably many developers
will be sharing this information around
the world and trying to prevent
theirelves and also to help to the rest.
But okay, we know from where to stay up
to date what is going on. But question
it is from where I should start warning
security. Usually security is very big
topic. Um in this presentation I
basically cover the most common pitfalls
I saw like example AI is doing. Of
course, the variety of AI security risks
are really a world and to be able to
stay up to date and warn also security
and how to check and explore security in
a way. I want to give you some examples
of very good websites I personally use.
So first one it's
OAPS or basically um organization
website which you can go there and they
explain in very very nice way um each
security vulnerability. They explain
what it is, how it's affecting your
application and also how you can protect
yourself. Another good resource is
called flare warning. They have a
warning path. You can go and follow some
courses. In the end, you will have a
very good understanding of security
itself. And last but not least, it's try
hackme. This really beautiful website.
It's created in a way that your purpose
there is to try to hack the website
itself. you have tasks and if you are
smart enough you will be able to succeed
to succeed successfully hack the uh
website which is really nice and good
resource to of course explore books
explore YouTube blog posts and etc the
topic about security is very very big
and I believe many people should talk
about that just because what is
happening nowadays is really
applications are done in a way that AI
help
But AI not defend us. All of the these
pitfalls are very nice. We understand
them. We will try to stay secure. But
also how we should prevent these
security issues. What we can do is
basically to create AI rules in for
example in cursor you can create
specific rules for the tool cursor and
use these specific rules. So whenever
you generate the code we will these
tools will be used and later on we are
sure that we have a checklist and this
check uh checklist will validate that
each step is validated you are secure
and all of these pitfalls are not in
your code. I created a public repo about
that. Of course, you can go explore um
commit it if you want in your code
itself or try to support the community
and contribute to open source and create
more rules. Personally, what I'm doing
is I have a rules for code, how to write
a code, what structure to follow, uh
what is best practices. Um also I
including here AI security performance
and not in the end testing. Testing is
very important. It's like a way to
prevent yourself before anything worse
happen. And if you change something, of
course, the test will fail. So, you
should update your code. And uh not in
the last point is probably the
documentation.
Don't forget to update the
documentation. Treat it like it's code
and also update your um application npm
packages to the latest one. So in that
way you will be up to date and you will
know that nothing bad will happen at
least for now because when we talk about
security everything is for today
tomorrow everything can be changed hope
really this presentation help you this
is just a raising uh topic and I'm sure
that if you are curious more about that
you go and explore I already provide you
very nice resources to start of course
if you have anything you want to share
with me you can contact me with LinkedIn
or X or go to my website, explore my
books and just try to be up to date what
is happening and also stay secure. Thank
you and hope this presentation really
will be used in your code.
Thank you so much Christian for your
session and uh that topic is uh
resonating. So I see I look at the
number of questions um yeah AI coding AI
development is here but is that really
secure? Can we trust that? So many open
questions, so many interesting stories
in the wild about uh this or that case
uh like hacking with AI or hacking AI
all that stuff. So let's let's start.
And the first question is a couple of
talks ago it was mentioned that um the
lost opportunity of letting AI
automatically review and merge uh pull
requests. What's your opinion on that?
So first of all I'm really happy that
this topic it's widely spread just
because it's very important and um
nowadays we all of the developers
probably use AI in some form. So yeah
people be aware AI it's not secure in
first place. So my opinion that is treat
AI code generating code like someone who
is doesn't know at all what is your
project what is security um how to
implement security and etc. Don't
blindly trust it which is meaning
implement as much as possible security
layers. One security layer of course
will be to don't try to blindly trust AI
to validate the generated code. for
example asking it uh do my code is
secure because we are knowing that AI
can coordinate a lot and can do mistakes
and it's happening in production and
that will be risky. So one validation is
first of all ask AI about the code to
validate it itself. Second, don't
blindly trust AI but review it by
yourself. In the end, in GitHub
um in pull request which can be really
leaked or has a lot of security
vulnerabilities, your name will be put
on not the AI. So don't believe AI.
>> Yeah. What uh how I frame it in my
sessions, we are pilots. We are still
pilots and all other AI dev tools
regardless of their name is just are
co-pilots right so it's we are still h
solely responsible for every single line
of the code ends up uh in the cloud or
in server on your basement so yeah
that's today might be different tomorrow
right but uh who knows
>> let's live in in in the real world next
question I see it more maybe joke there
rather than question have you seen Um,
anyone ship AI generated code straight
to Proton Friday afternoon and leave to
tell this story?
>> Let's frame it like the most scary story
of uh about AI security uh from from
your experience like scary or or fun
something that you can share with
everyone.
>> I don't overshare like without company
names please.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Of course, of course. Uh so
I will talk with without any company
names but imagine that be really quiet
and we should deliver really fast and we
know the rule don't deploy on Friday
which is like a maximum rule to
basically follow if you want to be
secure in a way and what is happening is
that with the deploy Friday and
unfortunately what is happening in the
end is that we don't manage because we
was on rush we don't manage to review
the code exactly what is going on and
yeah first of all we have a security
vulnerability issue with our inputs just
because we don't validate them and in
Monday we realized that in our databases
uh the records itself it was something
which we don't expect and we should fix
that faster than the deploy so first of
all um warning by mistakes uh don't
deploy Friday and second uh AI I is
good. AI can do a lot of helpful
generation of the code but in the end um
keep in mind that AI will do what is in
internet and how it's trained. If you
don't specify any rules or any uh
specifications how the AI should react
probably will get what is most important
and used by someone else and this is not
meaning is good.
>> Absolutely. Absolutely. Yeah. Thanks for
um like uh answering this uh kind of
funny question in very very pragmatic
and and useful way. I think uh everyone
learned from from that story. Uh and the
next one is is quite general. So let's
let's try to be as specific as possible
there. Uh are there any techniques you
use to leverage AI for building more
secure code? Like super general question
and a bit uh elaboration. uh for example
using AI to write an injection prompt to
test the security of a feature. I what
are your your personal techniques?
>> So so my personal techniques are
basically you grab any AI tool um
doesn't matter what is your preferred
tool of generation of the code but keep
in mind that you should tell AI how to
react what to do and etc. And nowadays
thankfully we have any variations like
planning we have also rules and what I'm
doing personally it's setting the rules
for security. So what is happening is
that after AI generate the code tell me
what security issues can have what I
should look properly and also what is
the security risks and later on I
validate the code itself by me but this
is not enough because when we talk about
security the layers of security as much
as possible as much as good just because
you can miss something and what we doing
usually it's we have a pipelines and in
pipelines we have security tests we use
different providers I will not mention
the names but a variety of tools to scan
our code how good it is what security
issues we have and of course we have
different environments like first code
is going in development then staging and
production so yeah that is my workflow
>> thanks for sharing it's a pragmatic one
and yeah we are like 100% % correct. Uh
and this is what I always uh remind
people make sure that you have multiple
security layers levels and uh try to
protect every single part of what we
call SDLC software development life
cycle. Right? So don't rely on like one
particular tool at one particular stage.
The more the more layers you have the
better for sure. And we have time for uh
one last question. Let me pick um this
one that is kind of very very specific.
How can I prompt AI to choose the
correct libraries or frameworks for a
task when I'm not sure what the ideal
implementation looks like so it can
choose appropriate and reliable
libraries. So let let let's reframe this
a bit. Uh how to make sure that um all
the all the external package we download
are to some extent secure right or at
least as secure as possible. Any
recommendation on that? Yeah. So my
recommendations is basically when AI try
to run some script or install any
packages in your application be aware
that your first job is to go to npm
registry to validate this package is
good enough
a lot. What is good enough? A lot of
downloads supporting no security issues.
I mentioned in uh my talk that some
resources you can use to follow the
trends what is going on and to be up to
date with the news about security. Um we
know that unfortunately we have a lot of
security issues in react world and yeah
it's happening this is the reality and
we are living in really dangerous times
about security. So it's your
responsibility to go to check the
packages and if you don't know what and
how should be the end result start with
end result to learn the basics learn the
language learn how the architecture will
work and later on trust the AI to do the
job.
>> Absolutely. Absolutely. And uh reminder
from from myself that folks even legit
library framework package at any single
point of time can become hacked right uh
supply chain attacks pull the rag
attacks yeah we are living in in
nonsecure way so don't um again but back
back to the statement about have
multiple layers of security uh thank you
so much Christian we have many more
questions but folks uh my best
recommendation find Christian on
LinkedIn uh send your uh questions there
and stay connected um to make sure that
you are updated on latest and greatest
part on AI um security and uh also find
myself on LinkedIn. I just accepted lots
of connection requests from um folks who
already did it. Find Maxim Salikov
Norway, Maxim Sal of Microsoft. My great
pleasure to stay connected with
everyone. Christian, thank you so much.
Let's stay in touch.
>> Thank you, Maxim.
I want to express huge gratitude to our
gold sponsor backslash. Backslash
secures wipe coding and AI native
development environments across. Prepare
for lots of abbreviations IDs, MCPS,
LLMs and agents. I hope after today's
conference you know every single
abbreviation.
And our next speaker, Gil Freriedman,
and it's all about MCPs. How to avoid
security pitfalls. I remember in early
days of MCP, there was a joke, no joke.
S stands for security in MCP
abbreviation. Of course, it's it's
slightly different today, right? And
let's hear from Gil. Gil is a field CTO
at back/security where he focuses on
securing modern software development in
the age of AIdriven coding. Gil, please
tell us about how to avoid security
pitfalls in MCP.
Hi, thank you for joining. I'm Gil
Freriedman, field CTO at Backlash
Security. Today we're going to talk
about MCP security. What should we do
before, during, and after we use MCPS?
What is MCP? MCP is model context
protocol. It's an open standard for
connecting airl
tools and data.
MCPS connect to our AI assistant.
MCPS provide tools which are all the
actions that we can do with the MCPS.
These are like our hands and legs.
Why should we care about MCP security?
We should care because some of the MCPS
can read files, write files and they
have all kind of permissions.
Also, they might be exposed to some
credentials. Also, they exposed to some
API keys and some files that contain
some security context.
As they also perform some actions, they
can be triggered by our model to do
things that we don't want them to do.
Let's go over the three stages of the
MCP life cycle. Before, during, and
after.
Before installing an MCP, we need to
search for one. MCPS are listed in all
kind of websites. First of all, search
for the official vendor where the day
published MCP.
Second, check the repo if it's active,
well-maintained, and with stars. In
addition, some of the AI agents websites
they recommend about MCPS.
Please don't use MCPS from random GitHub
repos. Check whether the servers are
trusted registries. Don't just copy and
paste configuration of MCP and copy
paste it to your environment. On local
MCPS that you install them on your
environment, you should go over the code
to check the code whether there are
security risks.
You should check the code for any
security risk that might have in these
specific MCPS. There are some website
like back/mcphub
where you can search for MCP and it
provide you the full security risk for
these MCPS. When you download the MCP
and now you configure it and now you
need to provide the API key for that
MCP. We need you to generate the API key
for example GitHub token.
Make sure it just for a specific repo
and read only if this is the only thing
that you would like the MCP to control
and interact with this repo. In most or
even all the AI agents, these very
important settings that you should
check. This is the auto run mode. You
should set it to ask every time. When
you set it to ask every time, the AI
agent will ask you every time before it
will trigger MCP to check for your
approval. The last thing you want that
the tool will run without your review.
Here is very interesting case study
about the Postmark MCP incident.
In September 2025, that was where the
first malicious MCP server was
discovered in a while.
attacker published Postmark MCP on APM
which was almost exact clone of the
official Postmark MCP.
There were 15 clean versions. Everything
was identical as the official MCP. It
was active and everything looked legit.
The problem started with the 16th
version of that MCP. They added one line
of code BCC of all outgoing emails.
That's it. Just one line of code.
Once it was added to the MCP,
once it was added, Once it was added,
password tokens, account details, and
payment receipt and other sensitive
information were silently copied to the
attacker email.
After you install the MCP, this is a
time to go over all the tools that this
MCP provides.
On the IDE, you will see the list of
tools the server exposes. And before
using this MCP, you should read each one
of the tools description and the input
schema very carefully. You need to
compare the declare tools versus what
you actually need. Also check whether is
this run command execute after you check
the tools and the descriptions. You
should disabled all the unused and the
suspicious tools.
For example, here on this specific
server, it exposes eight tools. If you
need to have just a functionality of
three of these tools, you should disable
all the rest tools.
When you use the MCPS and you type in
your prompt
before the AI agent will trigger a
request to that MCP tool, it will ask
for your permission. This is an
opportunity for you to read all the
parameters carefully. They might contain
some secrets, some API keys, some things
that you don't want them to be passed to
the MCP. Once you decided that you don't
want to have this MCP anymore, you
should remove it from your environment.
You need to clean up your environment
from that specific MCP. You need to make
sure that the MCP was removed from the
configuration settings and also from the
JSON files. Also check that there are no
any leftover files or processes related
to this MCP. If you provided API key for
that MCP, go to the provider dashboard
and delete the keys. Last thing, review
any git history for injected changes.
There might be some recent commits,
unexpected modifications that were done
as a result of configuration of the MCP.
Let's summarize. Here's a checklist for
you to check before, during, and after
using MCPS.
Scan the MCP. Use just trusted
resources.
Provide scoped APIs. Set auto run to ask
every time. After you install the MCP,
inspect all the tools. Disable unused
tools, suspicious tools, also by the
name and definitely by the context.
Check the parameters for data leakage.
After you decided to remove the MCP,
make sure it's completely removed from
your environment and also revoke all the
API keys.
Thank you very much.
Thank you so much for your great great
session. And our next speaker is the one
and only Ken K can villier of course and
his session is about your new job,
right? You remember the question we we
asked the very beginning of the
conference like what happens if AI takes
your job? Let's uh let's finalize the
event with u thoughts on that topic,
right? Of course, like it's it's a joke,
right? AI will not take your job. You
are safe and secure, but you need to
learn about AI to stay safe and secure.
Ken is a staff engineer at Redacted
ReactJS, advocate, speaker, producer,
thinwave artist after all. And I'm sure
that you want to ask Ken about many
things. uh maybe not uh not only about
the session but um all things around
what he is doing and you have great
opportunity to do that just use
slido.com and our today's code 2627
can tell us about your new job my new
job everyone's new
Hi everybody. I'm Ken Wheeler. Um, it is
6:30 in the morning. I'm in Orlando,
Florida in a business center. Looks like
I'm being detained, but I'm here today
to talk about your new job.
Um,
it's pretty weird out there
right now. Um, there's this there's a
wild vibe in the air. Um, if you're on
Twitter, uh, reading a lot of these
things, right, it can kind of play with
your mind a little bit. You have a lot
of uh
stuff that's that's that's hyped, some
stuff that's not hyped. You have a lot
of thread boys um saying that the
software is over. Um you have a lot of
people who are directly invested in AI
saying, you know, software's over.
They're super excited that um they don't
have to pay software engineers anymore.
Um and then you have, you know, other
takes saying that, you know, they're
wrong, yada yada, and it's this push
pull all day long. Um, I wanted to take
this opportunity to kind of talk through
some of this because I know that a lot
of people have some anxiety
um about what's going on and
I thought we should talk.
Uh, so what's going to happen? I can't
answer that. I don't know. Um,
you know, it
I would have slides. I would I would
give prescriptive uh advice on on what
to use or what to do. Um but by the time
this recording got released,
it would probably be out of date. Um you
know, I could sit here and say, "Oh
yeah, let's, you know, set up Open Claw
and how much fun I'm having with that."
Um but there'll probably be a new thing
in in a couple weeks. Um
but at the end of the day, one thing
that I can tell you is that you have a
new job.
and it is largely the same as your old
job. Um, but you are doing it vastly
different from from now forward. Um,
to really boil it down, right, it's
you're you're not typing, right? That
that would be the the most minimal sense
is like you're not going to do a great
deal of typing code out anymore.
And uh that's okay, right? I I think
that that is helpful
um not just in efficiency but you know
in avoiding carpal tunnel syndrome and
things like that. Um but I think that
you know it's definitely worth looking
at as a positive and there is precedent
in that sense. I think that um you know
I I operated coding a long time ago when
you didn't have a lot of the accutrants
that you have today. uh things like
I mean just just off the bat, right?
Like like I remember before even any AI
or anything like that. Um just
IntelliSense, right? Going into VS Code
and getting IntelliSense and being able
to um get Typescript language servers
and now like you get you know
autocomplete in that respect. Um you
know that that was a smaller form of
this and then prettier right? Um, I
remember there was a little bit of fight
put up against prettier
um, letting go of your formatting, but
now it seems absurd that you would
actually spend any time formatting your
code at all yourself more especially
now, but I mean even a few years back
you use it for a little while. Um, and
you know, it just begins to make sense
the efficiency that you're getting in
the and like that is now out of your
mind, right?
And
you know, you see this I I used to work
with my dad and we used to do uh
construction. He still does. Um, and
recently I spoke to him and and we had
talked about uh you know what the
day-to-day looks like because I hadn't
been there in a while.
And I was like, "Oh, yeah. You still do
all this? You still uh you know,
snapping lines or you know using tape
measures?" And he surprised me. He said,
"No, no, I mean it's it's completely
different now." He's like, "Uh, you
know, we used to, you know, snap chalk
lines. Now everything is is lasers,
right? You have these lasers that you,
you know, uh magnet to the wall. Um, you
know, they want to take measurements.
They go in, they have this little laser
cube. They go boop, measures the room
immediately for you."
Um, so I I think it's not just us. I
think um, you know, if you've been here
long enough, you see these things come
along and and and make it more
efficient. And while it may feel like
we're losing control in some sense, um,
it's it's kind of nice to let that part
go. And I can see for some people how it
would be difficult. Um, you know, I
think that a lot of these newer
construction tools might uh, you know,
if you're a real craftsman, you know,
perhaps you frown upon that, right? And
I think, you know, if you're a real
software guy, like you're really really
about, uh, really writing the code,
right? Uh, using AI might might uh you
might frown upon that, right? It might
it might feel bad. Um, but what I will
tell you is like the construction
analogy, um, if if you can get your work
done faster
um, by using those tools, that means
that you can make more money, you can do
more, you can get more jobs done, right?
You can get them done faster. Um,
and you know, that's really what
separates uh, someone who wants to do it
uh, for money, for business, or or
someone who who really enjoys the craft.
And you can be both. Um,
but
what I really like to address is, you
know, a lot of people think that, uh,
you know, essentially that they're
and I don't think that we are,
generally speaking, at least in the
sense that you individually won't be,
right? It's it's really hard to say
where everything goes from here. But um
you know if if it goes poorly poorly,
it's not just going to be you, right? It
would be it would be necessarily
everyone. Um which is an easier pill to
swallow than you specifically being
Um you know, or uh you know,
everything works out okay. um both for
you and for everyone. Um but as of right
now, uh all AI labs, all uh companies
that are saying this, um everyone who's
who's who's hyping the idea uh that
there's going to be no more software
engineers have full rosters of open
positions for, believe it or not,
software engineers. Um, so you know,
it's hard to separate the the wheat from
the chaff with regards to what is
marketing, uh, what is fundraising, and
what is reality. Um, but it's not all
So, I think that, you know,
there's there's something to be said for
seeing what's called writing on the
wall. Um, I've been doing this for a
long time, quite some time. Um, and I've
had not quite a situation like this, but
other uh shifts, so to say, over that
time. And always you do begin to see a
bit of writing on the wall. Um, I
remember
when I used to write Flash and if you
don't remember Flash, it was amazing.
Um, it was like the best game experience
in the browser ever. Still hasn't been
replicated properly. Um, but you know,
Flash, we used to make websites. to make
rich websites. And it was cool. It was
like visual basic for the web. You had
like a timeline. Um, you know, you could
sit there and it had like like a vector
editor built in. It was it was
phenomenal. Um, and then the iPhone came
out and
that did not support flash and you
started to see the writing on the wall
that uh, you know, with browsers
investing more in actual web APIs that
allowed you to do things um, libraries
like jQuery which made animation easy
um, made other things easy that Flash
was probably going to fall out of favor.
And in situations like that, what you
have to do um is a see the writing on
that wall and b adapt, right? So I I
remember um having the conversation that
we should probably start doing things
off of flash and on the web. It was a
little grindy at first, right? And what
happens is that you are missing a couple
things, right? There's whenever you go
from a a a shift into a new thing into a
green field. Um, right, you're missing a
lot of uh you might be able to describe
as like community supported things or uh
uh all all the capabilities of why you
would choose one thing over another. So
you come in and you're like, "Oh yeah,
well we had this in the old thing and
here in the new thing we don't have
this." And rather than look at that as a
as a as a problem, right? You need to
look at that as an opportunity. Um I'll
give you another example. Um I remember
you know for we we we did things that
way for a while. Um we did uh the web
and uh uh just JavaScript and jQuery. Um
and then you know backbone came along
but you know it was fairly niche. Um
Angular made a bit more traction.
Um but the the big one was React.
So when React came in um it it was so
different. Um the people got upset when
it was when it was debuted. Um and at
some point I was sitting there and we we
were building uh e-commerce storefronts
with uh jQuery and
um I don't even know what to call it
because it's been acquired so many
times. Um but I saw the writing on the
wall and I saw that uh React was going
to be the thing.
I started to uh tinker with it, right?
And and knowing that it's going to be
the thing doesn't mean that you're
immediately going to have a job in the
thing or be able to go do the thing. A
lot of the time you have to night and
weekend this You have to go
through and um you know write blog posts
or or or build things with it, explore
with it. And when you do that, what
ended up happening is I get a call and
they say, "Hey, uh you know, we wanted
to do a large scale replatforming with
React. uh we've seen you've been doing
React, you've been tinkering around. Um
would you like to come do it? Right? And
at that time, you've been exploring the
space, you're excited, you say, "Yeah,
you kidding me? I would love to." Um and
then you get there and it's the same
story again where uh now you're
operating in React, but a lot of the
things that you had in jQuery, you're
not there. And right, you're in a a new
opportunity to go back fill some of
those missing pieces, right? because you
were early. So, what I'll tell you now
is that if you are even listening to
this talk, if you're attending this
right now, you're so early, it's
ridiculous.
Um, I did some some sentiment analysis
of some some normies that were watching
the Super Bowl and their reaction to AI
ads. Even at your own companies, there
are people who still at this point,
right now, refuse to actually use AI.
So, if you're watching this, you're
early. Um, and what I can tell you is
that this is the greenest of fields for
you. Um, you have an opportunity to, uh,
use this as a force multiplier, right?
To punch out of your depth in many ways.
Um,
which is a funny thing because, uh, a
lot of what you'll notice is that the
the best bang for your buck that you're
going to get out of AI is things that
you actually know about, right? Um, so
it's like a it 10 it 10xes you, but it
10xes your your domain knowledge, right?
So that's why I can use it very easily
to make uh web apps. It's also why I
don't do a very good job of having it
make C++ or games or things like that.
Um, it's because you still fundamentally
need to know how to architect these
things. Um, right? Like I think if if
the old job was you sitting there
whacking along, writing the syntax,
sitting there formatting and hitting
tab, right? The new job is a level
higher, right? It's an abstraction level
higher where um you know, I don't want
to say it's a manager because it's not.
it would be more of an architect and
soon probably closer to a CTO um where
you're sitting here making the decisions
around maybe maybe a product manager or
something closer to that but you're
going to be operating at a level uh
slightly higher than than where you're
at right now. But with that said um you
know the real value is your domain
knowledge, right? this is going to annex
whatever it is that you do. So I would
expect that C++ guys are going to get
really good use of AI for using C++ and
I would suspect that uh you know hard
hardware folk would do the same with
hardware. Um,
I think that
what it comes down to is that you're in
a position right now, which is new and
it's scary. Um,
but you you kind of have a decision to
make. And I think if you know, again, if
you're watching this, you've you've
largely made that decision.
Um, and if you're watching it and you
haven't, the the decision to make is you
have you have two choices here. And
that's
um either don't dive into this or or
dive all the way in. And
when you look at like the potential, if
you don't go into it at all, I mean, I I
don't know what to tell you. Um, but if
you dive in all the way, uh, right, the
worst that could happen is that you're
early.
Um,
but what I'll leave you with is that
you just need to go build So, stop
watching me and go build Thank
you.
All right, folks. We are almost done for
this year's conference. First of all,
thank you to all of our speakers in the
Discord. Drop your round of applause. Uh
thank you speakers for your amazing
talks. Now, all the recordings will be
published on the GitNation platform. So,
don't worry if you missed two talks
because they were happening at the same
time or there was discussion room that
you went off to. Don't worry, check out
gitnation.com.
And if you're a full ticket older, you
will get early access to them. And free
attendees, you'll have access to them in
about a month's time. So definitely
stick around to check those out.
>> Yeah, it's a sad time every time when we
uh close the conference, right? But I'm
pretty sure that we'll meet again and
I'm pretty sure that amazing G nation
team will help us uh for AI coding
summit 2027 and this is a great
opportunity to say huge thanks to all g
nation team for organizing this event
and all other events for developer
audience. Huge gratitude.
We want to hear from you folks. Please
share your feedback. Share your
thoughts, ideas, comments. Just kudos,
just simple thank you will make our day
better, right? We have super quick
feedback form. Just spend a minute or
two for saying something to us.
All right, and there's been a lot. Thank
you so much for joining us. Thank you
for learning, for discussing, for having
fun, and thank you so much for
participating. We've said a lot of thank
you to so many people, but thank you to
you for showing up. We really appreciate
you. We can't wait to see you next time
at another conference, whether it's this
one, another Get Nation conference, or
just out in the world. It is a pleasure
sharing the day with you, and we'll see
you next time. Bye.
>> See you folks.
VI coding in AI Studio with Gemini 3
lets you build anything.
Build entirely new experiences.
Create apps that see. Make tools that
listen.
Build apps with a single prompt.
Get inspired.
Tell me what you want.
>> Refine
and refine some more
now.
>> Share with a friend
and remix.
>> Then share with the world.
Bring anything to life.
>> Tell me what you want to do.
>> Using cursor, wind surf, claw code. What
about MCP servers? This AI coding stack
creates new risks such as data theft and
prompt injections. Backslash security
provides visibility, governance, and
real-time protection for agents, idees,
LLMs, and MCPs. We make Vibe coding
safe.
Allow me to introduce you to the
Cloudflare Sandbox SDK. It is an npm
install away. It gives you wonderful
code like this where you get the
sandbox, you do a get checkout, and then
you execute code like that. How
beautiful is that? And look at this.
That's not all. You get longunning
processes, real-time streaming, preview
URLs. How amazing is that? Code
interpreter, file system, command
execution, and websockets out of the
box. There is a bunch of examples. Come
check it out. What are you waiting for?
Uh, it has given us a computer that's
really do weeks of effort. The developer
experience is well thought out. What are
you waiting for? Come here. Get started
now.
>> Pixie is the fastest way to solve
internal business problems on top of
tools your team already uses. Describe
the extension you want and get user
interfacing components like forms,
buttons, and modals connected to
back-end logic like API requests and
database queries. Oneclick deployment
for small teams. Enterprisegrade
security for scale. Build your dream
extension today.
You know, render for quick deploys, but
did you know it's also the fastest path
to production for full stack apps? This
one has a web service, that's a front
end and a back end, manage Postgress,
and a chron job that runs durable
workflows. And the best part is all of
your services in the same region can
communicate internally over a private
network that's both faster and more
secure than the public internet. So
whether it's an AI agent or your next
startup, build it better on render.
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Heat. N.
VI coding an AI studio with Gemini 3
lets you build anything.
Build entirely new experiences.
Create apps that see. Make tools that
listen.
Build apps with a single prompt.
Get inspired.
>> Tell me what you want.
>> Refine.
and refine some more.
>> Share with a friend
and remix,
then share with the world.
>> Bring anything to life. Tell me what you
want to do
>> using cursor windsurf cloud code. What
about MCP servers? This AI coding stack
creates new risks such as data theft and
prompt injections. Backlash security
provides visibility, governance, and
realtime protection for agents, idees,
LLMs, and MCPs. We make Vibe coding
safe.
Allow me to introduce you to the
Cloudflare sandbox SDK. It is an npm
install away. It gives you wonderful
code like this where you get the
sandbox, you do a get checkout, and then
you execute code like that. How
beautiful is that? And look at this.
That's not all. You get longunning
processes, real-time streaming, preview
URLs. How amazing is that? Code
interpreter, file system command
execution, and websockets out of the
box. There is a bunch of examples. Come
check it out. What are you waiting for?
Uh, it has given us a computer that's
really do weeks of effort. The developer
experience is well thought out. What are
you waiting for? Come here, get started
now.
>> Pixie Bricks is the fastest way to solve
internal business problems on top of
tools your team already uses. Describe
the extension you want and get user
interfacing components like forms,
buttons, and modals connected to
back-end logic like API requests and
database queries. Oneclick deployment
for small teams. Enterprise grade
security for scale. Build your dream
extension today.
You know, render for quick deploys, but
did you know it's also the fastest path
to production for full stack apps? This
one has a web service that's a front end
and a back end manage Postgress and a
chron job that runs durable workflows.
And the best part is all of your
services in the same region can
communicate internally over a private
network that's both faster and more
secure than the public internet. So
whether it's an AI agent or your next
startup, build it better on render.
Hi.
Heat. Heat.